<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chloe Murdock</title>
    <description>Virtual portfolio of Chloe Murdock</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 12:19:07 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 12:19:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>

    
      <item>
        <title>Women's self-defence class a rank above the rest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://chlomur.com/2018/01/08/womens-self-defense-class-a-rank-above-the-rest/&quot;&gt;The Miami Student&lt;/a&gt; in November 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Thursday. It was dark. I was Uptown, walking alone past a brooding Brick Street and suspicious cars tucked in alleyways. Walking alone at night reminds me of horror stories from family and friends, sexual assault notifications and the statistics that aren’t in my favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what drives the demand behind the women’s self-defense classes run by Tier 2 Defense. Tier 2 CEO Chris Cravens has eight years of experience in the U.S. Marine Corps Infantry, followed by work for a protective agency. Cravens also protected for a time on behalf of the U.S. Naval Criminal Investigative Service, or NCIS. The Tier 2 self defense syllabus for both law enforcement classes and women’s self-defense classes on college campuses is based on his experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on my way to Tier 2’s first-ever lesson at the Oxford Community Arts Center. The lesson ran from 7-9 p.m. (Another class marketed to Miami students is coming up on Nov. 30).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite spending the better part of the past year attending krav maga classes and learning tae kwon do, judo and hapkido with Miami’s Red Dragons martial arts club, I was about to find out I had been too tense to be able to effectively defend myself on my walk home in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While women’s self defense classes are often free of charge, they are nowhere near as intensive as the mindset training and maneuvers Tier 2 instructor Justin Goshorn focused on. He trained for a time in Langley, Virginia, to prepare for his current position, but he first worked for Tier 2 as a janitor before working his way up to an instructor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most self-defense classes offer a brief mindset or attitude training, but Goshorn began by pulling up a PowerPoint presentation complete with bullet points covering the legal rights of someone facing an assailant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you do have the right to defend yourself, Goshorn said that “you must be able to demonstrate you were not the initial aggressor,” since your attacker can file a civil suit if you injure them in a fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t punch someone just because they harrassed you at a bar,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unable to prove this in a court of law, consequences can land on you instead of the aggressor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You may be charged with assault even if you only use the force necessary to defend yourself,” Goshorn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the legal definition of aggression extends to the verbal kind as well — for example, if someone is intentionally intimidating you to get in their car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goshorn recommended escaping a situation as quickly as possible to avoid a lawsuit. He then moved on to what you should do before, during and after a potential physical altercation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is more applicable to your daily life than the moves you’ll learn later on in the training,” Goshorn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being aware of your surroundings can allow you to remove yourself from a situation before it starts. Goshorn also mentioned the importance of having a healthy amount of suspicion about people’s behavior and appearance, but warned that this was relative, citing the most recent high-profile sexual assaults in the news as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s okay to be suspicious of someone wearing a hoodie, but that does not mean a guy in a suit can’t be a potential aggressor,” Goshorn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Goshorn’s presentation, the 38 of us paired up to practice key moves that could apply to multiple situations. Goshorn and his assistant instructor, Chris Kleiner, would demonstrate a maneuver before allowing the class to break out and try the move on each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I paired up with a woman who’d been correcting the Chinese characters in her young daughter’s workbook before class started. Her name is Lei Kerr, a Miami University engineering professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think an attacker would be much taller than me. I need to be able to strike higher,” Kerr said while she practiced a lance strike — a quick hit to the throat with the space between the forefinger and thumb — on my forearm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kerr and I also practiced getting out of a hold if an attacker wraps their arms around you from behind, if they push you up against a wall and then if they are on top of you and holding you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goshorn encouraged everyone to return for another class. A two-hour session is educational, he said, but it is not a guarantee that we would be prepared for a potentially dangerous situation years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class was made up of Oxford residents of all sizes and ages, including Joelah Marcum, a 14-year-old who dances regularly at the Flowing Grace School of Dance studio, which hosted the lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not that you’ll necessarily have to go through this, but it makes you feel confident that you would be able to survive it,” Marcum said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcum and fellow dancer Sarah Webster, 17, asked the instructors questions long after the class ended. What if an attacker pinned you to the wall this way? What if they were holding you down this way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You see a bunch of scary stories all over the news and you think, ‘Oh my goodness, would I be able to survive this?” Webster said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tier 2 curriculum does not teach punching, kicking or kneeing techniques because this will supposedly come naturally in a dangerous situation. Goshorn leaves the “nitty gritty” details to traditional martial arts schools and gyms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the dark walk back to my dorm, I could tell Brick was packed through the windows. Music blared on both sides of Main Street. But after the Tier 2 Defense class, I felt a bit safer — relaxed, even — on my way to the other side of campus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/01/Womens-self-defence-class-rank/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/01/Womens-self-defence-class-rank/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Missing home and hot tortillas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An early draft of this was originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://miamistudent.net/missing-home-and-hot-tortillas/&quot;&gt;The Miami Student&lt;/a&gt; in September 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I should wait to visit. I’ve only been at school for a few days,” I say over the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family only lives two hours away, but it’s my first weekend away at Miami and they already want me to come visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my family, but maybe I should have chosen an out-of-state school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I start calling Miami my home the day I move in. I love my new friends, I love the campus and I love being disappointed every time I see Brick Street’s entrance and think it’s a movie theater. I can’t wrap my head around being homesick in such a place because I’m ready to live such a life, just like that moving (and propaganda-tinged) poem said I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not ready for the feeling when it hits. I’m fighting procrastination in my dorm alone, when my stomach outright scoffs at my growing to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I open my fridge for the Mission brand tortillas graciously given to freshman students without anything to put inside, and can’t push away the memory of my grandma’s homemade tortillas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission tortillas taste fine when microwaved, but they don’t taste like home. I spit out the limp bite of flour, remembering how hot a fresh tortilla is when you snatch it off the pan with just your fingers. Homemade tortillas taste good even when you don’t have anything to stuff them with, even when they grow cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name sounds white, I look white and I am mostly white. I check “Caucasian” on the U.S. Census. But my great grandma Rodriguez greets the men in our family with an ecstatic “Papasito!” and kisses their cheek, and tells tales of the teachers in San Antonio who scorned her for her accent and her appearance. And my grandma wistfully recalls when she could speak fluent Spanish just as well as she remembers the recipes from her late Mexican restaurant, which closed before I was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heritage is part of my identity, even though I feel strange sharing it. I want to, but I also don’t want to lay claim to the experiences I don’t have. It gets awkward when a white girl reminisces about her grandma making mexican food for Thanksgiving, especially to someone who actually looks the part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how to fight this kind of homesickness here. Instead, I call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Grandma, can we make tortillas this weekend?”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/Missing-home-and-hot-tortillas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/Missing-home-and-hot-tortillas/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now accepting roommate applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accepted to college? Check. Cried over your scholarships, or lack thereof? Check. Joined the Facebook group? Check. Now all you need to score a roommate is an uber-detailed summary about yourself. But who has time for that?! Save some of your last precious moments of high school by screenshotting one of these Facebook autobiographies instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;216&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-02.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOR THE JOCK: Hi, my name is probably Brad. I played all the sports in high school, and I’ve provided some sweet action shots taken by my mom to show that off. Grades are important to me so I can stay on my gains. I’m most likely studying something in business, but on the weekends I’ll be getting a Ph.D. in partying—I mean, networking with my fellow peers. I’m looking for a chill roommate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-03.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOR THE MUSICAL THEATRE GEEK: Hey everyone! My name is something upbeat like Carly. I’m 100 percent committed to this school’s music and arts programs, and I’m so excited about it I could sing—both literally and figuratively! I was in show choir, but you could tell that a mile away from this sparkly outfit I’m wearing in at least one picture. I am very specific about the music I listen to and also mentioned the musical “Hamilton” somewhere in my post. If you don’t mind me practicing facial expressions in the mirror or losing against me in a karaoke competition then we should be roommates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-04.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR THE FUTURE FRAT BRO: Hey guys, I’m Chad. Brad and I are already bros, and I convinced him to rush Sigma Apple Pie this year with me. You can see based on my photos that I’m always down for a good time. Follow me on all my other social media, because my life is wayyy too lit to post on Facebook where my grandparents are. Feel free to message me too, but if you’re a girl and I think you’re hot I may or may not aggressively DM you first. Gotta practice for Sigma traditions, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-05.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR THE FUTURE SORORITY SIS: Hey all! I have a popular name like Samantha, and I’m super pumped for college life! I am a walking @dory twitter account which makes me super relatable, and I will get hella likes on this post. I love working out and I can study, but I’m also going to vaguely hint that I know how to party like there is no tomorrow. I am rushing for the Chi Omega-Three Vitamins sisterhood, so if you have a problem with my love for Greek life I will throw a toga at you on my way to the latest frat party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;244&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-06.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR THE CONTROL FREAK: Hi everyone. You will only remember me as the crazy person with a billion planned activities, so my name is pretty irrelevant. I’ve provided bullet points of all my current achievements as well as my five-year plan, because I don’t have time to spend 15 minutes on a Facebook post. That said, this will still be an autobiography’s worth of facts about me because I can’t stand not doing the absolute most. This list might include student government, three seasons of sports where I was captain, along with a shortlist of nondescript clubs. My idea of fun involves having my crap together. I’m in the honors dorm this year so if you don’t have a 5.0 GPA, you probably can’t hang.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Now-accepting-roomate-applications/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Now-accepting-roomate-applications/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Juniors be warned: college apps are expensive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone talks about getting into college, but no one mentions the fees involved. Aspiring college students spend hours filling out personal information, writing essays, collecting teacher recommendations and sending test scores to get into schools of their dreams—only to pay a fee just to send an application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, students on average spent $41 on an application fee, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/education/best-colleges/the-short-list-college/articles/2015/12/01/colleges-that-charge-students-the-most-to-apply&quot;&gt;usnews.com&lt;/a&gt;. However, students often apply to more than one college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the time you are a senior, you should have three to five schools you are serious about. I know that $40 to $60 for each can add up,” guidance counselor Mike Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average student will pay $120 to $205 total in application fees, unless they request a fee waiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High school senior Jessica Jones spent $60 to apply to The Ohio State University, on top of applications sent to University of Dayton (although this fee was waived), University of Cincinnati ($50), Ohio University ($70) and Bowling Green State University ($45). She paid a total of $165 in application fees. After she was accepted, she was required to pay $100 more to commit to tOSU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I understand the application fee, since someone has to be paid to read them,” Jones said. “The acceptance fee seems ridiculous to me. If I’m going there, won’t I give them enough money anyways?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to economics teacher Joseph Cellar, whose wife Leslie formerly worked as an admissions counselor at Ohio Wesleyan University, there is an entire committee behind the admissions process taking home hours worth of applications. While she never provided a comment, J. Cellar said each individual on the committee at the time of L. Cellar’s employment was paid approximately $50,000 in wages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colleges charge these increasingly exorbitant fees to fund marketing campaigns and salaries of admissions counselors. University fiscal reports lump together revenue made from both tuition and fees, so where the money is funneled is unclear. Despite not knowing exactly where their money goes, most applicants are willing to pay the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We do have a segment of the Olentangy student population where they approach the process by wanting to go to the most prestigious college possible and they consider this factor above all others. They want to see if they can get in. At least one or two apply to 10 or more colleges,” Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest a student of Naveau’s has applied to is 16, but Naveau claims the highest in department history was 18.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Juniors-be-warned-college-apps-are-expensive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Juniors-be-warned-college-apps-are-expensive/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Student’s foundation creates change in India slums</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;They were born in the country, yet are not considered citizens. They don’t have access to a stable job, so they live on less than $10 a month. They are not provided schooling or healthcare, when they are the ones who need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social class caste system of India known as Varna prevents the Dalit—the lowest rung on the caste—from opportunities we take for granted in the United States, according to &lt;a href=&quot;borgenmagazine.com&quot;&gt;borgenmagazine.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vision Foundation is a nonprofit education that provides healthcare and education in the Dharavi slums of Mumbai, India every summer—yet the foundation’s president, senior Esha Chadha, is 18 years old and lives half a world away in Lewis Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They are not citizens, so they have no fundamental rights,” Chadha said. “They are not allowed education or healthcare, so they need an outside source to provide those things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last summer, the foundation gave artificial lenses to 133 blind children in the slums of Mumbai, India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The children were not born without sight, but were made blind to be more successful at begging,” Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orphanages use maiming techniques on children to gain more sympathy from passerbys unlikely to give their money to a healthy child, according to Chadha. The Vision Foundation’s primary goal is to turn children away from begging and toward learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Once they have their eyesight, they can focus on getting an education,” Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a two-week period, Chadha taught basic math in the slums alongside a few volunteer teachers. She also spoke to 300-400 women and children in the slums about domestic violence, civil rights and the dangers of sending children—girls in particular—out on the streets to beg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Begging causes a lot of problems in India. It leaves children vulnerable to rape and murder,” Chadha said. “No one else would talk to them about [their rights].”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chadha’s history of volunteering in India began long before she took up the presidential role in summer 2016. Chadha grew up between two places she called home—one in the state of Ohio and the other in Mumbai, India. Her aunt, Neena Chadha, brought along E. Chadha and her twin brother, Arjun Chadha, to donate food to the slums. According to cia.gov, 43.5 percent of children in India under five years of age are underweight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most of their food is donated, but other than that they’re on their own,” E. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chadha also paid for education needs on occasion, since people in the slums are not granted schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re doing a project on Malala [Yousafzai] in English class, comparing education all over the world. [Olentangy is] so much more advanced in comparison to both [schools in the United States and around the world],” Kirsten K. ‘20 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chadha claims some applied for televised Indian dance shows, but were turned away due to their social status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They aren’t provided education, but they are talented kids, especially in dancing and music, since they don’t have much else to do,” E. Chadha said. “In the slums, they are all moving backward while everyone else moves forward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Family friend Prasoon Dixit ran the foundation before he appointed E. Chadha as president. E. Chadha said he noticed her throwing herself into the foundation following her aunt’s death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My aunt was one of the last of my family still in India. I wanted a reason to come back home even without having family there,” E. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation morphed into a family affair following E. Chadha’s new role. E. Chadha’s sister, Neha Chadha, is putting together an official website, while A. Chadha attended the trip last summer to clean up slums in disrepair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The slums do not even have houses. Their roof may be a bedsheet. Their bed is the floor,” E. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While A. Chadha removed trash and recycled plastic, living conditions in the slums cannot remain clean without continual support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People complain about life in this country, but they have no clue about the conditions [the Dalit are] living in,” English teacher Sarah Zettler said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/geos/in.html&quot;&gt;cia.gov&lt;/a&gt;, 71.5 percent of India’s rural population—where most slums are located—has unimproved sanitation facility access. These living conditions allow “major infectious diseases” in India such as malaria, dengue fever, rabies and hepatitis strains to spread more quickly throughout slums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is really dirty and unhygienic there. A lot of kids are passing away from infections. If you ate their food, you would get sick and have to go to the hospital,” A. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While attending school in the United States, E. Chadha recruits U.S. doctors, nurses and teachers to work with her in India. She is seeking a new doctor to help her set up another blind camp this upcoming summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation has already created massive positive change, but E. Chadha claims the Vision Foundation is relatively small and hopes to expand the charity over time. Those who would like to get involved with the Vision Foundation can visit their Facebook page or email E. Chadha at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:eshachadha@gmail.com&quot;&gt;eshachadha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/Students-foundation-creates-change-in-india-slums/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/Students-foundation-creates-change-in-india-slums/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerschool helps, harms student stress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teen stress rivals that of adults during the school year, according to data collected from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apapracticecentral.org/update/2014/02-13/teen-stress.aspx&quot;&gt;2014 Stress in America survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A lot of things stress me out, especially Powerschool,” Justin F. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While colleges look for the well-rounded individual as the ideal student, the importance of grades has not lessened in the college admission process. This is one of the reasons the district introduced Powerschool, a program which helps parents and students track grades online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is more helpful to have current, updated grades as opposed to waiting to get the report card in the mail,” guidance counselor Meghan Roberts said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freshmen Jaclyn H., Grace M. and Simi A. felt Powerschool reduced stress in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In elementary school I had anxiety about when I would get a test back,” Assi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simi’s stress waned with the introduction of Powerschool, since it removes her fear of not knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I check [Powerschool] multiple times a day if I know an assignment is coming in soon,” Simmi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberts recommends students and parents check Powerschool once or twice a week to monitor progress, and even less for students who know their grades cause them stress. However, many students check Powerschool to lower stress over grades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I’m able to see what I’m doing bad in, then I can help that grade [improve] so I know what to do,” Jenna W. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frequency with which students and parents check grades varies from the recommended amount to several times per day. Grace and Jaclyn check it once a day, while Simi on average checks it “once in the morning and once at night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents who receive Powerschool notifications tend to check it more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Notifications] come in once or twice a week, at least,” Jaclyn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When teachers post new assignments, however, parents see it and confront students more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whenever they know I have a test, they ask about my grade,” Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Grace views the pressure from her parents in a positive light, Justin does not feel the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[My parents are] on my case about it, and it stresses me out more than it should,” Justin said. “When the grade from something that would boost my grade doesn’t come in immediately, they say, ‘hey, you didn’t work on this,’ when I did work on it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberts recognizes the “occasional confusion” Powerschool creates, but she argues the benefits outweigh the costs—and one bad grade is not going to ruin a student’s future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s the end of the year grade that is going to hit your transcript. A little dip is not going to hurt you,” Roberts said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Powerschool-helps-harms-student-stress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Powerschool-helps-harms-student-stress/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get off the couch, see these movies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/before-i-fall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Before-I-Fall&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q3Zyy4ZXegE&quot;&gt;Before I Fall&lt;/a&gt;” (PG-13) — three-point-five stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular girl lives the same day over and over after experiencing a tragedy and reevaluates her life choices in the process. Prior to watching the film, I incorrectly assumed this was a romantic drama. I am lucky enough to have found a boy who doesn’t mind “chick flicks,” so I was in good company; however, this screen version of a novel of the same name by Lauren Oliver was not what either of us anticipated. The repetitive day did not bore me into giving it three-point-five stars, but the shallow character development did. However, this movie will still make you feel all the feelings for family, friends and strangers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Pregame for this serious “Mean Girls”-esque movie with the latest seasonal Starbucks drink, then get basic white girl concessions: a small cherry ICEE and a box candy of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/get-out.png&quot; alt=&quot;Get-Out-Movie&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sRfnevzM9kQ&quot;&gt;Get Out&lt;/a&gt;” (R) — five stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris’ girlfriend takes him to her white parents’ plantation house, where his awkward interactions with her strange family escalate into dystopian violence. Actor Daniel Kaluuya, who plays main character Chris, was also the protagonist in the British horror TV show “Black Mirror” episode “Fifteen Million Merits”—I expected a lot out of this thriller, and I was not disappointed. Director Jordan Peele (half of the “Key and Peele” comedian duo) injects profound messages alongside surprising humor, often in the form of Chris’ TSA friend Rod, played by Lil Rel Howery. The Armitage family incites more psychological violence on Chris than physical—they claim they only intend for him to enjoy himself, but their psychopathic attitudes toward his skin color lie just underneath the surface from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Stress eat all your popcorn in the first scene so you don’t jump during a scary moment later and spill it everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/logan-movie.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Logan-Movie&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Div0iP65aZo&quot;&gt;Logan&lt;/a&gt;” (R) — four stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aging Wolverine and Professor Xavier drive across the country with Hispanic mutant girl Laura (played by Dafne Keen) in an unsuccessful attempt to avoid a clandestine cloning company. The villains were an unwelcome distraction from the three characters’ camaraderie, who bicker in true-to-form family road trip style—except in bullet-ridden cars, of course. However, the grudging bond between past and future Wolverines, Logan and Laura, grows into true respect in the final moments. Xavier’s deterioration due to Alzheimer’s makes an important statement about aging. While this will be the final Wolverine sequel, it is set in 2029 so we should at least expect more Logan and Xavier cameos in upcoming X-Men films. Laura shredded their adversaries just as well as Logan, and if she doesn’t star in future films I will boycott Marvel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Superheroes go big or go home, and so should you with the large drink and popcorn combo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/john-wick-2-movie.webp&quot; alt=&quot;John-Wick-2&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChpLV9AMqm4&quot;&gt;John Wick Chapter Two&lt;/a&gt;” (R) — two stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sole reason I bothered to see this movie was because my self defense instructor recommended Keanu Reeve’s stellar fight scenes, but that and Wick’s dog were the only things going for it. To be fair, I did not see the first “John Wick,” but after seeing this garbage I don’t want to. I wanted to throw my popcorn at Keanu Reeves every time he opened his mouth and choked on his lines. The weird subtitle font, cheesy acting and overdramatic music reminded me of a bad Spanish telenovela. Actress Ruby Rose is not even deaf but plays a hearing-impaired bodyguard for the villain—an impressive and underused actress, but she plays a part which could go to someone who is actually deaf. Wick never named his dog and left it with someone else for most of the movie, which was why I rated this so low—other than how many of my brain cells died while trying to comprehend the awfulness of this movie. I should have waited for this to launch on Netflix, so I could mute it and fast-forward to the fight scenes and whenever his dog showed up on screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Don’t even come to see this trash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Get-off-the-couch-see-these-movies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Get-off-the-couch-see-these-movies/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feminism vs. Equalism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a full version of my letter from the editor originally published and cut down due to spacing issues in the March 2017 issue of The Beacon. This is a response to a letter to the editor from a student who did not agree with our feminism in-depth spread.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Beacon editor and fellow student, thank you for your lively reply to our in-depth opinion article on feminism. However, there are a few errors in your response I need to point out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You claimed the article should have remained unbiased in the face of such a controversial issue. However, the article was an “in-depth opinion,” and we labeled it so on the top-middle section of the page and in the table of contents. An opinion piece, by definition, carries a slant. Opinion articles should at least bring up the opposing side’s viewpoint, then follow it with a counterargument, which is how our writers conducted the structure of the piece. All information included in the article was true, albeit filtered with a clear stance on the issue which was appropriate for opinion writing style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your statement claiming we are a school-funded—and therefore government-funded—publication to argue why The Beacon should remain unbiased is also incorrect. The Beacon is in fact funded by the small businesses and organizations who buy advertisements from us, as well as the issues we sell monthly. We do not receive funding in any form from the school. This is also mentioned in our policy statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the freedom of speech protects The Beacon’s writers as well as your opinion, it also protects mine. While the Latin definition of the word “fem” is, as you said, “feminine,” the term’s history, and therefore full meaning, carries a more complex connotation. Since this page doesn’t have enough space for me to describe the three waves of feminism and the changing goals of the feminist movement,* I will again repeat a variation of the official definition from reputable dictionaries: feminism recognizes the political, social and economic status of the sexes has yet to become equal. While women in the past made great strides in civil rights, we still have a long way to go to eliminate institutionalized sexism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have to tell you women make up about half of the population. This is one thing we have equal ground on. However, you might not be aware of the state of political inequality of women, looking at representation in the United States. Out of 535 members of Congress, 104 are female, according to the Center for American Women and Politics. Only the most qualified individuals should hold office, of course. But when men and women legally have equal opportunities to be elected into office, we have to look to social factors to understand why women’s representation in Congress is half of what it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender defines how parents should raise their children the moment they are born, and not just by choosing pink or blue paint for their bedroom wall. Girls are traditionally praised for being quiet, demure, pretty; boys are exalted for strength. They are expected to roughhouse and experiment but above all exhibit dominance, often in the form of aggression. While nothing seems inherently wrong with this parenting style, it assigns both genders respective advantages and disadvantages to navigate into adulthood. While some of these double standards do benefit women, most of them support men in a way which creates disproportionate demographics in the workforce—in particular the political, math and science fields, which encourages traditionally male traits and are still comprised of mostly men. Women with aspirations in these fields have a different set of obstacles to contend with than men, often with no clear outline available on how to combat them. While it is still possible for women to succeed in these fields, it puts them at a direct disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of “feminism” is for women to obtain the same social privileges men receive the moment they are born—not to be dominant over men, but to reach the same standards and expectations men are automatically granted. Bridging this gap also includes defying negative male stereotypes. “Equalism” debases the platform and meaning already built around feminism, and counteracts the focus on the need for women specifically to achieve equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, we would all be “equalists” as you say—but from what I can gather from your letter, you believe men and women are perfectly equal already and do not realize how this term debases the women and men who worked toward gender equality for over a century. The point of the article was to create a dialogue around a topic which is a major point of contention, and you opened up this conversation. The Beacon welcomes people of action like you to join in on discussions on a public platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you again for your response, and I hope you and readers like you are further encouraged to create a dialogue about issues of contention like gender. Only then will injustices and evidence of progress be brought to light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*A rundown of the changing goals of the feminist movement in the United States: the right to vote with the 19th Amendment, discrimination in the workplace, Equal Rights Amendment, Roe v. Wade, to the present: intersectional feminism, which incorporates all factors of inequality like race, socioeconomic status, sexual identity, etc. into the present inequality of the sexes; fighting female genital mutilation at home and abroad; addressing rape culture (which also applies to men but is often overlooked) and general violence against women; LGBTQ+ rights; challenges of people of color who identify as women; women’s health issues; unrealistic expectations for both men and women in society…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is too complex to summarize in one blog post. Not all feminists or even all women agree on all issues (linked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gloriasteinem.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Gloria Steinem) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.volkskrant.nl/boeken/ngozi-adichie-beyonce-s-feminism-isn-t-my-feminism~a4390684/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Beyonce and Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie’s somewhat conflicting viewpoints on feminism) are women of influence who seem to identify with the traditionally left-leaning feminist movement, linked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syracuse.com/celebrity-news/index.ssf/2017/05/kara_mccullough_healthcare_feminism_miss_usa_2017.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Miss USA 2017 preferring to call herself an equalist), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makers.com/phyllis-schlafly&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Phyllis Schlafly), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theblaze.com/video/tomi-lahren-offers-a-clear-message-to-left-wing-feminists-this-is-what-real-women-look-like/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Tomi Lahren) are examples of women of influence who distanced themselves from the word feminism, and linked here is the late &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/10/style/frida-kahlo-is-having-a-moment.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;Frida Kahlo&lt;/a&gt;, a Mexican artist also revered as an unapologetic feminist icon, although an unorthodox one). Educate yourself to see where you stand, whether or not you intend to join the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Feminism-vs-equalism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Feminism-vs-equalism/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cesar Chavez Day withstands today’s political climate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight states close school and government offices on March 31 for the national holiday celebrating the former leader of the late National Farm Workers Association (now known as United Farm Workers of America, or UFW).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Mahatma Gandhi’s strategies of nonviolence and fasting, Chavez cofounded the UFW with Dolores Huerta to advocate for better pay and safer working conditions for farm workers—many of whom identified as Mexican American and Filipino American, according to &lt;a href=&quot;ufw.org&quot;&gt;ufw.org&lt;/a&gt;.  In 1966, Chavez led the UFW’s 340 mile march from Delano, Calif. to Sacramento, Calif. to allow peaceful collective bargaining agreements between unions and the state government. Chavez endured three historic fasts to protest his own organization’s violent behavior and bring attention to the UFW’s “La Causa.” His longest fast in 1988 lasted 36 days, which influenced celebrities, politicians and religious leaders to continue the fast for several days to raise awareness of the UFW’s work—decades before the 2014 ALS ice bucket challenge raised awareness and money for its respective cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;recordsofrights.org&quot;&gt;recordsofrights.org&lt;/a&gt;, Chavez faced the greatest opposition from Delano, Calif. table grapes in 1968—a five-year-long boycott and strike protest—as well as pesticide proponents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 1989 address to Pacific Lutheran University, Chavez considered “protecting farm workers—and consumers—from systematic poisoning through the reckless use of agricultural toxins” more integral to the UFW’s cause than any other aspect of a safe working environment. This is still a point of contention in today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Monsanto is a company that does a lot of lobbying to get certain laws passed to allow pesticides to be used,” AP Environmental Science teacher Julie Effler said. “Touching” and “inhaling” chemicals is dangerous, as well as ingesting it via foods that are not organic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue the UFW continues to work toward in Chavez’s name is his stance on immigration. Chavez described illegal immigrants brought over by companies to break up UFW strikes as “wetbacks” and “illegals” in a 1972 KQED TV interview; he also supported President Ronald Reagan’s 1986 proposed immigration reform bill, according to NPR. The original bill converted illegal immigrants into citizens if they had lived in the United States since before 1982, on top of tightening border security and punishing employers who hired “scabs,” or illegal Mexican immigrants from Mexico, to continue working in protesters’ places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Growers were] in need of workers willing to work for less money, essentially taking advantage of those wanting a better life for themselves,” history teacher Daniel Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the UFW’s dismay, the section which put pressure on employers who hired scabs was eliminated to pass the bill as a law. However, Chavez’s past work in the UFW at the time had already made immense strides in farm worker’s rights. President Bill Clinton later gave a posthumous Presidential Medal of Freedom in Chavez’s name to the influencer’s wife, Helen, in 1994, a year after his death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight states touched by his existence (California, Arizona, Colorado, Michigan, New Mexico, Texas, Utah and Wisconsin) celebrate Cesar Chavez Day by closing government offices and school buildings, according to &lt;a href=&quot;time.com&quot;&gt;time.com&lt;/a&gt;. However, Lewis Center students such as freshman Rachel S. would not mind another day off of school—despite her limited knowledge of Cesar Chavez’s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If other states think it’s that important, they clearly must have reason for it,” Rachel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior Kayla Blanton does not agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know who he is. It doesn’t make sense for us to miss school for it,” Blanton said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Cesar-Chaves-day-withstands-todays-political-climate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Cesar-Chaves-day-withstands-todays-political-climate/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Attraction turns scientific</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published as a cover article in the 2017 February issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is it about the glimmer in a pair of eyes across the room that makes you wish you knew the person behind them? Can we pin down the “je ne sais quoi,” or a special someone’s intangible beauty you can’t explain, that leaves one falling head over heels? Whether or not you already have a certain person in mind, the answer to making a connection may lie in a few psychological theories rather than a mystical connection. If you’re desperate to trap a boo, put your doubts aside for these borderline manipulation tactics, curated from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceofrelationships.com/home/2012/5/17/top-5-classic-studies-in-the-psychology-of-attraction.html&quot;&gt;scienceofrelationships.com&lt;/a&gt; and backed up by AP Psychology teacher Brian Wendel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your looks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If they take time to make themselves more presentable, they hold themselves to a higher standard,” Anthony Sasso ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal of beauty changes depending on who you talk to, but a cleanly appearance and good hygiene gives the impression of exceptional trustworthiness in any situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you walk into a job interview, and you don’t try to look nice, it looks like you don’t care,” Grace H. ‘19 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While stealing the attention of a love interest is not a major career move, taking care of your physical appearance—both synthetic and genetic—defines the iconic “love at first sight” plotline. However, some consider exceptional beauty at arm’s length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I just assume ‘she doesn’t like me, there’s no way,’” Luke S. ‘20 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freshman Joe D. agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m intimidated because I don’t think I’m good looking,” Joe said. “You critique yourself and what you did wrong when you have a chance to talk to them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Luke and Joe admitted feeling inadequate despite being otherwise confident in themselves. But those considered physically imposing may work harder to establish a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When someone is mangled, disfigured, or viewed as a threat it may prevent connection. We are biologically hardwired to not trust people outside our group biases,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proximity fosters genuine connection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily interactions reveal more about a person than the seven seconds it takes to make a first impression. We are more likely to become attracted to those we come in contact with on a daily basis rather than someone we pass once in the hallway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With a fellow student or coworker, you are usually going to have things in common,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strongest attraction over time, however, can stem from someone you once hated—per the mere exposure theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The mere exposure theory is a sequence of events occurring over months or years. There may be a certain person you have nothing in common with or are not even physically attracted to, but go through an evolution of your feelings for each other,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After initial dislike passes, a tolerance for one another develops into respect—which may turn into a deeper connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is based on compatibility rather than looks, so it can survive the test of time. This explains why arranged marriages are often successful,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opposites don’t attract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to surround ourselves with people who foster the same core beliefs and values; therefore, we are attracted to people who are similar to us—or are at least resemble an ideal we want to strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We tend to be attracted to characteristics we find admirable in ourselves,” Wendel said. “Similar interests, goals, thoughts and attitudes can certainly form an attraction between two people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it surprising to find out people are not magnets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I never look for someone who’s different from me. I look for someone who will push me out of my comfort zone, but still aligns with me,” Sasso said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It depends on who you find. If you find someone similar, you have stuff to talk about. But with someone different you have more to discover about one another,” Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, Wendel argues opposites attract when infatuation is involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Infatuation occurs when someone is more reckless, or unlike ourselves. This leans on physical characteristics, and traits or behaviors you know aren’t typical to your own,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fear creates romance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fancy dinner is classically romantic, as are chocolates and flowers. But to create an authentic chemistry between you two, scare the love out of your date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any time people share a traumatic experience, they experience a shared biochemical reaction,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While studies focus on life-or-death situations, Wendel says any emotional bond creates a deeper feeling of attraction than the physical aspects of romance. To recreate this, put a spin on the classic “dinner and a movie”—or more likely “Netflix and chill”—by hitting “play” on the latest thriller… as long as the other person doesn’t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s more about what the girl is into, especially if you really like them,” Aiden M. ‘20 said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/Attraction-turns-scientific/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/Attraction-turns-scientific/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Holidays draw out religious differences</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first job in fast food at Subway. Five other workers worked up front with me on the notorious sandwich line, and together we cranked out orders like a machine. We did all we could to finish their meals as fast as possible, but I still felt guilty for holding up their holiday shopping. I finished up my current customer’s order with no problems, even with a line of angry people stretching past the booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Happy holidays!” I said, releasing a sigh of relief and a big smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t say that. That’s what terrorists say. Merry Christmas!” the customer said cheerily. My former manager agreed with him, and they shared a moment of bonding over their blatant intolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, two women wearing traditional hijab head coverings waited further down in line, silent amid the chaos of the food court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the most wonderful time of the year—except for those who do not share the same traditions as mainstream culture. The embedded impatience of the season tends to bring the worst out in shoppers. Those in the minimum wage workforce are exposed to little moments of people’s covert bias against others who do not look or celebrate like them. Holiday deals lure in customers, and long lines keep them long enough for an unsuspecting worker to see or hear snippets of underlying prejudice of Christmas time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family and I also celebrate Christmas and participate in mainstream traditions associated with the holiday. We listen to Christmas music, we put up a freshly cut pine in the corner of the living room and we cover presents in wrapping paper dotted with “Joy to the World” lyrics. I am a typical white girl, dark blonde hair and all. I do not want to speak for those who face these struggles this time of year, but I do wish to comment on the controversy of political correctness during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should not be offensive to say “happy holidays,” but the motivation behind it—to consider other religions or beliefs as well as those who celebrate Christmas—can be perceived as threatening to Christianity. Yes, Christians are still threatened in this country because of their faith. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucr.fbi.gov/hate-crime/2013/topic-pages/victims/victims_final&quot;&gt;FBI data&lt;/a&gt; collected in 2013, 105 hate crimes targeted Protestants and Catholics combined. However, 625 crimes were also committed against Jewish people and 135 attacked those of the Islamic faith in the same year. Everyone deserves a chance to exercise their religious freedom, but this does not mean it is okay to disregard other faiths in the process. We still have a long way to go toward acceptance of all people in our melting pot of a country, and this is just one aspect of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/01/Holidays-draw-out-religious-differences/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/01/Holidays-draw-out-religious-differences/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Voters OK Olentangy Levy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 16, 2016—Local newspapers reported the successful passing of the Olentangy levy, determined by voters a day prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Passage of yesterday’s ballot issue allows us to continue the level of excellence that has become the standard in our community,” Superintendent Mark Raiff said in a public thank you letter on the school website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with the standard means the district maintains AP classes, electives and extracurricular programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While building repairs, new technology and more teachers are also mentioned, these administrative decisions will alleviate student overcrowding in the district while construction is planned for a fourth high school on Berlin Station Road, another addition to the levy ballot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The design for the fourth high school will be similar to both Liberty and Orange high schools with some key updates and modifications,” Raiff said in an April 15 statement to the district community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The groundbreaking ceremony for the building site is set for June 9 of this year. Raiff expects to finish redrawing attendance boundaries by March 2017. Similar to building openings in the past, a senior class will not exist in the first year of opening. Student rearrangement will affect those in sixth, seventh and eighth grades this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No current high school students will change schools,” Raiff said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students already feel effects of overcrowding in school restrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before [classes], after classes and during lunch are the worst to go,” Muskan A. ‘19 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parking lot space is an additional concern for students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I changed my schedule second semester so I could get out early and avoid the after-school traffic,” Shayna Haberman ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Voters-ok-olentangy-levy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Voters-ok-olentangy-levy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sriram fulfills 2016 valedictorian dream</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, the only Olentangy High School student to qualify as a Class of 2016 valedictorian is Adithya Sriram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a young age, Sriram was already learning at a pace to become valedictorian, taking AP Calculus AB his freshman year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Needless to say, I did study a lot. I made a point to make sure I was always as prepared as I could be for big tests, so I was never reluctant to put in the time. I also studied in groups which made it a lot easier. I never got a tutor, but I did seek out extra help from teachers anytime I needed it,” Sriram said via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing about the valedictorian title as a freshman, Sriram sought advice from his guidance counselor, Michael Naveau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It takes a tremendous amount of work to achieve the marks to become valedictorian,” Guidance department head Michael Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sriram went on to take 15 APs total in four years. Somehow, he still has free time after his rigorous school schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I play Varsity tennis as a spring sport and play recreational tennis year-round. I play violin, I’m in chamber orchestra at school and in the Columbus Symphony Youth Orchestra. I’m also involved in robotics and biophysics research down at The Ohio State University,” Sriram said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Sriram was the sole qualified valedictorian announced last semester, co-valedictorians could join Sriram by the end of the year. To become valedictorian, school policy states “a student must have attended OHS for their entire fifth through eighth semesters,” score all As and carry the highest GPA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It just so happened that at the end of the seventh semester, one student made the qualifications. However, it’s possible if more seniors meet them at the end of the eighth semester, we could have more valedictorians,” Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For seniors with similar lofty goals, hope is not lost. School handbook policy on the topic refers to plural “valedictorians,” due to “the probability that the above criteria will result in more than one senior being recognized as valedictorian.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Sriram-fulfills-2016-validictorian-dream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Sriram-fulfills-2016-validictorian-dream/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Haikus to summarize senior year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope FAFSA comes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In clutch or imma strip to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pay off college debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior year is meant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fun? Tell that to all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of my AP classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last tests taken, last&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadlines made, last goodbyes said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As last days pass by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The senior deadlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are killing graduation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vibes these last few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senioritis KILLS…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPAs for the sake of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning the shootout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last days will soon be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distant memories for our&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 class.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Haikus-to-summarize-senior-year/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Haikus-to-summarize-senior-year/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring-cleaning a worldwide phenomenon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other season motivates those suffering from chronic disorganization like the one at present. But what inspires us to make our living space just as beautiful as it is outside? Is it the budding greenery, or the fear of pollen and collected dust hijacking our sinuses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We clean in the spring to get clutter out of the house, and start new for the season,” Emma W. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever one’s personal motivations, the practice itself spans across cultures. The cleaning ritual of Khaneh-Tekani—or “shaking house”—is meant to prep the home for the Persian, Iranian and Zoroastrian New Year called Nowruz, according to &lt;a href=&quot;howstuffworks.com&quot;&gt;howstuffworks.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its origins, Thailand’s festival Songkran was a time to clean and to show respect for elders, by pouring water used to clean Buddha statues onto them. This cleansing tradition has since modernized into a mass water gun fight in the streets, since temperatures can reach up to 100 degrees in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the week of Passover, Jews eat the flatbread “matzo” in remembrance of the Israelites’ escape from slavery. People may burn, give away or donate chametz to get rid of it, on top of cleaning their house thoroughly. Having chametz, products used to make bread rise, in the house during Passover is frowned upon. However, this is not synonymous in every Jewish household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My great grandparents never did any of that and they were very religious. It’s more of an orthodox thing. It depends on the person and how religious they are,” Julianna Kickbusch ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring cleaning takes place in varying degrees of cleanliness, whether it be the soul, the body or the home. Yet the theme of clean seems to be universal wherever we come from, and whatever we do or do not celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/spring-cleaning-a-worldwide-phenomenon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/spring-cleaning-a-worldwide-phenomenon/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Cursed child&quot; lights new wand this Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An eighth installment of the Harry Potter series comes to London’s Palace Theatre this summer in two parts, called “Cursed Child.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a Gothic theatre. There’s a majesty there, and it has this Hogwarts feel to it,” “Cursed Child” playwright Jack Thorne said via &lt;a href=&quot;pottermore.com&quot;&gt;pottermore.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thorne and Tony award-winning director John Tiffany collaborated with J.K. Rowling to create the play. They would be hard-pressed to say no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d asked my three nephews and my grandchildren whether I should do this show. They’d all gone through Harry Potter, and they all said ‘We’ll kill you if you don’t,’” Tiffany said, according to pottermore.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many rumors followed the announcement of “Cursed Child.” Rowling responded via Twitter to false reports of a prequel and a botched title “Unearthly Child” reported by Radio Times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jk_rowling/status/703562900464640000?lang=en&quot;&gt;“Not a prequel. Not unearthly. Magical,” Rowling said on Twitter.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The play stars a grown-up Harry Potter, according to &lt;a href=&quot;harrypottertheplay.com&quot;&gt;harrypottertheplay.com&lt;/a&gt;. An aging Potter, played by Jamie Parker, is dissatisfied with his Ministry of Magic desk job while his fame tortures youngest son, Albus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowling also defended the decision to cast Olivier award-winner and black actress Noma Dumezweni as Hermione. The heroine’s race was never identified in the books, yet some fans are making a ruckus about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Diversifying the character makes Hermione a better character because [she] has more differences to overcome with race and wizard power and sexism,” Erin Devine ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, no one complained about the lack of red pigment in actor Paul Thornley’s hair, who plays Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re all preoccupied with race and women’s physical appearance in the media. Yet Harry had blue eyes instead of green in the movie, and now Ron is different. It just shows [boys appreciate the character’s true value over the character’s appearance]. No one cares about Rupert Grint,” Devine said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To monitor the arrival of the play, visit harrypottertheplay.com for more up-to-date information on the show’s development and a countdown to the release. For those unable to see their favorite characters come to life onstage, the play’s script book comes out July 31 this summer. But the new mode of writing could damage the Harry Potter reading experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s so many of the books that you become accustomed to a certain writing style. To change that at the very end might make it difficult for readers to enjoy,” school librarian Kaelin Harrison said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/cursed-child-lights/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/cursed-child-lights/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Reasons to Vote for Vermin Supreme! in 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 February issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sat·ire    ˈsaˌtī(ə)r/     noun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the use of humor, irony, exaggeration, or ridicule to expose and criticize people’s stupidity or vices, particularly in the context of contemporary politics and other topical issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s the 2016 presidential candidate you never heard of, but wish you did. &lt;a href=&quot;https://verminsupreme2016.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Vermin Love Supreme&lt;/a&gt;—his legal name—and his zany wizard style cannot be topped. Not even a certain presidential hopeful with a bad haircut can trump Supreme, and here are 10 reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are you indecisive? Then Vermin Supreme is the candidate for you. His campaign slogan delivers the promise: “The decision to vote for Vermin Supreme! is the last decision you will ever have to make.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are you a Doomsday Prepper? If so, you would be ahead of the curve under Supreme’s regime. With the zombie apocalypse fast approaching, no other candidate is more concerned for the country’s welfare than the King of the Rats.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you reject conventional weddings? Supreme is a certified minister for the Universal Life Church and licensed to officiate marriage ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always wanted a pony, but worried about money? As a member of the Pony Party, Supreme intends to rescue the economy by requiring everyone to own a pony. He claims this tactic will increase jobs, lower fossil fuel emissions and serve as a government-issued identification for citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you brush your teeth? Clean chompers may be rewarded under Supreme’s proposed mandatory tooth brushing law, which aims to combat “moral and oral decay.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you appreciate the magical properties of glitter? Supreme used the power of gold glitter to turn Republican candidate Randall Terry “gay” in 2011. A recording of the ritual can be found on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you despise conventional fashion? The signature wide-calf rubber boot he wears as a hat may strike a chord in your own rebellious sole.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you despise protest violence? According to cnn.com, Supreme diffused tension between police and 2012 Florida protesters with humor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are you in denial of Dumbledore’s death? Of course you are. Let the leadership of this wizard doppelganger console your grief.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not care about the political process, anyway? You might as well give up any rights you still have by electing this self-described “friendly fascist.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/01/10-Reasons-to-vote-for-Vermin-Supreme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/02/01/10-Reasons-to-vote-for-Vermin-Supreme/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New year, new pool, very cool</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 January issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sat·ire     ˈsaˌtī(ə)r/     noun
the use of humor, irony, exaggeration, or ridicule to expose and criticize people’s stupidity or vices, particularly in the context of contemporary politics and other topical issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lewis Center, OH—Swimmers spent their first practice of the year on Monday, Dec. 4 in the &lt;strong&gt;third-floor pool&lt;/strong&gt;, the latest sports renovation since the 2014 stadium turf installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The tiles are still very slippery. The pool hasn’t been broken in yet. You can still feel sawdust on the floor of the pool,” junior Alex Garner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, swimmers made a 23-minute drive to practice at the Delaware YMCA—a 7 ½ mile trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now we don’t have to waste as much gas to get to practice,” Garner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While saving on gas is an undeniable perk, the new &lt;strong&gt;third-floor&lt;/strong&gt; facilities also allow more privacy for the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before, we shared locker rooms with the public. Now we have locker rooms of our own,” Garner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The much-anticipated &lt;strong&gt;third-floor pool&lt;/strong&gt; and additional exercise opportunities opened December 2015 to the general public for those willing to pay membership fees. But due to years of misinformation, many freshmen are missing out on the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the past, the pool has been a joke,” Oshra Gadkar ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past semester, the class of 2019 drowned in punch lines from their older peers, the most popular being the third-floor swimming pool. Fact or fiction aside, the urban legend coming to life is somewhat of a relief from the constant grilling of poor freshmeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I heard rumors about the pool, but I was never fooled. Incoming freshmen won’t get scammed anymore, but I don’t think they’d fall for it anyway,” Varun G. ‘19 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upperclassmen seem to view the phenomenon as a benefit rather than a concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you tried to tell the freshmen there really is a pool now, they wouldn’t believe it and would never even try to go up there. It would become an all upperclassmen pool, which would be sweet,” Madalen Medovich ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the existence of the mysterious pool continues to be debated, the swim team faced off against Dublin Scioto Friday, Jan. 7—their first meet at the new location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: There is no third floor pool. Any mentions of the third-floor pool can be replaced with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountcarmelhealth.com/&quot;&gt;Mount Carmel Fitness Center&lt;/a&gt; and still make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;amp;A with Olentangy High School Dean of Students Brad Henry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How much money did it cost to install?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: I think it was a tax-free deal. We got a donation from one of our generous parents who helped us put it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How can students get to the pool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: The elevator, by the Wigwam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Does school dress code apply at the pool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Speedos are okay, as long as the boys aren’t wearing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Any rules or conditions regarding the third-floor pool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Just that students go to the fourth floor and try to use it as a high dive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/New-year-new-pool-very-coolmd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/New-year-new-pool-very-coolmd/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Health measured on a greater scale</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 January issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the ball made its annual drop in Madison Square Garden, the nationwide quest for fitness began—but the resolution to be healthy often isn’t for the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People who make a New Year’s resolution to lose weight don’t go about it the right way, because they only care about what they look like,” Jake R. said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our culture, appearance—weight in particular—is a supposed measurement of overall health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Society’s idea of attractiveness isn’t as attainable for some people, and that’s not fair,” Jake R. said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others are not as empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everyone is different. But sometimes the gains don’t agree with you,” Megan C. ’17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But weight isn’t a reliable tool of determining how healthy someone is, according to neuroscientist Sandra Aamodt’s 2013 TEDTalk, “Why dieting doesn’t usually work.” A person’s health is in fact more dependent on the number of healthy choices made on a regular basis, rather than the number of pounds on the scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a person below or meeting a “normal” weight range surviving on junk food and TV alone is more likely to develop a chronic disease than someone overweight taking daily walks and meeting their recommended fruit and vegetable intake—whether or not they lose weight in the process. However, making unhealthy choices on top of being overweight or obese is when chronic diseases like diabetes and heart disease come out to play. This deadly combination increases disease likelihood by three times the normal amount of risk, Aamodt said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If long-term disease prevention isn’t enough to tweak resolutions, preventing short-term sickness may be more convincing. Sickness is one less stressor for people making healthy choices, school psychologist Alison Armstrong said. Nutrient-dense foods and regular exercise strengthen the immune system, leaving the body less susceptible to illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with resiliency against the common cold, a healthy lifestyle can ward off a bad mood. Exercise prompts neurotransmitters to fire faster, which in turn “increase brain chemicals related to having an elevated mood,” Armstrong said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the first step is harder for those with depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you are clinically depressed, it is often very hard to get yourself to [exercise]. But the benefits are there,” Armstrong said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the more obvious physical benefits, greater confidence in what you and your body can do is the greatest advantage gained from making better choices—not losing weight. Well-being is measured on a more complicated scale than attractiveness, and resolving to be healthier just to change how you look on the outside won’t change how you feel on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/Health-measured-on-a-greater-scale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/Health-measured-on-a-greater-scale/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More vegans raise forks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VEGAN: &lt;strong&gt;A person who chooses to not eat meat or other animal products (dairy, eggs) because of health and/or moral and environmental reasons.&lt;/strong&gt; Many vegans don’t wear leather under similar logic. Six percent of the U.S. population is vegan, according to the 2015 Nutrition Business Journal Food Tribes Report—a number which has tripled in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the veg-curious, science teacher and vegan-leaning vegetarian Julie Pinney advises to, “take small steps at a time or you’ll end up crash dieting. Stick to white meat, then eventually wean yourself off.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consult a nutritionist to avoid protein deficiency and other health problems before becoming vegan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VEGETARIAN WITH VEGAN TENDENCIES: &lt;strong&gt;“I don’t drink milk. I don’t eat yogurt. Cheese is probably the only reason I don’t consider myself a full vegan.” — Science teacher Julie Pinney&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: “I have to be careful about how much protein I get,” Pinney said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinney relies on protein-packed nuts, hummus and organic burritos. Going out to eat can also be a challenge, but Pinney can always count on Mediterranean restaurants like Greek Express on Polaris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VEGETARIAN: &lt;strong&gt;“I became a vegetarian because it’s healthier, not because of animal cruelty. I didn’t eat much meat anyway.” — Gwendolyn Kunz ‘17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: Protein is the greatest concern. Kunz found forms of protein in foods like bean burgers and tofu, but the time and money needed to discover these new foods is sometimes too great a cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s too much effort,” Alyssa K. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;PESCATARIAN: &lt;strong&gt;A person who does not eat meat, but relies on seafood as a primary source of protein.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: Some fish have high amounts of mercury and other chemicals, which pose health risks to consumers. Overfishing is another environmental concern. But when sourced responsibly, fish can be a great source of omega-3s as well as protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MEAT EATER: &lt;strong&gt;“Meat tastes good. If it was easier to be a vegan or vegetarian, I’d do it.” — Faiz Jafri ‘17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: The World Health Organization (WHO) deemed processed meat an “established carcinogen” and the 2015 Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee recommended a “movement toward less resource-intensive diets” grounded in plants, grains and legumes rather than meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/more-vegans-raise-forks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/more-vegans-raise-forks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snowboarding is rad, Skiing is sad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snowboarding is cooler than its polar opposite. With its origins in surfing, how could skiing compete?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, snowboarders are a nuisance to skiers, but it’s because skiers are so uptight in comparison. Snowboarders take time to enjoy the view from the top while strapping up, while skiers are so anxious to hop off the chairlift and get to the bottom as fast as they can. Snowboarders criss-crossing down the slope revel in the satisfying feeling of snow under their board, while skiers fast-forward to the end, not bothering to enjoy the journey. However, it’s not their fault for being in such a hurry; those uncomfortable ski boots would make anyone scramble over a hill as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skiers may reach faster speeds, but snowboarding tricks are still more entertaining to see. Who watches skiing in the X Games when they can watch Shaun White or Ohio-raised snowboarder Louie Vito shred up the snow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Snowboarding is more fun to watch than skiing. They can do better tricks,” Michael Savoldi ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While snowboarding has higher street cred than skiing, it is also surprisingly safer. According to snowboarding-essentials.com, snowboarding is kinder on the knees. While snowboarding does leave the wrists more vulnerable in a bad fall, this can be easily avoided with wrist guards and proper form. Although skiers and snowboarders nationwide are susceptible to similar amounts of catastrophic injuries, skiers are still more likely to die from a serious accident, according to the National Ski Area Association.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s too bad skiers can’t use their lame poles to propel their minds around how rad snowboarding is. The rivalry between the two sports has gone on for what seems like forever, but skiers will always shake their pole sticks at snowboarders for having more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/Snowboarding-is-rad-skiing-is-sad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/Snowboarding-is-rad-skiing-is-sad/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The evolution of social media</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, social media has enriched the lives of its users by allowing them to connect and share with others a couple clicks away. However, it also carries a potential to make life more complicated, with Twitter fights and direct messages gone awry. Here is a look at how social media has changed over time and continues to evolve, yet still borrows from preceding programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early 1980s: The Bulletin Board System, or BBS, becomes popular with nerds and outcasts. Although technology of the time limits its capabilities, users are still able to send messages similar to Remind101, as well as download files and games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late 1980s: CompuServe, a communication system reserved for business purposes, is released to the public market. AOL is released not long after, with the first communities of members and member profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1995: &lt;a href=&quot;classmates.com&quot;&gt;Classmates.com&lt;/a&gt; enables users to find former classmates. Today, the site has over 57 million accounts, according to &lt;a href=&quot;digitaltrends.com&quot;&gt;digitaltrends.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1997: &lt;a href=&quot;SixDegrees.com&quot;&gt;SixDegrees.com&lt;/a&gt; launches, based on the six degrees of separation theory: a person is a mere six steps away from being connected to any other given person. In 2000, the site shuts down; the failure is attributed to the over-spamming of users to invite friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2002: &lt;a href=&quot;Friendster.com&quot;&gt;Friendster.com&lt;/a&gt; allows users to find friends in a similar matchmaking process to modern dating sites. When the social media aspect of the site lost considerable traffic, it focused on online games instead before shutting down in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.friendster.com/&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2003: LinkedIn and MySpace become popular. While MySpace fell from a household name to social networking for musicians and bands, LinkedIn continues to be a mainstream business networking tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2006: Facebook is released to the public, after being restricted to the Harvard campus for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2007: Another FaceBook launch introduces the “Like” button on Facebook and Twitter, Facebook’s adopted sibling site. Google changes the social media game with Google+’s live video chat “hangouts,” and FaceBook scrambles to replicate this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010-2015: Mobile-based apps such as Instagram, Snapchat and dating apps based on location rule the social media sphere – yet Facebook still reigns supreme with 1,490 million users, according to &lt;a href=&quot;statista.com&quot;&gt;statista.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future: Virtual reality in social media may be in reach in a few years, with the Oculus virtual reality headset and Google Glasses already making gains in this area. Developers hope to someday immerse all five senses of users in experiencing games, live sports and even while speaking to friends in holographic form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/The-evolution-of-social-media/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/The-evolution-of-social-media/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to shop and survive in the thrift store jungle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 October issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step One: STALK YOUR PREY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you seek a few classic pieces or the latest trend blasted from the past (we’re looking at you, dad sandals), you must have an idea of what you want before even stepping into the mod-print rainforest that is Goodwill. So, do your fashion homework! Read up on trends coming back into style or reference entire time periods for your style inspiration. Shopping with a half-baked goal in mind will suppress any urges to impulse buy green gator shoes at half its original 1980s price—or pass on the hunt for a bargain altogether. The latter is where inexperienced hunters fail to understand the full reality of a thrift store, led astray by the Macklemore hit single—there will be rows upon inevitable rows of your grandad’s clothes, and not all of them will look incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Two: PROWL THE AISLES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skim the entire store the moment you hit the linoleum tile. Once this is completed, move in for the kill and target specific clothing sections. While examining each individual hanger is the most thorough approach, consider each article of clothing quickly. Otherwise, you will have miraculously aged faster than your purchases upon exiting the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Three: DON’T BE AFRAID TO EXPLORE THE UNKNOWN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outer layers, ambiguous jackets or coats in particular, are notorious for being disorganized. Regardless of gender, check both the men’s and women’s sections for a hidden gem not yet copped. Also, hello? Oversized men’s sweaters? Need I say more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Four: CLEAN YOUR KILL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Goodwill does dry clean all of their fabric items, you may still want to wash your (new?) clothing purchases anyway for the sake of comfort. The smell of your family’s detergent will smell more familiar than a secondhand scent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STEP FIVE: WEAR IT WITH PRIDE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finally rock your thrifted finds, do so with the confidence that you made a purchase friendly to your wallet, the environment and your community. The stigma surrounding thrift stores may be off-putting, but only increases your chances of finding a diamond purchase out of the rough interior of the thrift store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/How-to-shop-and-survive-in-the-thrift-store-jungle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/How-to-shop-and-survive-in-the-thrift-store-jungle/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sister hikers get lost, then found</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 September issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;285, 505 acres. Three sisters. One hiking trip gone wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gros Ventre Wilderness Area in Moose, WY is most known for where the infamous Andrews-Sharer sisters went missing and since been found in the summer of 2015, but not before their story spread worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sisters left for the trip June 28, to hike the trail that Tuesday. They planned to be in the woods for five days and hike back out to their car on July 4. They were officially lost for six days, July 4 until July 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As experienced hikers, they had all the essentials to survive. They did everything right, speaking with rangers beforehand to ensure their safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The park ranger recommended the trail we went on because it was the most-used. We figured we would see people, and the trail would be maintained like a national park,” Kelsi Andrews-Sharer ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nothing like they thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The trail was a small game-hunting trail along a mountain cliff. The meadowgrasses overcrowded the path and came up to our necks, making it hard to see,” Andrews-Sharer said. “But my sisters are both experienced in reading maps and using a compass, so we fared pretty well for most of the trip.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday afternoon, they decided to follow a shorter loop on the map than planned, since they moved slower than anticipated that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had been hiking hard for four days, but I had not yet acclimatized to the altitude,” Andrews-Sharer said. “Then we came upon an avalanche of rocks covering the trail. We planned to hike back to our previous campsite, then to a sign we’d passed before on the edge of the Wilderness Area and hike to our car from there. But the trail we took to retrace our steps began to veer off in a different direction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They knew they were lost, but more immediate problems loomed on the horizon. The sun was to go down in an hour and a half, when they found fresh mountain lion pawprints. They acted fast to pitch their tent for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The next morning my sister Megan, the most experienced hiker, decided the safest choice was to stop and get help,” Andrews-Sharer said. “We thought our parents would be waiting for us to call in the morning, and when they didn’t get the call they would start searching immediately.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three stayed optimistic while they waited but took precautions to ration food, build a signal fire, set out colored gear and make right angles with fallen trees as an SOS to any aircraft flying overhead. But when they weren’t rescued Saturday night, they began to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We realized we hadn’t explained to our parents exactly where we were hiking before we left for the trip,” Andrews-Sharer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday came and went, with hopes of being rescued unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When our food supply became dangerously low, we found strength in our faith… We all realized we could very possibly die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday morning, the sisters sat freezing in their tent, bodies too weak from starvation to keep warm. In mid-prayer for a helicopter, they heard two fly overhead, the second one spotting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It hovered over us, and we were screaming and crying and our bodies were shaking,” Andrews-Sharer said. “Five minutes after getting into the helicopter, we were in our dad’s arms.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never take the little things for granted. They are what matter in the end. Food, showers, hugs from your parents, late night conversations with a friend, laughing so hard your stomach aches. Life is short and tentative, so take chances. You might not get them again,” Andrews-Sharer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against all odds, fear did not trump these sisters’ love of backpacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re planning on hiking again next summer,” Andrews-Sharer said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/sister-hikers-get-lost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/sister-hikers-get-lost/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 Olentangy HS Fall Sports Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 September issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boys Golf:&lt;/strong&gt; After players came up to par in OCC’s, the boys prepare to dominate in the Delaware County Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a major rivalry event that goes back 25 years, and we have won this event more than any other school,” head coach Joel Glassburn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Football:&lt;/strong&gt; The defending OCC champs swept Westerville South with a score of 41-17. They also did well in the preseason scrimmages, with a tie against St. Edwards High School and a 17-7 win against Pickerington Central High School. The boys have big plans for this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to win the state championship,” Jimmy Elmurr ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boys Cross Country:&lt;/strong&gt; The boys placed third place at Mt. Vernon, with top finisher Anthony Sasso ‘17 taking eighth place in the team race. New head coach Ken Whalen experienced leading his first high school cross country team in a meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I coached many of the runners as middle schoolers, so I know what needs to be done to push them to their full potential,” Whalen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whalen coached the middle school cross country team for eight years, was on staff for the middle school boys track program for seven and assistant-coached the boys and girls distance track team for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He is really making an effort to understand the strengths and weaknesses of the team, to get us in optimal shape for districts and hopefully beyond,” Tyler Reed ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Cross Country: The 87-strong team placed second at Mt. Vernon. The exploding number of the team is double the challenge for captains and coaches, where new assistant coach Kaitlin Rever comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Size is a challenge, but top athletes only get better with more teammates challenging and pushing them forward,” Rever said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rever, a 1990 Olentangy alumni with 20 years of coaching experience, has taken multiple teams to states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Coach Rever is very supportive and encouraging,” Krescens K. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Volleyball: After losing their first two matches, all three teams won matches against Big Walnut Aug. 27 and Dublin Scioto Aug. 29.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had a bumpy start, but we are now playing well after our opening conference,” head coach Michelle Mimna said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Varsity team also beat Orange Sept. 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re expecting a good season,” Katelyn Petrycki ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Tennis:  2014 state quarter finalists Brianna Brdicka ‘16 and Kathleen J. ‘18 are serving aces and taking names. They are the first ever players of any OHS tennis team or individual to win the first Doubles Division of the Watterson Invitational, according to the school athletics website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t want to get overconfident, but we definitely hope to place at states,” Brdicka said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Golf: Kara Raines ‘17 finished sixth out of 66 golfers at the Midwest Classic in Canton with a score of 82, with the team finishing ninth out of 18 teams in the tournament, head coach John Feasel said. Raines and Alexandra Cardi ‘17 are the players to watch for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They are two of the best golfers the team has ever seen, and they are only juniors,” Feasel said. “If they make it to districts it would be the first time in school history.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Field Hockey: Varsity Captain Allison Martin ‘17 and Junior Varsity player Emma B. ‘18 each scored a goal on state champion Thomas Worthington Aug. 24, the first time in the school’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was refreshing to see the ball hit the back of the goal and know we are capable of scoring against a powerhouse team in our division,” Martin said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also a first, 14 seniors return to play this year, the highest retention rate ever for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As long as they continue to push themselves to be better, anything is possible,” head coach Biz Brehm said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boys Soccer: The Varsity team won 1-0 against Big Walnut Sept. 1 with a goal by Corey Sweet ‘17, cheered on by new assistant defensive coach Dan Ensign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s good at explaining tactics,” Ryan R. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite a rough start to the season, Ensign still saw the team’s potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had the pieces needed to make a great starting lineup, we just needed to sort out who plays what after so many graduating seniors last year,” Ensign said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Soccer: Last season, the girls team won their first OCC Championship since 1999. They also took home First Regional Finalists, 12 individual awards, and an OCC Coach of the Year award for head coach Megan Kirsten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re prepared to live up to how we did last year,” Ireland Fallona ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Varsity team won their season opener 1-0 against Thomas Worthington, goal courtesy of Stephanie Burzinski ‘16. With another goal by Julia F. ‘18, Varsity beat Big Walnut 1-0 in a game Sept. 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/Olentangy-HS-fall-sports-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/Olentangy-HS-fall-sports-review/</guid>
      </item>
    

    
      
        
      
    
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Resume</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:murdocc3@miamioh.edu&quot;&gt;murdocc3@miamioh.edu&lt;/a&gt; or view my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/in/chloe-m-275197133&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;education&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018-2021 — current student at &lt;strong&gt;Miami University&lt;/strong&gt; in Oxford, Ohio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;majoring in Journalism and International Studies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3.6 cumulative GPA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 — Graduated from Olentangy High School&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3.7 cumulative GPA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;experience&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 2019 - July 2019: writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kosovalive360.com//?s=Chloe+Murdock&quot;&gt;KosovaLive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 2019 - July 2019: undergraduate assistant for Miami University journalism course, “The Role of Journalism in a Democracy,” in Kosovo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edited long-form pieces of inexperienced writers and recommended next steps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Led class discussions and provided materials for professor, Dr. Richard Campbell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 2017 - Present: marketing intern at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abb.com/&quot;&gt;ABB Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Editing and formatting brochures that enhance ABB sales interactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing internal success stories and scripts for videos and video teasers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Project managed, acted in and wrote the script for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ut79jmyeimx9tou/ServiceSells%20FINAL%20High%20Quality.mp4?dl=0&quot;&gt;promotional video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing order announcements
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abb.com/cawp/seitp202/41e785445f004da8c1258154006c22c3.aspx&quot;&gt;Monarch Cement purchases ABB upgrade to improve operator interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://medcoenergi%20renews%20abb%20oil%20and%20gas%20care/&quot;&gt;MedcoEnergi renews ABB Oil and Gas Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abb.co.in/cawp/seitp202/3f90f076010a97a6c125818600649f83.aspx&quot;&gt;ArcelorMittal evolution path leads to ABB Ability upgrades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abb.com/cawp/seitp202/fc80eb99040d282bc12582ab0063d059.aspx&quot;&gt;Self-maintaining plant opens up for ABB services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://new.abb.com/news/detail/5887/pge-capital-group-renews-abb-care-adds-control-systems-services&quot;&gt;PGE Capital Group renews ABB Care, adds control system services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/abbindustryserv?lang=en&quot;&gt;@abbindustryserv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project managing an internal marketing campaign and drafting campaign emails through Constant Contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 2018 - Present: Contributing editor and writor for &lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.miamistudent.net/&quot;&gt;The Miami Student Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November 2018 - December 2018: Social media manager for The Miami Student magazine &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/miamistudentmag?lang=en&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/miamistudentmagazine/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September 2017 - Present: Writer for The Miami Student &lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/author/chloe-murdock/&quot;&gt;newspaper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.miamistudent.net/tortillas-and-motorcycles-my-family-its-memories-and-the-opinions-in-between/&quot;&gt;magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured in The Miami Student Magazine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.miamistudent.net/real-life-fairy-godmothers/&quot;&gt;Real-life fairy godmothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.miamistudent.net/tortillas-and-motorcycles-my-family-its-memories-and-the-opinions-in-between/&quot;&gt;Tortillas and motorcycles: My family, its memories and the opinions in between&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.miamistudent.net/nowhere-to-turn/&quot;&gt;Nowhere to turn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured in the Culture section of The Miami Student newspaper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/a-medieval-club-in-no-mans-land/&quot;&gt;A medieval club in no man’s land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/mufd-combines-style-and-sustainability/&quot;&gt;MUFD combines style and sustainability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/people-are-finally-talking-about-the-elephants-in-the-room/&quot;&gt;People are finally talking about the Elephants in the Room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/april-poetry-contest-buds-into-spring/&quot;&gt;April poetry contest buds into spring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/ballroom-dance-club-finds-footing-in-new-roles/&quot;&gt;Ballroom dance club finds footing in new roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/womens-self-defense-class-a-rank-above-the-rest/&quot;&gt;Women’s self-defense class a rank above the rest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/first-year-shock/&quot;&gt;Missing home and hot tortillas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured in the Opinion section of The Miami Student newspaper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/and-marie-antoinette-said-let-them-go-vote/&quot;&gt;And Marie Antoinette said, “Let them go vote!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/ask-me-are-you-sure-again-i-dare-you/&quot;&gt;Ask me, “Are you sure?” again, I dare you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured in the News section of The Miami Student newspaper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miamistudent.net/central-park-five-member-speaks-on-institutionalized-racism/&quot;&gt;Central Park Five member speaks on institutionalized racism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 2019 - Present: Vice President of Miami University Martial Arts Club&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weighing in on club executive board decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning alumni events, taekwondo performances and other club gatherings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Announcing at festivals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 2018 – February 2019: PR Chair for Miami University Martial Arts Club&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created and implemented a recruitment campaign plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Posted relevant Facebook and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MartialMiami&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; content that aligns with recruitment campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016-2017 Olentangy High School’s The Beacon magazine: Editor-in-chief, Writer, Designer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/01/Get-off-the-couch-see-these-movies&quot;&gt;Get off the couch, see these movies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/04/19/Students-foundation-creates-change-in-india-slums/&quot;&gt;Student’s foundation creates change in India slums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/01/Attraction-turns-scientific/&quot;&gt;Attraction turns scientific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/12/01/Holidays-draw-out-religious-differences/&quot;&gt;Holidays draw out religious differences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/01/Powerschool-helps-harms-student-stress/&quot;&gt;Powerschool helps, harms student stress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/01/Cesar-Chaves-day-withstands-todays-political-climate/&quot;&gt;Cesar Chavez Day withstands today’s political climate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015-2016 Online Olentangy High School’s The Beacon magazine – Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Islamophobia in the 21st century&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohsbeacon.com/688/sports/new-coach-returns-to-alma-mater/&quot;&gt;New coach returns to alma mater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015-2016 Olentangy High School’s The Beacon magazine – Writer / Designer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sriram fulfills 2016 valedictorian dream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voters OK 2016 Olentangy Levy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haikus to summarize senior year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Cursed Child” lights new wand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spring-cleaning a worldwide phenomenon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 reasons to vote for Vermin Supreme! in 2016&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health measured on a greater scale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New year, new pool, very cool (satire)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowboarding is rad, skiing is sad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More vegans raise forks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The evolution of social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2015 Olentangy High School Fall Sports Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sister hikers get lost, then found&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to shop and survive in the thrift store jungle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;awards&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 — James L. McCann Excellence in High School Journalism Award&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 – “Superior” and “Excellent” ratings from the Ohio Scholastic Media Association&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 – three “Honorable Mentions” from the Ohio Scholastic Media Association&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Won first place in Power of the Pen competition while representing Olentangy Shanahan Middle School&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Won essay contest to present wreath on the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interests&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interests&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling, snowboarding, kayaking, paddle boarding, reading, volunteer work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/Resume.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m an intern as well as a college student, majoring in journalism and international studies. Whether I’m writing a news article, a feature story, a press release or a script, I set out to turn complicated topics into stories anyone can read. I will complete any assignment, but I especially love my job when I get to work with stories that make people think, act, feel or do all three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is my virtual portfolio. Explore my resume and past work to see what I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/about.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
