<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chloe Murdock</title>
    <description>Virtual portfolio of Chloe Murdock</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:39:24 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:39:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>

    
      <item>
        <title>Divided mining complex oxidizes amid multiple truths</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prishtina, KOSOVO—More than just a bridge on the Ibër/Ibri River splits Mitrovica, Kosovo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In South Mitrovica, the sky mixes with flags from Kosovo, the United States and Albania. People exchange euros for espresso and rakia, a strong brandy of the Balkans. Cars blow past street signs labeled in both Albanian and Serbian, though the street names have changed so many times that people tell taxi drivers to stop at landmarks instead of addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across the bridge to the north, drivers and passerby read only Cyrillic letters of the Serbian language on street signs, storefronts, food labels, anti-Kosovo graffiti and billboards thanking Russian President Vladimir Putin. People exchange Serbian dinars for coffee and plum brandy instead of euros. Russian and Serbian flags flap against the wind and hang from every building in the city center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Trepça is as divided as the city whose economy it used to power, and this split has created multiple truths and segmented production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serbians in Kosovo have collected themselves into enclaves throughout the country. A barricaded bridge divides North Mitrovica and the rest of northern Kosovo, which has a high Serbian concentration, from South Mitrovica and below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trepça/Trepča mining complex spans both sides of this divided city, and before 1999, the two sides of Trepça/Trepča worked together. Zveçan/Zvečan, near North Mitrovica, received all lead concentrate, while South Mitrovica received all zinc concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new production line churns in the south Stan Terg/Stari Trg flotation facility in South Mitrovica, next to equipment that has collected dust since the 1980s. Lead and zinc rise up from the muck and are pulled apart to what sounds like a dozen high-powered washing machines revolving at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing water leaking from an unidentified source fails to evaporate from the bottom floor. Most of the equipment is broken, too old to be updated and too expensive to be upgraded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forty years ago, the sound was 2-3 times more intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across the bridge into the north of what used to be the same city, a former zinc smelter facility rusts in the sun. Two security guards only shake their heads from behind the gate at anyone who approaches. The gate entrance is locked, and no one visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s, the Trepça/Trepča mining complex was the jewel of the Yugoslavia socialist regime. Over forty mines produced lead and zinc concentrates in addition to other minerals, though it often failed to profit because of overexpansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Trepça/Trepča’s records, its profits didn’t reach $15 million in the 1980s. A report from the Kosovo Stability Initiative says the Yugoslav Federal Fund stimulated most of Trepça/Trepča’s growth. During the socialist regime, the same report says Trepça/Trepča received $5 billion in total from the United States through this fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metallurgy and smelting plants now are neglected in North Mitrovica, Kosovo—or Serbia. The answer to the question, “Are we in Serbia or Kosovo?,” depends on who you talk to and what side you are on, though Kosovo declared independence from Serbia in 2008. Serbia does not recognize Kosovo as a country and covets the area for its historical and religious significance to Serbians and the national Orthodox Church religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to Serbian Orthodox churches throughout Kosovo that are protected as UNESCO Heritage sites, Serbia also claims to own 75% of the Trepça/Trepča mines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naim Gashi, a Radio Television of Kosovo (RTK) board member and macroeconomics professor at the University of Mitrovica, said that Serbia seeks to extend the border of Serbia past Trepça/Trepča as part of peace talks with Kosovo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Serbia intends to take these mines under its ownership through border correction,” Gashi said. “Unfortunately, the idea of border correction is supported by the President of Kosovo, who no longer has civic support.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, Kosovo operated as an autonomous province of Serbia with an ethnic Albanian and secular Muslim majority that Serbia treated as second-class citizens. This former underdog majority now runs Kosovo after surviving several rounds of ethnic cleansing in the 1990s, which led then-U.S. president Bill Clinton to urge NATO to launch a bombing campaign against Serbian soldiers on March 24, 1999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the north Bello Bërdo/Belo Brdo mine and the south Stan Terg/Stari Trg mine both produce lead and zinc concentrate but operate at a fraction of their former capacities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead concentrate is an early version of lead metal (found in materials like batteries and bullets) and lead alloys (used to harden products such as pipes and storage battery grids). Zinc concentrate is an early step before it becomes the almost final form of zinc, used to galvanize steel and make chemicals in addition to other uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Xhafer Peci, who is the manager of the Stan Terg/Stari Trg mine in the south, four of the mine’s 12 levels are in operation, though he hopes to build a 13th level if foreign investment kicks in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely does the Stan Terg/Stari Trg mine earn a profit. It faced nearly $4.8 million in 2015 losses. However, it generated $2 million (USD) in 2017 profits after offering up for sale its industrial waste—which is almost a misnomer because it is rich with valuable minerals, such as gold, silver, cadmium and bismuth, with uses that span multiple industries—via open tender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stan Terg/Stari Trg mine in the south sells its concentrate to the highest bidder for an entire year. Mineco won the open tender in 2019 and is an international company with facilities in Serbia, Bosnia and Russia that specializes in base metal mining, commodities trading and the smelting and refining of metals. Mineco receives the Stan Terg/Stari Trg’s 600 tons of lead and zinc concentrate that 650 miners and flotation workers produce every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concentrate is produced from 10,000 tons of unrefined ore that Stan Terg/Stari Trg mines every month. In 1987, the same facility mined a maximum of 700,000 tonnes per month according to Qazim Jashari, who managed the Stan Terg/Stari Trg mine during the Yugoslavia regime and is the current manager of the Stan Terg/Stari Trg flotation facility. This specific building separates lead and zinc concentrate from the rest of the ore using chemicals that cause lead and zinc to “float” to the top of the mixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ore and concentrate production in the north is less certain, since Serbian northern managers were unable to respond fully to information requests. But a 2017 report by Audit &amp;amp; Conto, a private auditing and accounting firm, noted that the north mines employ just over one thousand total workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rade Nedeljković is a retired Serbian miner who worked in the Stan Terg/Stari Trg, Bello Bërdo/Belo Brdo and Cërnac/Crnac mines between 1976 and 2017. According to him, only 30% of workers are fully employed at a time since 1999, and they rotate who gets shifts and full-time pay. Everyone else receives a pension of 11,000 Serbian dinars, which equals about $105 in U.S. dollars, from Belgrade, Serbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nedeljković also said that the Bello Bërdo/Belo Brdo and Cërnac/Crnac mines in the north do not directly sell concentrate but sell unrefined lead and zinc ore abroad, primarily to Macedonia where another unknown company finishes refining the unfinished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kemajl Zeqiri, who is chairman of the Independent Commission for Mining and Minerals (ICMM) of Kosovo, denies the former miner’s claim that the northern mines do not produce or sell lead and zinc concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zeqiri maintains that there is no market demand for ore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From an economic point-of-view, who will buy?” Zeqiri said. “Who will pay for the transport of more than 90% waste?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2017 Audit &amp;amp; Conto report also reiterated that the north mines sell “lead and zinc concentrates and a smaller amount of lead due to the impossibility of final processing, so two semi-products are considered finished products and treated as final.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danilo Rakovic, the Chief General of north Trepça/Trepča, was not available for comment. Jovan Dimkic, a manager in the north, was not available for comment. Ivan Kovacevic, an inspector from ICMM who is assigned to the Bello Bërdo/Belo Brdo and Cërnac/Crnac mines, was not available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICMM, which inspects mining facilities for safety concerns and issues licenses to all mines including those in the north, regularly grants licenses to both mines for the production of lead and zinc concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies that exploit mineral resources receive a special tax on mineral royalties. An ICMM license normally comes with a 10% discount on taxes on the total sum of mineral royalties for concentrate, which is considered a sub-product. Trepça/Trepča, however, is exempt from paying this specific tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The northern mines also receive permission from the Kosovo Ministry of Economic Development to sell concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For sure, the separation is different in the north part,” Zeqiri said. “But in terms of legislation, in terms of licensing process, it is one Trepça.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICMM oversees all of Trepça/Trepča, but Kosovo legislation does not always align with reality. Management of Trepça/Trepča is still divided between north and south Mitrovica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new supervisory board—within the Trepça/Trepča corporation—was established a year ago with the intention of installing nine total board members that oversee all of Trepça/Trepča, which is a public company. But the board still waits for three representatives to join from the north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ardian Syla is a Trepça/Trepča chairman on the supervisory board and says northern managers reach out when they don’t receive Kosovo government subsidies, when they experience bank account issues or when their exports are not approved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Only when they have some problems, major problems do we get in contact,” Syla said. “Otherwise, we don’t have an everyday cooperation or everyday contact.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Serbia and Kosovo squabble over the land, Stan Terg mine operators hope for foreign investment to kick in. It would require an approximate $150 million investment to transform Trepça/Trepča into a complex that resembles a more sustainable version of its former glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until this money appears, most of Trepça/Trepča’s 40 mines and other facilities—from smelting and metallurgy to battery production—will continue to oxidize in silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kosovalive360.com/divided-mining-complex-oxidizes-amid-multiple-truths/&quot;&gt;kosovalive360.com&lt;/a&gt; (Chloe Murdock is a reporting intern with KosovaLive this summer, in collaboration with Miami University in the United States)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 20:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/05/divided-mining-complex-oxidizes-amid-multiple-truths/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/07/05/divided-mining-complex-oxidizes-amid-multiple-truths/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A monument highlights environmental issues, but has limitations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prishtina, KOSOVO—The plastic Reclamation installation covering the Newborn monument was torn off last weekend to reveal the swirling designs of rivers, trees and recycling symbols once again. Newborn’s environment theme highlights an issue that is sometimes left as a last priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fisnik Ismaili first revealed the Newborn monument in Prishtina, Kosovo when the country gained its independence on February 17, 2008. That day, people gathered at the site to sign their names on the yellow facade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismaili and the - then Prime Minister argued after the opening, and Ismaili was not allowed to update Newborn. Five years later on the 2013 anniversary, after the monument faded with time and was buried under overlapping signatures and graffiti, the government repainted it yellow and days later, Ismaili organized 150 volunteers to paint the flags of countries who had recognized Kosovo’s independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, Kosovar citizens are annually reminded of this day when Ismaili collaborates with the Institute for the Protection of Monuments to repaint the monument with a new theme on the country’s independence anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nita Qena handpainted the entire monument herself last February and has been involved in the Newborn sign’s evolution since Ismaili, her husband, revealed it when Kosovo gained independence on February 17, 2008. She hoped to use environmentally-friendly paint to fit the theme, but Qena had to use oil-based paint in order for the design to handle all kinds of weather until the monument is repainted next February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each letter in the Newborn monument stands for a different area of environmental protection: Nature, Energy, Water, Biodiversity, Oxygen, Recycling and Nature. Beginning and ending with Nature represents the idea that every aspect is connected in a cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newborn’s annual theme reflects a new pressing issue every year. Since the beginning of the tradition in 2013, Newborn has celebrated NATO and KLA troops (2014), highlighted the diaspora (2015), tackled the issue of visa liberalization (2016), border issues (2017) and marked the 10th anniversary (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Kosovars usually link the monument with the country’s independence, not how Ismaili or anyone else transforms it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flamur Kadriu, an engineer, who passes Newborn every day, mainly associates the monument with Kosova’s independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it was placed, it created that mental environment. Whoever you ask, everyone will say it relates to independence,” Kadriu said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next year, the environmental theme will be replaced with something else, but the country’s environmental issues are not disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Luan Shllaku, who is the director of the Kosovo Foundation for Open Society and in the past has worked for the U.N. Development Programme and the World Health Organization on environmental issues, some of the largest contributors to pollution are companies and Kosovo public enterprises that exploit minerals and excavate rivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kosovo government’s climate change strategy published in 2018 notes that Kosovo is believed to contain just over 166 million tonnes of collective lead, zinc, nickel and chrome reserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s, mining and quarrying gobbled up 50 percent of Kosovo’s GDP, but the Kosovo War that ended in 1999 curbed this industrialization because industries were slow to be privatized. In 2011, mining and quarrying represented only 1,5 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shllaku, as well as the climate change survey, anticipates the rate of pollution from this “underground wealth” will only increase as Kosovo ramps up its industrialization. This increase combined with Kosovo’s small size will exacerbate effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Within 10,000 kilometers, you have what I would call four industrial giants based on mineral exploitation,” Shllaku said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industrial complexes like Trepca, KEK, Ferronikeli and Sharrcom contribute the most hazardous waste out of the 1,92 kilograms of domestic waste that Kosovo generates per capita every day, which is worsened by the lack of regulated landfills and wastewater treatment facilities in most municipalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 2016 Riinvest report detailing ways that Kosovo’s 16 municipalities could work together to improve environmental protections found that untreated wastewater from seven municipalities, including Prishtina, leaks into the Ibër River and ends up in the Sitnica River, which is the most polluted river in Europe. Kosovo’s Climate Change Strategy, published in 2018, classified Sitnica as a “‘dead river.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diellza Gashi Tresi, Riinvest advanced researcher, contributed to the above Riinvest report, which was an unusual project for an institute whose mission is to look into socioeconomic factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She attributes the root of most municipalities’ obstacles to the lack of financial investment in environmental protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When decentralization happened, municipalities were left on their own to deal with so many issues and they weren’t given enough, they aren’t given enough resources because the budget is limited,” Gashi Tresi said. “There is only so much they can do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Riinvest report, specific departments devoted only to environmental protection do not exist in most municipalities. Instead, they rely on a single environmental protection officer or merge the responsibility with a department of public services that juggles multiple missions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of these factors and in addition to a lack of inspectors, aging landfills fall into disrepair and the ability to enforce the protection of the environment, particularly when people and companies don’t follow protocol, is limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Riinvest report also noted that a lack of awareness of environmental issues causes civilians to be part of the problem, when people create illegal landfills and cut trees illegally without considering how that affects the environment and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismaili, who is also a member of Parliament and is in a working MP group for “green” issues, believes that Newborn helps to raise awareness but acknowledges its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think that raising awareness is not enough, you know,” Ismaili said. “Much more should be done about this. Not only the environment, but everything else that Newborn has stood for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kosovalive360.com/a-monument-highlights-environmental-issues-but-has-limitations/&quot;&gt;kosovalive360.com&lt;/a&gt; (Chloe Murdock is a reporting intern with KosovaLive this summer, in collaboration with Miami University in the United States)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 20:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/05/a-monument-highlights-environmental-issues-but-has-limitations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/07/05/a-monument-highlights-environmental-issues-but-has-limitations/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Newborn monument reclaimed with mixed reactions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pristina, KOSOVO—The Newborn monument’s Reclamation generated a storm of public discourse after the creator and U.S. journalist Lauren Peace installed it on Friday, June 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Fisnik Ismaili first revealed Newborn on February 17, 2008, the day of Kosovo’s independence from Serbia, Ismaili changes the facade every year on the anniversary of that historic day to represent a political issue relevant to the people. Others are allowed to enact temporary installations like Peace’s, leave signatures and their own graffiti, since it is a public space on what is now Luan Haradinaj Street in Kosovo’s capital city of Prishtina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reclamation design presented the names, faces and quotes of 99 women whose roles ranged between a high school student, a game designer and a former Kosovo president. According to a Kosovo 2.0 column by Peace, she intended to subvert the idea often presented by international media that women are not active in the workplace and other public spaces in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Ismaili, Peace received consent from the Institute for the Protection of Monuments and also consulted Ismaili on the overall concept beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismaili, who is a member of the Kosovo Parliament, did not choose the women included in the installation but expressed support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s about time that women are more recognized for their work and effort that they do here,” Ismaili said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newborn had not specifically represented women in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismaili first started changing Newborn’s theme in 2013. Previously, the government would not permit Ismaili to repaint it. Overlapping signatures and graffiti buried the faded monument before the government updated it on the 2013 anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Displeased with the result, Ismaili called for volunteers via Facebook to help him repaint the monument with the flags of countries who had already recognized Kosovo’s independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nita Qena, who has been involved with the Newborn monument since its creation as a painter and is Ismaili’s wife and business partner, said the team worked for 24 hours straight in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We started at six o’clock, and finished at six o’clock the next day,” Qena said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2013’s recognition theme, a tradition was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the monument was adorned with camo to celebrate NATO and the Kosovo Liberation Army. The year of 2015 saw Newborn remade to represent Kosovars who had left for better opportunities. Barbed wire encased blue sky and clouds on the structure in 2016 to represent visa liberalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the ‘N’ and ‘W’ in Newborn were pushed down to send the message, “No Walls,” and then the ‘B’ and ‘O’ swapped for a ‘10’ in 2018 to celebrate the country’s 10th birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qena hand-painted the monument by herself in 2019 to celebrate Kosovo’s environment with swirling natural and man-made elements in a cyclical format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reclamation installation briefly covered up this theme last week and elicited both positive and negative reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismaili noted that he heard of concerns that 2013 Olympic Gold medalist Majlinda Kelmendi was not included. While Peace said in her column that the installation was not meant to be a “Top 99” list of women, some questioned whether it was an honest representation of Kosovar women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four female activists of Haveit, a performance and protesting group, were featured on the sign. At the time that Vesa Qena, Hana Qena, Alketa Sylaj and Lola Sylaj gave permission for their names, faces and quotes to be used in the installation, Peace had not yet determined the location of Reclamation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four told Insajderi, an Albanian online news site, that they felt blindsided when Peace revealed the installation at Newborn and were angered by the lack of representation of ethnic minorities and transgender women, citing violence against transgender women and Roma women in Ferizaj and Lipjan, in addition to other women’s rights issues. In protest, the women tore their own likenesses off the sign on Tuesday, June 11, and posted it on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Haveit activists were not available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architect Lena Ahmeti saw pictures of the installation on Facebook, though she did not see the installation in person. She had not previously heard criticism of Reclamation and thought it delivered a positive message despite concern that it didn’t represent all women in Kosovo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not such a big space to represent all women in our country,” Ahmeti said. “I liked it, and I would like it if they did it again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kosovalive360.com/newborn-reclaimed-with-mixed-reactions/&quot;&gt;kosovalive360.com&lt;/a&gt; (Chloe Murdock is a reporting intern with KosovaLive this summer, in collaboration with Miami University in the United States)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 20:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/20/newborn-monument-reclaimed-with-mixed-reactions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/06/20/newborn-monument-reclaimed-with-mixed-reactions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real-life fairy godmothers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, UNITED STATES—A student once approached Vonda Reynolds with an odd question: Did Vonda want a cat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” Vonda said, confused, and continued cleaning the common rooms and restrooms of the former Mary Lyons Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda, a building and grounds assistant, later found out the student’s boyfriend had given her a kitten for her birthday. The cat was not allowed in the dorm, and the student had until 6 p.m. the next day to get rid of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resident assistants had called local animal shelters. None would take the cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the day, Vonda ran into the student again. This time, the girl was in tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was midterm week, and the student couldn’t study for exams because she had yet to find a home for the cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She begged Vonda to help: She knew no one in the building, but Vonda knew everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a good point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll see you at five o’clock,” Vonda said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda already had two cats and didn’t need another, but she showed up at 5 p.m. anyway to pick up the cat. She gave it to her niece, who named the cat Whalen and still shares pictures of the cat with the student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda’s friend and fellow building and grounds assistant, Helen Hackney, has her own story of helping a student find a new home for a pet— in her case, the student’s dad wouldn’t let him keep it at home while the student was away in college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Vonda says, she and Helen “are some good housekeepers.” They don’t have to take care of displaced pets or students, but they find themselves doing it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda and Helen are in a unique position to come across students, their messes and the occasional odd request. They are fairy godmothers with Cinderella’s job, cleaning the restrooms and common areas of their assigned building for the year while occasionally tending to students’ emotional needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Vonda first started working at Miami, she had been instructed not to interact with students. The university’s stance on this has flipped back-and-forth over the years since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Vonda tends to develop bonds with the few students she sees most regularly in Stonebridge Hall, like the pre-med major who practically lived in a study room inside the basement of Stonebridge Hall last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda would pass the study room around the time that students started waking up for their 8:30 a.m. classes and see the student through the glass, still working after huddling over her laptop and books all night. The student perked up when she saw Vonda, and they would chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Vonda sees Melina Slye, a sophomore studying psychology and neuroscience, most often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first week of classes this semester, Melina ran into Vonda almost every day around 10 a.m. before Melina added an 8:30 course to her schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I notice I don’t see her as much and I think, ‘I wonder how Vonda’s doing,’” Melina said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they still chat when Vonda runs into Melina in common rooms, typically when Melina is doing statistics homework. Vonda hopes to meet Melina’s mother, who visits often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building and grounds assistants don’t expect most students to remember them after they move into a different hall or an apartment the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes they do remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the case for Vonda’s mother, Barb Mitchell, who also worked at Miami. Greg Abbas hadn’t yet earned his doctorate in 1991. He was pursuing a bachelor’s degree in chemistry and assisted with biochemistry research in Hughes Hall. Two doors away from the lab where Greg often worked late nights, Barb Mitchell could be found relaxing in the staff break room for a quick break during her night shift cleaning Hughes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greg juggled his classes, extracurriculars and research, but didn’t have a lot of time for a social life. He had been craving social interaction when he first struck up a conversation with Barb and her coworker in the staff break room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became habit to stop by and talk about his classes, her work, their families, their travels, their friends — everything about their lives outside of Hughes Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barb kept asking about why Greg didn’t have a girlfriend, and for a long time he deflected the question. Eventually, he told her why: He’s gay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greg said it was difficult to come out to most people in the ’90s, but had a feeling that telling Barb would be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She needed to know. She deserved to know,” Greg said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first Barb was surprised, then confused. Like Greg did before he realized he was gay, Barb had “perceptions and misconceptions” about gay people. Eventually, she came to a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She said, ‘I don’t care what ya are, I just love who ya are,’” Greg said. “That’s just who Barb is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Greg graduated and left for medical school, he and Barb stayed in touch. She visited him once during his residency in Lexington, Ky., and he caught up with her in Hamilton, Ohio, for a chat over a meal in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greg became Dr. Abbas, while Barb retired in 1995 and later became a grandmother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As years went by, they heard less and less from each other, but still stay in contact through holiday cards, text messaging and Facebook likes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once, Vonda went Uptown to eat with a friend, and students bombarded their table to say hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A woman who didn’t know Vonda and her friend approached them, asking if they were famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, honey, we ain’t nobody. We’re just housekeepers,” Vonda said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman laughed. Vonda asked who she was. The woman mentioned her sister had attended Miami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the woman’s surprise, Vonda immediately named the woman’s sister, who had lived in a dorm Vonda had worked in years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people just want to do their job, collect their paycheck and go home. It’s an understandable mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Vonda and Helen sometimes can’t help but reach out to students — if not to hear their deepest secret, then at least to say hi. That connection helps the day go by more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes students don’t return their greetings until midway through the school year, but that doesn’t deter them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I like my job, first of all. But if I came in here every day and did not interact with anybody, it would be horrible,” Helen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helen has worked the morning shift in Beechwoods Hall for three years. Before that, she exclusively worked the night shift for 10 years — cleaning in Bell Tower Place, then in Shriver Hall and Armstrong Student Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda has worked in various residence halls. For a time, she cleaned academic buildings but switched back to residence halls so she could spend more time with her son, who was young at the time but is now 16 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Residents of Stonebridge Hall see Vonda regularly, while residents of Beechwoods Hall see Helen on a daily basis. It’s rare for students to see them sitting, but what students do notice is that Vonda is short, and Helen is tall. Vonda’s hair courses in waves down the sides of her head, while Helen’s flows straight. As fullfledged adults who’ve earned jobs and wrinkles, they are easy to tell apart from students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Vonda and Helen have seen their fair share of messes: Eggs stuck to the kitchenette ceiling. Furniture carried out onto the lawn. Beer cans in urinals. Furniture turned upside down. A wad of spit on the floor every day for a week until Helen sent a picture to her boss, who sent out an email and the spitting stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes Vonda and Helen find students in messes that are not part of the job description and are not so easy to clean up. This is where they sometimes step in as fairy godmother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helen once came across a student who was crying, distraught, overwhelmed. Helen asked her if she was OK, and the student said she was dealing with something her parents did. Helen stepped in: “Parents make mistakes. We don’t get a handbook for parenting.” Helen’s words calmed her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda remembers a Mary Lyons Hall RA from her first year working on campus. The RA always had her door open — sometimes with desserts — and waited for Vonda to come around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, Vonda ran into the RA, who was tearful and red-faced. Vonda consoled her — “This moment will pass. This moment will not last.” It was just what the girl needed when she didn’t have her family around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it was time for students to move out at the end of Vonda’s first year, the mother of the Mary Lyons RA was in surgery and not able to help move the student out of the dorm. Vonda pulled up her own truck to the building and helped the RA load up her belongings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had already met the girl’s parents by the time Vonda attended her graduation party. Vonda couldn’t stop crying when she left Miami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, on social media, Vonda watched the former RA move to Texas and unfold into full-fledged adulthood. The RA became a schoolteacher, got married and had kids, a future she could not have imagined when Vonda had run into her when she was just a tearful college student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, Helen and Vonda’s acts of kindness fall short of fairy godmother status. They worry about students who keep to themselves, but they can only do so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonda remembers when her colleagues who worked the night shift had to clean out and pack up the room of a student who’d died unexpectedly, then wait for a parent to pick up his things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Helen recalls working at Bell Tower Place six years ago, when workers could get a free meal after working a certain number of hours per night. One of her coworkers was a student who heavily relied on that free meal to get by. Sometimes when the student hadn’t eaten anything that day, Helen would pay for a meal for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After her junior year, the student was forced to leave Miami — she could no longer afford to attend college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students inevitably leave Miami. Helen and Vonda remain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 13:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/04/real-life-fairy-godmothers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/12/04/real-life-fairy-godmothers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>And Marie Antoinette said, &quot;let them go vote!&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION COLUMN originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/11/and-marie-antoinette-said-let-them-go-vote&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to Election Day on Nov. 6, students received plenty of encouragement to perform their civic duty, but that only took us so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The national voting campaigns, the celebrity endorsements and the handful of emails from Miami faculty worked. People lined up at the polls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we need more than cheerleaders on the sidelines while we fill in our ballots. We need a more efficient absentee voting system for those of us who vote outside of our home county or state, who don’t live close enough to a post office to vote comfortably and who belong to disenfranchised populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at my schedule on the day before Election Day, Nov. 5, as a case study:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around 1 p.m., and I had time to kill before my 2:50 class. I could have rushed to grab my absentee ballot out of my mailbox and buy postage stamps from the Package Center, but I still hadn’t eaten lunch and I had some pressing homework due that day. For once in my life, I’m on the cusp of a semester with all As and I wasn’t about to sacrifice that for what I figured wouldn’t take too long, since I live so close to the Package Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My class got out at 4:10 p.m. and I sat down in King Library for a total of two minutes before I realized I had to race home to check my mailbox. When I did, I found not only my own absentee ballot, but also that of my roommate, Sydney, and my next-door-neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sydney and I filled out our ballots. She finished before me and went to the Package Center at around 4:33 p.m., then sent the text, “Post office closed at 4.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a not-so-cute little asterisk on the Package Center sign that points to the small print, which says that the post office window is not open past 4 p.m., though it is manned by non-postal-worker staff until 5 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never in my life have I needed to buy stamps. So as an intellectual, I responded to Sydney, “FUUUUUU.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sydney had to go to class, but I decided to make the trek to the post office on Brown Road, which is a 34-minute walk from my dorm. If I took my bike, I could make it in half that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tucked my absentee ballot and Sydney’s into my sweater, since I didn’t have pockets big enough for voting-sized envelopes, and got on my bike. I didn’t even know if I could send Sydney’s ballot on her behalf, but I figured I might as well try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know exactly where this post office on Brown Road is, so I had to pull out my phone every few minutes to figure out which road I needed to take, while trying not to get hit by a car or kill any pedestrians myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy what you’re reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signup for our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email Address&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I made what would normally be a leisurely 15-minute bike trip in nine or ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to the post office at 5:01 p.m., threw my bike on the ground, and opened the door. Then I pulled on the door of the actual post office room – wow, I made it just in time – and the door was locked. There were still people in the mailroom, but the door made a sad clunking noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post office closed at 5 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was too late, and I didn’t get to vote. Neither did many others in the Miami community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is 2018. It’s not like I’m expecting world peace, but in what is supposedly the most democratic country in the world known for its convenience, I expect to be able to vote without having to sweat for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, absentee voting shouldn’t be as easy as ordering fast food, but maybe if the post office and the bureaucracy in charge of voting could learn a thing or two from the ordering process at McDonald’s, voting could become a tad more efficient and easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting should not just be made easy for this white Gen Z student, but also for people with disabilities, the elderly and poor minorities. All of these groups have been disenfranchised nationwide since 2008, when states began passing laws that suppress these votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federal, state and local institutions (including Miami) have about 351 days until next year’s Election Day to clean up their act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for me, you can bet I’ll be registered to vote in Oxford, Ohio, instead of my parents’ house, since I’ll be living in an apartment when the next election rolls around. If we hold all else equal and assume that nothing will change next year, I will at least be able to avoid this same mess in 2019 and in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 20:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/20/and-marie-antoinette-said-let-them-go-vote/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/11/20/and-marie-antoinette-said-let-them-go-vote/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Medieval Club in No Man's Land</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—First-year Daniel Melson wanted to join something he, “could only do in college.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he followed the sound of a lute into a Goggin press box at Geeks on Ice and discovered the owner, fourth-year Jack Haney, he found that something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To peasants, it’s the medieval club. But to those in the club, like Melson and Haney, it’s the Marche of the Unicorn chapter of the Society of Creative Anachronism (SCA), a nationwide organization that recreates the Middle Ages in 2018 – minus the black plague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since that meeting, Melson regularly practices rapier sword fighting, which is like fencing but with heavier swords that don’t wobble, at 7 p.m. on Mondays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The club doesn’t do live action role play, though cosplay comes with it. SCA recreates any and all things medieval: five forms of fighting, as well as “arts and sciences” like cooking, calligraphy, music-making, embroidery, blacksmithing and leatherworking. Name any activity you think has been aged out of existence from this era and SCA revives it at events for fun, as long as it is backed up with history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most people come for the fighting, but stay for arts and sciences,” said the club’s president, Emma Fleming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arts and Sciences includes research that justify SCA processes by pointing to medieval history, which can turn into books like Tobi Beck’s The Armored Rose, which advocated for allowing women to become knights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are SCA kings, queens, barons, dukes, knights and squires across the world. Kings can declare war on each other over a wrong look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCA is divided into 20 kingdoms worldwide. Kingdoms are divided into baronies, or regions. Baronies are divided into lands. To count as a land, chapter members have to attend baronial meetings in Dayton, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marche of the Unicorn used to be considered a land. Due to the current small size of the chapter – most attendees are transient, about five members come regularly while three serve as the executive board – club members don’t have time to attend these weekly meetings. So it is not officially considered part of SCA anymore. It exists in no man’s land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might not show up on an SCA map, but it still gets perks of the barony, or region: club members are covered by the barony insurance, and can ask medieval arts instructors outside of the club’s specialties to teach a class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than sporadic SCA classes and workshops on the weekends, the club is gearing up for its grand tournament on April 13, which is a festival where the club hosts fighting tournaments, music circles and other arts and science classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy what you’re reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signup for our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email Address&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The medieval club operates like a fraternity that doesn’t ask for dues, though many of the members at Monday practices graduated years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Bolenbaugh is a computer engineer in Oxford, Ohio, who graduated from Miami in 1993. He is also known as Sir Nicholas of Wicklow, an Irish Viking from the year 1000 who partakes in heavy fighting, calligraphy and illumination, creating the illustrations on edges of the calligraphy scrolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bolenbaugh was a baron for five years. He has friends from SCA who are undergraduate students now, who graduated 10 years ago and friends whom he graduated with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I walk in and I expect to know people [at SCA events],” Bolenbaugh said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attending national and regional SCA events allows members to meet a huge amount of like-minded people, whether it be on a recreated battlefield of 10,000 people or in a small music circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming, who is pursuing occupational therapy, has previously drawn on her SCA network for future and short-term job references, like her upcoming Renaissance gig as a professional fairy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We look out for each other, since we’re all in this nerdy subgroup,” Fleming said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last night’s practice, Fleming practiced in room 117 of McGuffey Hall with the intent of becoming authorized in heavy fighting at an upcoming tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heavy fighters did a simulation where each fighter had to defend against 120 total blows – the six other fighters each made 20 hits at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think every person got hit in this room by Emma, so you do not have a power problem,” Patrick Savelli said to Fleming after the drill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savelli used to be a king, but is now a duke and goes by Sir William.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in room 120, Melson and Haney sparred at last night’s practice. The butt of Melson’s sword caught Haney’s, and Melson had to be careful not to crack Haney’s blade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haney is authorized in all five forms of medieval fighting and is training Melson with the help of higher-ranking SCA members. Nonetheless, Melson got the better of Haney and caught his armpit – a kill shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melson wanted to find something he could only do in college when he followed Haney’s lute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the elder members, Melson hopes to continue rapier sword fighting through the SCA Ansteorra kingdom, which encompasses his hometown of Dallas, Texas – not only over the summer but also after he graduates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/11/a-medieval-club-in-no-mans-land&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Genevieve Dietz&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 20:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/13/a-medieval-club-in-no-mans-land/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/11/13/a-medieval-club-in-no-mans-land/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ask me &quot;Are you sure?&quot; again, I dare you</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION PIECE for The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to forget that taekwondo wasn’t created with women in mind. Even 100 years after the creation of taekwondo, there is still evidence of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The uniforms are unisex, but there is always space for a man’s junk in the front of the pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most taekwondo moves rely on a person’s strength rather than using your opponent’s strength or weight against them. This is typically not helpful to people (such as women) who are smaller than their opponent, unless you become a black belt and learn hapkido movements, which deal with joint locks to redirect your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a yellow belt in taekwondo at a tournament last spring semester, and there were no other 18-years-or-older females in my belt range. I looked around me, in the corral where the tournament volunteers herded us into lines based on belt rank and gender to determine who sparred who.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had beat the same four guys in my line in the “forms” event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miami’s martial arts club teaches a traditional taekwondo style, meaning we focus less on sparring and more on forms and other aspects of taekwondo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an objectively bad sparrer, so I am used to getting my ass kicked by males, females and nonbinary people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was expecting to lose this tournament and I hoped to learn from fighting a martial artist who I wouldn’t get to fight otherwise. But I didn’t expect what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A volunteer counted us, up then pointed her pen at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you sure you wanna spar boys?” she asked. “Because I don’t want you or your coach to come crying to me afterward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“… Yes,” I said. “Who else am I going to spar?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shook her head and scribbled on her clipboard. The volunteer led us to where we would compete, and handed us to a referee, an older man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t notice me at first. I blended in with the three guys, strapped into the same protective gear that makes everyone look like red and blue turtles rather than people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he read my name on the clipboard and asked me again if I wanted to go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” I said, nearly spitting at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The referee shook his head and questioned the volunteer about why she let me compete. He asked for our ages: My opponent was 36 years old. I am 19 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No headshots. I will end the fight if she needs to stop,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am decent at headshots, so limiting our fight actually disadvantaged me. The fight started, and my opponent pummelled me. He was shorter, so he could easily get under my arms, blocking my chest and stomach to hit me and score points. I was in pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the fight, I nailed a spinning-wheel kick to his chest. My opponent had to stop, his hands on his knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The referee stopped the fight. “Are you hurt? What happened?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He just needed to catch his breath after my kick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fight continued and he won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sobs started, and I couldn’t figure out why I couldn’t stop. I couldn’t stop thinking about the volunteer’s words, and the referee’s. It got to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched for my teammates, but I couldn’t find them through my squinting. I returned to our pile of bags to tear off my protective gear and slumped against the wall, head in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the intercom, I heard: “If anyone would like to spar an adult female black belt, come to registration.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched the recording of my fight over and over. I was convinced that he had slowed down to let me hit him. Eventually I realized that, yes, I did make the shot. But I shouldn’t have to question myself or have others constantly question me because of my gender. And that female black belt who didn’t have anyone to spar with shouldn’t be alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More women need to be in male-dominated spaces. Women need to be sparring in taekwondo, running business meetings and leading in STEM fields. No woman can single-handedly subvert stereotypes – unless you’re Simone Biles. However, the more women there are in a field, the more likely it is there will be qualified women who can succeed and become leaders in that field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could challenge the status quo more. A small part of me wished I could have proved the volunteer and referee wrong by winning the fight. At the same time, I’m happy my opponent didn’t go easy on me, because otherwise my hard work – despite my loss – is a moot point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I can do is work harder, speak up when I can and exist in other places where I can break the stereotype of what a woman is expected to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 20:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/06/ask-me-are-you-sure-again-i-dare-you/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/11/06/ask-me-are-you-sure-again-i-dare-you/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>People are finally talking about the Elephants in the Room</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—Within a week of popping the question, “Hey, wanna start a band?” a group of people who knew each other from church and mutual friends were honing a sound – one that meshes jazz, soul and pop. They call themselves Elephants in the Room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two founding members are Daniel Thompson, who graduated from Miami in 2017, and Sharee Nurse, a current graduate student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating from Taylor University with a degree in music marketing, Nurse told herself she would turn away from making music. Now, she’s the lead singer, songwriter and acoustic guitarist of the band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their debut performance was on Aug. 25 at the Ernst Music Festival in Kumler Chapel. At one point, the audience had filled between 75 to 100 seats to hear the band sing jazzy renditions of songs like Ben E. King’s “Stand By Me” and Taylor Swift’s “Shake It Off.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In three months, Nurse wrote 10 songs that will become the band’s first album. The plan is to finish up lyrics, finalize instrumentation within the next few weeks, start doing regular local shows and record the album within the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the group is missing is a bass guitarist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s the thing you don’t know is missing until you hear it,” Nurse said. “It’s like the bass in a car – that low, vibrating part. When you take it out, it sounds weird.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the missing bass, a few songs have been successfully crowd-tested. Nurse and Thompson played an acoustic version of two original songs, “Brown Skin Baby” and “I Think This is Love,” at Art After Dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t as packed as the Ernst Music Festival, but the applause of the people filling the few rows of chairs in front of the stage set off a shrill feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You guys are too excited! The sound system can’t handle it,” Thompson said during the performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the final touches are being made on the album, the band is putting its own spin on mainstream songs. The band never ends a song cover the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When covering a song, the band first tunes it to their own soul-and-jazz pop frequency. They slow down fast songs, and bolster slow songs with the trumpet or trombone. They practice until they trust each other to make their own individual riffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy what you’re reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signup for our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email Address&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anything we can do that makes people go, ‘ooh!’– we do that,” Nurse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the “ooh!” is carried by the lilt in Nurse’s voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It gives me chills every time I hear her sing,” Amanda Gonzalez, a fan and a friend of Nurse, said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the “ooh” is prompted by an impromptu set of notes on the keyboard, the trombone, the trumpet or from the mouth of Thompson, who is the band’s resident brass and keyboard player as well as background singer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thompson, now a mechanical engineer in Cincinnati, spends his free time as part of Elephants in the Room, or as the lead for another local band called Just Dandy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the “ooh” comes out when Callie Miller’s fingers get a fresh grip on her jazz guitar. Miller is the youngest of the group, a junior at Miami, although the group often forgets her age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Add all of our ages together and Callie is more mature than all of us combined,” Thompson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always constant is Juiquetta Harmon riffing behind the drums. She’s also a highly-rated barber at the Rose Room Salon who has cut the hair of almost everyone in the band. Harmon doesn’t sing, but her facial expressions say a lot from the back of the stage, exuding joy or surprise with one tilt of her smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the last piece of the band, the bass guitarist, has yet to fall into place, Elephants in the Room is still performing at school functions and house shows. You can book them for an event on their Facebook page by searching the group’s nickname for their fans, “Little Trunkies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/09/people-are-finally-talking-about-the-elephants-in-the-room?ct=content_open&amp;amp;cv=cbox_latest&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Sebastian Neufuss&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 20:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/18/people-are-finally-talking-about-the-elephants-in-the-room/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/09/18/people-are-finally-talking-about-the-elephants-in-the-room/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABB press release: Polish energy company’s eight-year contract renewal supports seven sites</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://new.abb.com/news/detail/5887/pge-capital-group-renews-abb-care-adds-control-systems-services&quot;&gt;abb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PGE Energia Ciepła, part of PGE Capital Group, renewed an ABB Power Generation Care Agreement. The eight-year contract covers the following Polish facilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PGE Energia Ciepła S.A. Branch Wybrzeże (CHP Gdańsk and CHP Gdynia)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PGE Energia Ciepła S.A. Branch nr 1 in Kraków (CHP Kraków)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PGE Toruń S.A. (CHP Toruń)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kogeneracja S.A. (CHP in Wrocław and CHP in Siechnice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the agreement, ABB conducts annual service inspections, remote diagnostics and repairs of the control systems at these sites. ABB technicians and the spare parts warehouse are available for emergency situations that may impact production capacity, as well as for other service needs where local intervention is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time in the service agreement, PGE Energia Ciepła included both ABB and third-party control systems,  including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ABB Symphony Plus Melody&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ABB Symphony Plus Procontrol P14&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ABB Symphony Plus Safety, based on AC800M high integrity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ABB Central PGIM, archiving and reporting system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third-party Siemens safety system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ET200 I/Os integrated within Symphony Plus via Profibus DPV2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ABB AC500 controllers for telemetry and water pumping station in the heat distribution network in the PGE Toruń&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ABB Freelance control systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Siemens safety system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB Power Generation Care is a modular service agreement framework designed to cut complexity, control cost, and maximize capital for ABB customers. ABB Power Generation Care offers three Care Packages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rapid Response, which guarantees fast and flexible service response to maximize equipment availability;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lifecycle Management, which provides powerful tools and our knowledge base to optimize and extend equipment life;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performance Improvement, which increases productivity through usability and efficiency optimization of equipment and processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PGE Energia Ciepła produces and supplies heat in the largest Polish cities - Kraków, Gdańsk, Gdynia and Wrocław, as well as in Toruń, Zielona Góra and Siechnice - in which it also has heating networks. The company is also the owner of the system power plant in Rybnik. PGE Energia Ciepła, a part of PGE Group, is responsible for the implementation of the PGE Group’s Heating Strategy for 2018 – 2023 with perspective for 2030, announced on December 14, 2017. In accordance with the adopted Strategy, PGE’s intention is to be the leader of environmental changes in the sector by carrying out activities supporting the battle for clean air in Polish cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PGE Capital Group is Poland’s largest energy sector company with respect to sales revenues and net profit. Thanks to the combination of its own fuel resources, power generation and distribution networks, PGE guarantees a safe and reliable power supply to over 5 million households, businesses and institutions. PGE’s mission is to ensure security and growth based on reliability of supply, technical excellence, modern services and partnership relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB (ABBN: SIX Swiss Ex) is a pioneering technology leader in electrification products, robotics and motion, industrial automation and power grids, serving customers in utilities, industry and transport &amp;amp; infrastructure globally. Continuing a history of innovation spanning more than 130 years, ABB today is writing the future of industrial digitalization with two clear value propositions: bringing electricity from any power plant to any plug and automating industries from natural resources to finished products. As title partner of Formula E, the fully electric international FIA motorsport class, ABB is pushing the boundaries of e-mobility to contribute to a sustainable future. ABB operates in more than 100 countries with about 135,000 employees. www.abb.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 13:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/06/abb-press-release-polish-energy-company-s-eight-year-contract-renewal-supports-seven-sites/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/08/06/abb-press-release-polish-energy-company-s-eight-year-contract-renewal-supports-seven-sites/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABB press release: Self-maintaining plant opens up for ABB services</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;us-cement-plant-replaces-10-gas-analyzers-for-107447&quot;&gt;U.S. cement plant replaces 10 gas analyzers for $107,447&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abb.com/cawp/seitp202/fc80eb99040d282bc12582ab0063d059.aspx&quot;&gt;abb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westerville, OHIO, USA—A leading U.S. cement company’s immediate response to general maintenance is to perform it in-house rather than turn to a service provider. However, the North American supplier of aggregates and building materials did not yet know the analyzers in its Texas, USA plant were becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site would not easily go to an outside source for help, but the cement plant picked up the phone when Jack Swartz, ABB Test and Customer Care Service Manager, called about its obsolete equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swartz, who has worked with the plant for 15 years, already knew the company had a problem he could stop before it started. Despite the site’s do-it-yourself mindset on maintenance, he visits the plant at least once a year to ask about the state of their facility equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘‘I proactively approached the customer,” Swartz said. ‘‘So the customer came through.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A discussion about spare parts during his last annual visit gave Swartz a chance to provide the company with a recommended spare parts list, just in case the plant ever needed outside assistance. He also took note of the plant’s aging analytical equipment. He recommended for the customer to consider upgrading the older analyzer modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2016, Swartz contacted the company again to suggest upgrading the older analyzer modules including their Magnos 17 and Uras 14s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2017, a $107,447 purchase order was received for four Magnus 27 analyzer modules and six URAS 26 analyzer modules. The 24-hour installation took place last October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swartz’ perseverance with a self-maintainer like this cement company serves as a reminder of ABB’s ability to support customers’ needs face-to-face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In a way we have always pushed these values,” Swartz said. “Some people don’t like getting in front of the customer, but I have always seen it as part of the job.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 13:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/abb-press-release-self-maintaining-plant-opens-up-for-abb-services/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/abb-press-release-self-maintaining-plant-opens-up-for-abb-services/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nowhere to turn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally published in The Miami Student Magazine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—Ying tells stories in a thin, nonchalant voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like when she mentions that on a near-constant basis, professors and international students alike approach her with a flourish of welcoming Mandarin, before they find out that Ying can only respond in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or when she recalls the various moments throughout her life when someone thought it was OK to ask her if she fit Asian porn stereotypes, some of which she wasn’t even aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bukakke? A sideways vagina? She had to Google them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot has happened to Ying on this campus, but it is simply following a pattern she picked up in her hometown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She grew up in Dayton, Ohio, with first-generation immigrant parents who fled violence in Taiwan, and a grandma who told the Buddhist monks at their local temple to pick on her for being an ungrateful American child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe you’re just a magnet with a big, white, racist ghost following you,” Marisa, Ying’s close friend, joked with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghosts, both white and Asian, seem to haunt Ying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classrooms that dismissed her&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying didn’t speak English for her first two years in school. Her teachers and peers thought she was dumb, but she just refused to speak out of spite. Ying understood them, but she simply didn’t want to talk to people who pulled their eyelids back and greeted her with “Ching chong ching chong!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her teachers put her in the mental retardation class a year before the school rebranded it as special education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Ying spoke English. Her teachers put her in regular classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying grew up, but perhaps her peers did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once, she was giving a tour to a new freshman student at her high school. They finished the tour, and she dropped him off at his next class. She left the classroom thinking she was alone, but the student ran out of the class to catch up with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, come back here! You dumb chink Asian slut!” the student, whom she had never met, said before he ran back into the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying rushed in after him. “Get the fuck out of here! You need to leave!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She cussed him out. In front of the whole class, the new student, the teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying got in trouble. Not him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it Miami?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying is unusually kind. She will help someone she just met to carry a heavy load. She will walk a new friend home. She will offer to connect someone she barely knows with another friend who can give free stick-and-poke tattoos and piercings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Ying has a lot of anger. Lately, it has been bubbling up more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying saw the warning signs in the months leading up to the fall semester of her first year at Miami. Students protesting the campus’ handling of the Thomas Wright n-word scandal last year had taped up posters in Armstrong Student Center to warn prospective minority students and to make the university worry about how it could affect admissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While touring the campus after being accepted, Ying snapped pictures of these ominous posters and sent them to her friends, adding, “This is the fucking school I’m going to.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they saw the posters, they told her to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying didn’t choose Miami. Her parents did, for the sheer amount of scholarship money she received here in comparison to Ying’s first choices, the Ohio State University and Yale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying attended the Bridges Summer Scholars program, which offers scholarships between $2,500 and $5,000 and emphasizes diversity, but couldn’t bond with people of color in the program. They were snobby, standoffish. A sophomore helping to lead the program bragged that she could get into all the best parties because of her race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time Ying returned to campus, it was to start her four years of college — “the best four years of your life,” some people call it. Within a week, she considered transferring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just hours after moving into her residence hall, her roommate mentioned showing a picture of Ying to her grandma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, she’s oriental!” the grandma had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old slur didn’t alarm the roommate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yep, she’s smart, too,” the roommate added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After her first time going Uptown, Ying walked along frat row to return to her residence hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drunk bands of brothers splayed themselves on their respective porches. She made eye contact with them. It seemed like they assumed she was an international student, because they talked as if she couldn’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why are there so many people of color on this campus now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We shouldn’t have let them in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying is Taiwanese, and so is her name. She doesn’t bother sharing it at Miami, though, no matter how easy it is to pronounce. So she goes by a generic English name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the one similarity between her and international students on campus, other than not being white. But for Ying, not being white nor Asian enough has put a target on her back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s having a hard time finding her place at Miami because of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, people drop the casual “yo, chink,” “yellow” or “oriental” on Ying from the opposite side of the sidewalk, as if in greeting. Frat boys have catcalled her, targeting her Asian appearance with these same words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes. Her skin. Her hair. Her eyelids. Ying’s appearance makes her the target of people who don’t look like her, but international students see a friend in the same features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, until she opens her mouth. They become disappointed once they find out Ying is too embarrassed to respond to them in her broken Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the locked door of Clawson Recreation Center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying and a friend waited for the gym to open, leaning on the stair railing that leads up to the door. They went to the gym together every Saturday afternoon during fall semester, so they didn’t have to look at the gym’s hours of operation, on a sign beside the door, to know the facility would open in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of students sauntered up, muttering to each other in Chinese. One pulled on the door handle. They inspected the sign, not seeming to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One turned to look at Ying: at her skin, her black hair, her familiar eyes and eyelids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asked his question in Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this door locked? Is the gym open today? His questions were expectant, hopeful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stood up straighter, off the railing now. She understood, but she responded in English. They didn’t understand, so Ying tried again in her rusty Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group only grew more confused and walked away. Ying returned to the railing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 2 p.m., the door lock clicked open automatically. Ying and her friend walked into the gym alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closed exit doors of a packed bus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“HEY! What do you think you’re doing?!” the bus driver screeched, glaring at the mirror above her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Butler County Regional Transit Authority bus hadn’t fully stopped. The doors weren’t open. Yet a group of students were out of their seats, crowding the exit doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driver kept yelling while Ying watched and listened from her seat, jaw clenched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They all looked the same to the driver: another bubble of international students who could only understand each other. She opened the doors and turned to continue her tirade while the students escaped the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“WHY can’t you all just —”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying snapped. Her voice became shrill. “They can’t understand you! Yelling is not going to help them know what you’re saying. Why can’t you understand that?!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying left no room in the air for the driver to keep yelling after the students, who had already left the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying watched the driver’s face morph as she registered Ying’s words, clearly stunned. As if she was on autopilot, the driver turned back in her chair, turned the handle to close the doors and kept driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Ying seethed. She couldn’t help but say something in a situation like this, even if the same international students may not have treated her with the same respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eyes, the skin and the hair do not always equate to mutual respect when centuries-old politics are involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The island of Taiwan became a Chinese colony for Han Chinese immigrants during the 17th century. Taiwan and its people — Ying’s people — were given to Japan as war spoils in 1895, and the neighboring island governed Taiwan for 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Taiwan’s lingering genealogical connection to China, both Taiwan and China would transform during their time apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan had used classic censorship and propaganda from afar in an attempt to assimilate the people of Taiwan into Japanese culture, while China’s communist state emerged. Then, amidst a civil war, Chinese nationalists loyal to the old government — or, as the Chinese would call them, traitors — had fled to Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan eventually gave Taiwan back to the Republic of China as its penance for being on the wrong side of World War II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the new China, Taiwan was under harsh martial law. In the 1980s, when Ying’s own parents grew up in Taiwan, China’s iron grip weakened and finally left room for Taiwan’s independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;War spoils. Assimilation. Fifty years of separation, bookended by propaganda. Traitors. Over 100 years of political conflict are dumped unceremoniously on Ying when a Chinese international student lets her know she doesn’t belong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Ying looks familiar to international students. But in the case of Chinese international students, this interaction gets more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Ying doesn’t talk about her country, they don’t have a problem with her — but of course, the first thing they ask Ying is her nationality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they discover she’s Taiwanese, they assume she’s not wealthy. When they know she was born in the United States, they assume her parents must be traitors for leaving China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, they release a verbal wrath that carries a ghost of what history unleashed onto Taiwan — a ghost older than the original racist white ghost that Marisa had joked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should have been an uneventful line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying waited patiently in line to get a stamp from a table at Chuseok, a Korean Thanksgiving festival organized by the Korean American Student Association. Once she and her friend collected enough stamps on their “passport,” they could get in line for traditional Korean food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An international student with an entourage of two girls started speaking Mandarin to Ying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry, I don’t speak Mandarin,” Ying said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, so where are you from, then?” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m Taiwanese.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh. But you don’t speak Mandarin,” he said, not believing her. He continued to speak Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look, I can understand, but I can’t speak back to you. I don’t know how.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, so you’re not actually Taiwanese. You’re just American-born, you’re not actually from Taiwan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I’m not. But I do speak Taiwanese,” Ying said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taiwanese Hokkien is a dialect of Chinese Mandarin. The differences can be compared to how British English and American English use different words for the same object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s the same language,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, it’s not,” Ying corrected him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So why don’t you speak Mandarin?” he pushed again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I speak it at home with my parents. But I don’t usually speak it while out in public, because it’s not good enough,” Ying said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He began a tirade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your country’s not real. It’s not a real place. Taiwanese people are all shit, and you don’t speak another language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two girls backed him up: Why don’t you just speak Mandarin with him? You’re literally being so rude right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shut down. The food hadn’t even arrived, but the ghosts were here. So Ying left without a word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel like you can’t be a minority and be here, and not notice it all the time,” Ying said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying can have a visceral reaction to both casual and targeted racism, but at the same time, she usually tries to be gentle with the same people who say these things to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When these things happen, they’re not intentional. They don’t grow up around people who aren’t like them, so they don’t know how to talk or act,” Ying said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Ying reached out to other minority students on campus, they told her the racism at Miami was about the same as it was in their own hometowns. But Ying seems to experience more than the normal student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying told her RA everything that had happened after a month into fall semester. The RA gave the standard response: report them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing’s gonna happen,” Ying said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RA said it was all she could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying filed the reports. Nothing happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s at least easier than it was in high school for Ying to never see these people again, but it’s not unavoidable, and it adds up. Ying still passes by the same people who mocked her, on campus sidewalks, in class and on dating apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She doesn’t feel at home with her roommate. As a Taiwanese person, she doesn’t feel welcome in the Asian American Association (AAA), a Miami organization for students from all backgrounds to celebrate Asian and Asian-American cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ying doesn’t want to steel herself against another person who doesn’t understand her culture and demands for her to explain herself, so she refuses to go to AAA meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last semester, she wanted to transfer. But she had to do her best to make Miami feel like home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She interviewed for the RA position and made it, so her room and board will be paid off next year. She hopes to support other students with similar struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I want to help other kids like me,” Ying said. “It’s suffocating here, and it’s worse when you feel alone.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial security softens the blow of everything else. Ying’s roommate is hardly ever in the room anyway, and Ying simply chooses to avoid going to Asian American events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ghosts are still here. But so is Ying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 19:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/01/nowhere-to-turn-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/05/01/nowhere-to-turn-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Central Park Five member speaks on institutionalized racism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—Yusef Salaam came to speak about his experiences in the criminal justice system in Armstrong Student Center last night, following the presentation of Ken Burns documentary, “The Central Park Five”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salaam is one-fifth of the Central Park Five, a group of black and Latino teenagers wrongfully convicted of raping a white female jogger in Central Park in the early morning of April 19, 1989. He came to campus as part of a spring tour for the Ohio Innocence Project-undergraduate (OIP-u), which comprised most of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The student law organization, led by president and senior Ariel Shuster, raises awareness of the frequency of wrongful imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is not just the story of one person,” Salaam said. “This is the story of a lot of people’s lives.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salaam was the only one out of the five who did not make a false confession, which prosecutors used to send the teenagers to prison as adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The only crime I committed that night was [that] I hopped the turnstile,” Salaam said in the documentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After over 24 hours of interrogation, the police had coerced the five, who had been in Central Park that night, to falsely confess. Years later, the Central Park Five – Salaam, Korey Wise, Kevin Richardson, Raymond Santana and Antron McCray – do not hold animosity toward one another, and even wrote to one another while in prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real rapist, Matias Reyes, came forward 13 years later after meeting one of the Five, Korey Wise. Reyes was a serial rapist, who continued to rape while the case against the Central Park Five persisted despite a lack of physical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day after the five teenagers were brought in, Donald Trump took out full-page advertisements in The New York Times demanding they receive the death penalty. Salaam compared Trump’s reaction to the Central Park Five case to Trump’s reaction when his cabinet member was accused of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He said, ‘hey, let’s not rush to judge. People’s lives are being destroyed from a mere accusation,’” Salaam said. “Where was that talk back in 1989 when he pulled out the ads calling for the death penalty, for a mere accusation?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also read aloud hate mail his mother received while he was in prison and commented on the media’s treatment of the case. Over 400 articles covered the case at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People turn cameras on the reaction, rather than what causes the reaction,” Salaam said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salaam highlighted corruption in the criminal justice system and pointed to criminal law loopholes in his speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Laws made because of the Central Park Five case are still around, even after the case was overturned,” Salaam said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salaam also responded to the controversy at Miami over the recent use of racial slurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is definitely not enough to not make a statement, because other schools and other institutions have suspended students like that,” Salaam said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also quoted the African saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The child that is rejected by the village will burn down the village just to feel the warmth,” Salaam said. “That is a scary thought.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event at Miami was Salaam’s second tour stop. He is scheduled to speak at five other Ohio college campuses with an OIP-u presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ava DuVernay, a high-profile filmmaker, is also releasing a five-part docuseries about the Central Park Five on Netflix next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/04/central-park-five-member-speaks-on-institutionalized-racism&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 20:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/10/central-park-five-member-speaks-on-institutionalized-racism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/04/10/central-park-five-member-speaks-on-institutionalized-racism/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>April poetry contest buds into spring</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—Learning is the continual/Change in which one/becomes an alloy/of the Entirety of the world/Beautiful university, where?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This poem by sophomore Viengsamai Fetters became one of three grand-prize winners in last year’s social media poetry contest. Fetters, a literature major, wrote her poem in the Notes app on her phone the night before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme last year, determined by President Gregory Crawford and Director of Creative Writing Cathy Wagner, was Diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They were saying, ‘Hey, we’ve got things to work on, but we can do that together,’” Wagner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fetters and other participants posted their poems on Twitter and Instagram under the #LoveHonorPoem hashtag, to compete for the chance to win prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, senior JuJuan Johnson and graduate student Shamika Karikari were the other two grand-prize winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three winners each received a Love &amp;amp; Honor medal, a handwritten note from President Crawford and a $40 gift certificate to the Miami University Bookstore. Honorable mentions received $18.09 in Miami University Bookstore credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fetters spent the Miami University Bookstore certificate she won on a textbook she rented for her linguistics anthropology class, which she found serendipitous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Linguistics anthropology is about how language and culture interact with each other, which I think is very poetic,” Fetters said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last line of Fetters’ poem, “Beautiful university, where?” is in Arabic. While this was left out in the original announcement of the poetry winners, Wagner is working Fetters’ last line back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some poets were seasoned veterans, while others – like mechanical engineering major Julie Matz – entered a poem for class credit. Matz is a junior in the Lockheed Martin Leadership Institute, which President Crawford had invited to participate in the poetry contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My poem was a terrible play on math,” Matz said. “All of my writing is very distinct and straightforward because what I know is calculus.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matz won an honorable mention for her poem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the prizes and the number of winners will stay the same, but participants will instead write their poems based on the theme of Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all about opening the senses,” Wagner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wagner and the Miami University Creative Writing Cohort hope to see, feel and hear spring while reading poems under the #Miamioh_poem hashtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest deadline is April 20, and Wagner hopes writing poems related to spring will be a destressor in the midst of projects and exams. Wagner also wants this contest to inspire honest writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think that people should necessarily write pretty, happy poems,” said Wagner. “I think it’s important to write about whatever is going on in Miami in the spring. Writers can take it wherever they want.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Diversity theme followed the same strain of honest writing. This is best exemplified in a line from Johnson’s poem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard there’s more power in unity than division/So either y’all just don’t see the vision/If we combine can you imagine the impact of that collision!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/04/april-poetry-contest-buds-into-spring?ct=content_open&amp;amp;cv=cbox_latest&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 19:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/03/april-poetry-contest-buds-into-spring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/04/03/april-poetry-contest-buds-into-spring/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TORTILLAS AND MOTORCYCLES</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-family-its-memories-and-the-opinions-in-between&quot;&gt;MY FAMILY, ITS MEMORIES AND THE OPINIONS IN BETWEEN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in The Miami Student magazine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students packed the auditorium for a diversity panel at the Ohio University High School Journalism Workshop. It wasn’t crowded just because the panel was mandatory, but because diversity was a controversial topic even in a world where Donald Trump wasn’t yet president. It was 2016, the summer before my senior year of high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation quickly became heated, and the adults lost control of it. Everyone was angry and divisive, especially while talking about Trump. Most people seemed to be anti-Trump, except for one kid in the front who stuck out like a red “Make America Great Again” thumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A student in the middle of the stadium-like seating raised her hand and said she didn’t understand how this kid in her school, who was half Mexican, could support Trump. She absolutely could not wrap her mind around it. How could he turn on his own people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I raised my hand, though my public speaking skills were not exactly reliable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, it’s really hard to explain my family in two seconds unless I want to sound like an idiot. That’s exactly what I sounded like when I said, “I’m a fourth-generation Mexican,” into the microphone and immediately wanted to sew my mouth shut and never speak again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crowd roared with laughter at me, a white girl who couldn’t explain herself, and I immediately tried to course-correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry, I’m sorry. That was really insanely dumb of me to say. I was just trying to explain my family really quickly, and it came out wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started over. I explained that my family is very proud of their legal status in the United States, their conservative beliefs and their support for Donald Trump. I also made sure to make it clear that I didn’t share those beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What I am trying to say is that you can’t always put people in a box because of their demographic,” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loud murmurs. The rest of the auditorium did not agree. I sank into my chair, wishing I could become two-dimensional and slide to the floor. I remember ringing in my ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation escalated from there. The adults failed to calm us down until a Latina counselor at the top of the auditorium, who described herself as “a Venezuelan queen overlooking you all,” took the microphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who is very clearly white and has not undergone the discrimination that non-white people experience, I realized that during a diversity panel, I really should just shut up and listen. But at the same time, other than my really bad intro, what I said was relevant to the point of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only I hadn’t been such a devil’s advocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only I could have articulated it better. It could have been constructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panel ended eventually, and we all filed out of the auditorium. I was outside the doors waiting for my friend to catch up, contemplating where I could buy a needle and thread to sew my mouth shut forever, when two Latina students came outside and glared at me as they passed. And probably rightly so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“‘A fourth-generation Mexican,’” one of them said. “This gringa.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a lot of time — and a lot of mistakes — before I figured out where I fit in my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was little, I looked like a German Dora. My mom gave me Dora’s bowlish bang cut, but with thin blonde hair. My hair has since darkened to brown, but it has always been clear that I am a white person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English is my first and only fluent language. My family pressured me to take Spanish in high school, but I only took three years of it so I could make room for journalism classes. When I turned 15, my birthday passed without a quinceañera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my entire childhood had passed in San Antonio, I would still look the same. But I would be fluent in Spanish and would have worn a big, poofy dress on my fifteenth birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was born in Ohio, and I grew up in Ohio. I almost always lost in games of cornhole and wished I lived somewhere more interesting. I scuffed my knees while riding my bike, I stayed up late to wait for imaginary fairies to pop out from behind tree leaves, I fought to be the boss of my little brother and I reached my tongue out to catch thick snowflakes from a packed winter sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the religious differences among my relatives, they are mostly united on the front of immigration — and their thoughts don’t fit into the tidy statistics on Latinx public opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I delve into this, I should make it clear that I do not oppose or accept these beliefs. I simply respect them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is just about my family, and with my family comes strong opinions, which are sometimes very unpopular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I can remember visiting my relatives in San Antonio, Texas, I was a little towhead Ohioan who liked to listen to my relatives talk. And gossip. And chastise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soaked it all in: The age-old sibling rivalry between my great-grandma Hilda and my great-grand aunt Olga. The switches from Spanish to English to a harsher, rapid-fire Spanish when conversation turned to Stephen Colbert or the President or how a family drama went down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember thinking of the house as “the place where too many people lived.” At the time, the little house hosted Walter “Bud” Hersey; the ex-wife Bud remarried in the 1990s, Hilda Hersey; their daughter, Lynda Hersey, a teacher; and their son, Eddie Hersey, a kind man who is good with kids but is currently serving time in prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent most of our San Antonio trips visiting this little house. I loved my family and its bustle, but I grew tired of the Febreze-soaked furniture, the three dogs that could smell fear and the constant yelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a high school physics unit on sound, I found out my hearing level is 100 decibels lower than average. I attribute this slight hearing loss to occasionally blaring my earphones and attending concerts, but especially to my time in this little house, where Fox News blared in two separate rooms and my relatives yakked in Spanish or English — but never Spanglish — in the cramped kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then, my great-grandparents’ hearing was really bad, and it’s even worse now. Yelling to one another was how all conversations were conducted; when people in the house yelled at each other, somehow it became even louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, my great-grandma Hilda is 86, and my great-grandpa, Walter “Bud” Hersey, turns 88 in May. While they do not live in this house anymore, yelling is still the acceptable volume for conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My great-grand-uncle George’s house was a quiet break from this funny little house with too many big personalities. When I was older and my family visited his home on our trips to Texas, George pulled framed pictures from the walls to show us the faces of long-gone relatives and younger, goofier versions of the living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one face I can clearly remember from those sepia-toned pictures is that of my great-great grandma Armandina, a motorcycle-riding flapper. Armandina’s face and her badassery cut through all the noise of the trips to San Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years later, I asked Great-Grand-Uncle George about her. I found out Armandina Flores-Peña stole moments on her friend’s motorcycle until she was 61. But she didn’t ride motorcycles as much after she got married and traded in her last name for “Rodríguez.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Armandina had kids and grandkids, her role became “Mamá.” This is what her daughter, my great-grandma Hilda, called her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the cracks in her dementia, Hilda can almost always recall the teachers who scorned her for her Mexican-ness: her accent, her skin and her hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These memories can wring out bitter laughter, but more often they bring tears to her eyes. Every time I visit her, she tells anyone who will listen about those devil teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They told me I would drop out of school to marry a Mexican bum,” Great-Grandma will say, then point to my white great-grandpa. “I tell my kids they only got it half right. I married their father.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My great-grandparents both have dementia, but Hilda is typically a bit more aware than Bud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say hello or goodbye to him with a hug and a kiss on the cheek, most of the time a tear leaks out of one eye. Maybe it’s because he understands I love him, but doesn’t always remember who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bud was born and raised in Maine. He grew up poor. Once he told me a story about how going to a movie cost 10 cents when he grew up, but his family couldn’t afford even that. Then he laughed his loud, gasping laugh that’s strangely infectious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever Bud speaks Spanish, it’s meant to be ironic. He’ll sip his coffee, say “muy bueno,” then crack up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, this comes after Hilda does something like toasting to “Salud, dinero y amor!” — health, money and love — at a restaurant, and everyone clinks glasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bud used to be fluent in Spanish, but he didn’t learn from his wife or her family. He learned Spanish from a guy in a bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He wanted to learn English, and I wanted to learn Spanish,” Bud said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So they met at the bar every day for an hour, trading languages and downing drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armandina had spoiled her kids, refusing to let Hilda and her four siblings cook. So when Hilda married Bud — who served as a Morse code operator in the Korean War — and had the baby who would become my grandma, Hilda could cook only with a pressure cooker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Armandina, or Mamá, taught her granddaughter — my grandmother — how to cook classic Mexican dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandma, Barbara, was 11 years old when she cooked flour tortillas for the first time. By the time she turned 16, she was cooking almost every single meal for her five siblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandma’s recipes are never the same, because my grandma doesn’t measure out her ingredients. Neither did her grandmother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own grandma’s cooking is amazing, but her resume is all over the place in the best way: She started her own Mexican restaurant, got a degree in religion and now works in computer security. She was also the officiant at my parents’ wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t forget the cobalt blue Harley-Davidson motorcycle she used to ride with my papaw. On that Harley, they visited Frank Lloyd Wright mansions and Myrtle Beach and one really dangerous road down south with their motorcycling friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandma clearly inherited Armandina’s badassery, but the rest of the family history was news to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George has traced Armandina’s side of the family as far back as 1691, which is when our ancestor Nicolas Saenz was born in Monterrey, Mexico. Armandina’s parents, Abran Flores-Peña and Antonia (with the maiden name de los Santos), entered the United States legally in 1900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By custom, the Spanish put the husband’s last name in front of the wife’s maiden name. Abran and Antonia’s official U.S. documents dropped the “Peña,” and they became the Flores family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can trace the line of Armandina’s husband, Eduardo Rodríguez, back to 1856, when my great-great-great-great grandfather, Jesus Rodríguez, was born. George hasn’t been able to find much before that, since many family records were burned during the 1910 Mexican Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My great-great-great grandfather on Eduardo’s side, Rodríguez de Carvajal, was a servant to Marques de Aguayo, a Spanish military leader who oversaw the Spanish mission that is now San Antonio. At the age of nine, Rodríguez helped build this settlement, the Alamo and four other missions later in his life before settling in Monterrey, Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 11, my great-great-grandfather Eduardo Rodríguez, along with two skinny 12-year-olds, reinstalled historic church bells in the San Augustine Catholic church in Laredo, Texas, in 1912. At the time, the church bells were 127 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catholicism ran deep in the family, including the Peña family on Armandina’s side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They had their own private pew at Catholic church, and they had a special room in their home for Wednesday church worship,” George said. “Being wealthy and being Catholic went hand in hand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was when the Mexican Revolution forced a mass exodus of people from Mexico — including clergy of the Latter-Day Saints, known colloquially as “Mormons.” Some of these missionaries met Armandina’s mother, Antonia, in 1918, after they moved to Laredo, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meeting, and one later held at Antonia’s house that featured lemonade, set off one of the biggest family dramas I had never heard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The missionaries taught their beliefs to Antonia, who also went by Tonya, and her three oldest children, including Armandina. Scandal ensued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Catholic priests excommunicated them publicly, while Tonya cleaned out her private church room in her home,” George said. “The family never fully recovered socially, and it even affected them financially because many people stopped doing business with the family.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t stop Tonya, or her daughter Armandina. In 1940, Armandina’s daughter Hilda would be baptized as a Mormon in the Rio Grande.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George grew up as a Mormon and remains a Mormon, along with many of my other relatives in this part of the family. Mormons place a lot of emphasis on family genealogy, which is partly why George has gone to such great lengths to remember our family history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some relatives have since left the faith. My grandma Barbara was once a licensed teacher in the Unity Church, and I have at least one great-aunt who reverted to Catholicism. I am not Mormon, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My life was very normal, but in Spanish and English,” George said. “We spoke English at school and with friends, but always spoke in Spanish with my parents.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is Armandina’s youngest child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He fondly recalls his Mamá’s food, “and, of course, all the hugs and kisses because Latins are very expressive and touchy-feely.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a generalization, but it reminds me of how great-grandma Hilda always has a “Papasito!” and a kiss on the cheek whenever my uncle or brother enter the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, put simply: my relatives don’t support illegal immigrants in the United States, and they have a history of not doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Papá organized a printers’ union in Laredo in the 1940s because cheap Mexican labor competed with Mexican-American [laborers],” George said. “Mamá’s brothers helped establish the Border Patrol in Laredo because so many Mexican criminals caused problems in their community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George’s Papá, Eduardo, also helped organize the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), which at the time worked to integrate Mexican immigrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Their community leaders wanted to be seen as ‘American,’ not ‘Mexican,’” George said. “Bottom line was, be proud of your family roots in Mexico, but be American for your future and children. It’s typical of all immigrant groups who have come to the USA.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, LULAC supports open borders and blanket amnesty. George does not support LULAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know George as my great-grand-uncle. Google knows him as “El Conservador,” a conservative, Spanish-speaking blogger and radio host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before he became “El Conservador,” he worked for the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George was a member of the Reagan administration’s transition team, then worked his way up to preparing speeches and travel plans for the president. He later worked at the Justice Department on immigration issues and police-community relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During George W. Bush’s presidency, he worked in the U.S. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development. He was an office director in Houston, Texas, and later in West Virginia. After Hurricane Katrina, he worked for the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s recovery program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, he’s been interviewed on Univision, a local Texas NPR station and, most recently, “Fox &amp;amp; Friends.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George was the only Spanish speaker Univision could find to provide a conservative viewpoint on the border wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When George first began making media appearances, he grew frustrated with the mainstream media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George’s hesitancy comes from a series of bad interviews over the years. One reporter hooked him up to a mic, trained the camera on him and asked for his opinion on the border issue as a Mexican-American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George explained his father’s opposition to illegal Mexican workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reporter didn’t air George’s segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have learned to be very precise in my comments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandma taught me how to roll out tortillas using a rolling pin when I was little. Rolling out whole batches of tortillas was sometimes too much on my little arms, and I had to take breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No tortilla was a perfect circle. One would be smaller than the rest, another would have a chunk missing, and all were lopsided in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter the shape, everyone salivated at the smell of fresh tortillas and stood up for seconds a few minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the tortilla-making process is faster, shinier. We’ve gone through several modern tortilla presses, but my grandma still measures her ingredients by saying, “We added a bit too much of this, so we should add more flour,” or, “This looks about right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no need to take breaks, unless I’m stopping to eat an ugly tortilla that I pressed too hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tortilla press is not enough to do it all. First, Grandma kneads the ingredients, lets them rise, and flattens the dough into little spheres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I join in and take the little spheres one at a time. I take one, smash it in my hands and flatten it on the hot tortilla press. I drag the almost-tortilla off the press and put it onto the even hotter pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandma grabs the edge of the tortilla, sometimes with a spatula but more likely with her bare fingers, to uncover the golden brown patches on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always keep two tortillas on the pan longer than usual, just for my great-grandma Hilda. She likes hers a little burnt, with crispy charred marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process has changed a little, but the end result hasn’t. Anyone who strolls through the kitchen — my brother, my father, my mother, my papaw, my great-grandma, my great-aunt, my great-uncle, my cousin, an old family friend, a new family friend — always steals a fresh tortilla on their way out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why one batch is never enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 13:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/03/tortillas-and-motorcycles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/04/03/tortillas-and-motorcycles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>She's got options on Valentine's Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—Here is what you should know before you swipe right on Athena Scalzi: she’s a creative writing major, a Capricorn, left-handed, thicker “than a bowl of oatmeal” and a “bit of a nihilist,” according to her Tinder profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She might add you to her network if you’re cute and you’ve recently tested negative for STDs, but she’s busy this Thursday. Athena is a single sophomore, but she has three friends-with-benefits to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three “spicy boys” allegedly are out of her league.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m a four at most,” Athena said. “Or a 4.5. I’ll be nice to myself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One mile away is a first-year she won’t name. All she will admit and all we need to know is that he is tall, dark, handsome and private about his sex life, and Athena won’t abuse his trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few months of small talk, Athena was bored and sent him the classic Snapchat message, “hey, DTF?” and a mutual agreement was born. The only condition: no strings attached. They haven’t had sex in a while, but they still make small talk sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 58 miles away is Zach, a 33-year-old who flips houses in her hometown. In terms of sexual range, ability or whatever you want to call it, Zach is her favorite. He is the only person Athena has been with who has facial hair – dark, thick and clipped close to the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They matched on Tinder last Christmas, two days after their shared birthday on December 23, when Athena turned 20 and Zach turned 33. After two days of direct-messaging (Athena messaged first) and two extended phone conversations, they finally met in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After meeting face-to-face, Athena spent 3-4 nights per week at Zach’s during the month of January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the obvious, Athena and Zach also went sledding one time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s met his friends and he’s met hers. A few of her friends asked Zach if he was a junior or senior. Zach was pleased. Some of Athena’s friends were shocked, but if they had read a recent study that shows women peak, or get the most matches and messages, at 18-years-old while men peak at 50-years-old on dating apps, they might not have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, Athena and Zach aren’t dating. Athena is not interested in a serious relationship right now. But when she had dinner with his parents, Athena still wanted to impress them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy what you’re reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signup for our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email Address&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Athena’s third friend-with-benefits, Jack, is 255 miles away at Kent State University. They met while playing Dungeons and Dragons in high school and remained friends in college, though they only recently added the “with-benefits” over winter break. Out of the three, Jack knows her best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack was a swimmer in high school, which explains why Athena describes his body as “lithe,” “smooth” and “not a lot of hair” with “a twink look to him.” In his selfies, he mimics “the smolder,” a look made popular by the character Flynn Rider in Disney’s “Tangled.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s got options. Yet over a week before Valentine’s Day, she hadn’t made any plans. She just knew she didn’t want to be alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel like anyone who gets their heart broken and spends Valentine’s Day alone kind of resents happy couples,” Athena said. “Any time they see a happy couple on Valentine’s Day, they’re just like, ‘ugh, like, gross,’ and bitter and upset about it. That’s not who I want to be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Wednesday, Feb. 6, Athena made plans to drive to her hometown to spend the night with Zach this Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have no plans to go out that night and it’s not projected to snow Thursday, so we know they’re not sledding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2019/02/shes-got-options-on-valentines-day?ct=content_open&amp;amp;cv=cbox_latest&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 20:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/12/shes-got-options-on-valentines-day/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/02/12/shes-got-options-on-valentines-day/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ballroom dance club finds footing in new roles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oxford, OHIO, USA—Mambo. Cha cha. Quickstep. Foxtrot. All ballroom dances involve a “leader,” which is traditionally a man, who directs the “follower,” traditionally a woman. To help others learn to dance – regardless of gender identity – through the ballroom dance club, first-year Brynne Menkhaus and graduate student Josh Schussler are learning to be both leaders and followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It shouldn’t matter who follows or who leads, so we let people choose,” Josh said. “You become a much better dancer when you know how to do both.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh first switched roles while dancing at Rochester Institute of Technology, where he received his bachelor’s degree in physics and a few years of ballroom dance lessons. Brynne’s grandfather once won a dance contest in Jamaica by pairing American dances with reggae music, and years later he taught Brynne her first dance steps in middle school. She began learning to lead in ballroom dances last summer at A-Marika Dance Company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I went from the ‘advanced following’ class to the ‘beginner leading’ class,” Brynne said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brynne and Josh jumped through the necessary hoops to start the club last fall, but they are still working out some kinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This could easily be an ad for half-priced violins,” Brynne said about the club logo, which she thought still needed work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brynne and Josh tucked themselves into the corner of an Armstrong conference room, which was devoid of furniture, to discuss the logo and other plans while waiting for people to trickle into the meeting last Wednesday. One of those people was first-year Brooke Bennington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My mom gave me a list of clubs to join this semester, and this is one I actually chose to go to,” Brooke said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After learning the basic foxtrot steps, Brooke paired up with sophomore Marcus Meyer. They traveled around the room without music, stepping slow, slow, quick-quick in unison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power dynamic in a dance is hard to trace. Marcus, the leader, gave direction to Brooke, the follower, by putting slight pressure on any point where they touched. But the follower can also direct the leader without realizing it. This makes it hard to find out how dancing partners end up making a misstep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once, Brynne and Josh stopped Brooke and Marcus mid-quick to figure out how the two made a wrong turn. They could not figure out how it happened, until:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, I was leading you!” Brooke said through surprised laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy what you’re reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signup for our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email Address&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To newcomers, it can feel awkward to dance with a stranger. Dance partners hold hands, switch partners every few minutes and are close enough to smell the other person’s deodorant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over the course of the night, everyone loosened up. The group danced to unexpected foxtrot tunes that ranged from Michael Buble to Bruno Mars. Josh flashed funny faces at a partner in the middle of a move. Marcus surprised Brynne by twirling her in the middle of dancing the hustle. Brooke cracked jokes at everyone’s expense, including her own, and Brynne exclaimed in sheer glee while successfully leading her partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes! I’ve never been able to lead a quarter-turn before!” Brynne said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MU ballroom dance club meets from 7:30 p.m. to 9 p.m. on Mondays and Wednesdays in Armstrong 2084. Josh and Brynne will teach the waltz, hustle, cha cha, tango, merengue, salsa and other ballroom dances to anyone who comes during these times. Dues are $20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/02/ballroom-dance-club-finds-footing-in-new-roles?ct=content_open&amp;amp;cv=cbox_latest&quot;&gt;The Miami Student newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/ballroom-dance-club-finds-footing-in-new-roles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/ballroom-dance-club-finds-footing-in-new-roles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Women's self-defense class a rank above the rest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;104 items found for your search. If no results were found please broaden your search. « First ‹ Previous 1 2 3 4 5 6 Next › Last » Miami basketball player arrested (04/05/19 2:43pm) Three weeks ago, after pounding at the door of the mother of his child's apartment at 3:30 a.m., Miami University senior and RedHawks men's basketball guard Darrian Ringo allegedly shoved his child's mother to the ground and rushed to the bedroom to find him. The mother got up to stop Ringo, and he put his hands around her neck and pushed her on the bed. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2019/04/former-miami-basketball-player-arrested-for-domestic-violence-to-face-charges-next-week Audrey Davis, TMS managing editor, dies in home town (12/31/18 2:30am) Miami senior Audrey Marie Davis died suddenly on Wednesday, Dec. 26 in her home town of Hicksville, Ohio. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/12/audrey-davis-tms-managing-editor-dies-in-home-town Continuing the conversation (12/04/18 10:00am) Miami University sophomore Emily Pawlecki was walking to a date party while scrolling through her phone on a late Thursday night in early October. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/12/continuing-the-conversation Controversy over mace ban in residence halls (11/20/18 5:34pm) Correction on November 29: The Office of Residence Life does not prohibit mace and pepper spray in dorms. University departments gave The Student conflicting information about Miami policy on the matter. We should have taken greater care to ascertain the truth, and we apologize for the error. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/11/controversy-over-mace-ban-in-residence-halls Miamians are using painful experiences, creativity to power change (11/06/18 11:00am) The following reflects the majority opinion of the editorial board. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/11/miami-students-use-creativity-to-power-change 'Kick back', 'fight back': Former Miami student finds healing in helping others (11/06/18 10:01am) While sitting in the AMC Dine-In movie theater in the Anderson neighborhood of Cincinnati early last December, Maria Racadio struggled to put aside the thoughts eating inside her brain. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/11/kick-back-fight-back KickBackBathCo.jpg (11/06/18 3:08am) https://www.miamistudent.net/multimedia/4d342dba-f697-4105-8903-c9b28d33996f &amp;quot;The Right to Grow Old&amp;quot;: Capturing Hondurans' fight to live through photographs (10/16/18 9:01am) Tomas Ayuso has spent the last couple years traveling through Central America and Mexico, photographing people and telling their stories. In his latest project, titled &amp;quot;The Right to Grow Old,&amp;quot; Ayuso captured photos of Hondurans and their fight to live. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/10/photojournalist-captures-hondurans-fight-to-live Football shows resilience, throttles Akron for second win (10/09/18 9:00am) Throughout the first five weeks of the 2018 campaign, the Miami RedHawks perplexed fans and analysts alike. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/10/football-shows-resilience-throttles-akron-for-second-win Can we make 'Stranger Danger' a little more realistic, please? (10/02/18 9:30am) When I was in sixth grade, our local &amp;quot;Officer Smiley,&amp;quot; the name he gave to kids, visited classrooms once a month to talk about &amp;quot;Stranger Danger.&amp;quot; https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/10/can-we-make-stranger-danger-a-little-more-realistic-please Volleyball sweeps Northern Illinois (10/02/18 9:00am) With the RedHawks down 24-23 to Northern Illinois University in the second set on Sunday, junior libero Emma Leahy reassured her teammates from the sideline, yelling, &amp;quot;Hey, you're good!&amp;quot; https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/10/volleyball-sweeps-northern-illinois The tale of &amp;quot;two&amp;quot;s - Miami travels to Minnesota (09/14/18 9:00am) Saturday's Miami-Minnesota game is a matchup of two teams in very different positions two weeks into the 2018 season. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/09/the-tale-of-twos-miami-travels-to-minnesota New year, same story (09/11/18 9:00am) vinelca@miamioh.edu, @ChrisAVinel https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/09/new-year-same-story Kanye aims for open-mindedness, misses the mark (05/08/18 9:04pm) It's tradition by now: right before the release of a new record, Kanye West makes waves in the news. This manifests itself in his rageful tirades in interviews promoting 2013's &amp;quot;Yeezus&amp;quot; and in the incoherent, shambly rollout of 2016's &amp;quot;The Life of Pablo.&amp;quot; https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/05/kanye-aims-for-open-mindedness-misses-the-mark Happiness: Fickle, but worth striving for (03/27/18 12:00pm) At the beginning of this year, a wise professor told my class that we need to prioritize physical health and mental wellness above all else, and the best way to achieve that is to subscribe to a systematic planner. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/03/happiness-fickle-but-worth-striving-for The guys who make it and the guys who don't (02/13/18 12:00pm) Defenseman Grant Hutton often feeds forward Josh Melnick for transitions out of Miami's defensive zone. Melnick may dump the puck and forward Karch Bachman will use his speed to try to make space in the offensive zone. Forward Carson Meyer may then jump off the bench for a line change and, if defenseman Louie Belpedio is pinching, Meyer might find Belpedio in front of the net. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2018/02/the-guys-who-make-it-and-the-guys-who-dont TMS picks the 20 best albums of the year (12/07/17 2:55am) Here are the 20 best albums of 2017 (so far). https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2017/12/tms-picks-the-20-best-albums-of-the-year Sgt. Michelle Hercules: Strength and beauty (12/05/17 10:00am) She doesn't look nearly as tired as she must be. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2017/12/sgt-michelle-hercules-strength-and-beauty Women's self-defense class a rank above the rest (11/28/17 10:30am) It was Thursday. It was dark. I was Uptown, walking alone past a brooding Brick Street and suspicious cars tucked in alleyways. Walking alone at night reminds me of horror stories from family and friends, sexual assault notifications and the statistics that aren't in my favor. https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2017/11/womens-self-defense-class-a-rank-above-the-rest&quot;&gt;The Miami Student&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;in November 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Thursday. It was dark. I was Uptown, walking alone past a brooding Brick Street and suspicious cars tucked in alleyways. Walking alone at night reminds me of horror stories from family and friends, sexual assault notifications and the statistics that aren’t in my favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what drives the demand behind the women’s self-defense classes run by Tier 2 Defense. Tier 2 CEO Chris Cravens has eight years of experience in the U.S. Marine Corps Infantry, followed by work for a protective agency. Cravens also protected for a time on behalf of the U.S. Naval Criminal Investigative Service, or NCIS. The Tier 2 self defense syllabus for both law enforcement classes and women’s self-defense classes on college campuses is based on his experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on my way to Tier 2’s first-ever lesson at the Oxford Community Arts Center. The lesson ran from 7-9 p.m. (Another class marketed to Miami students is coming up on Nov. 30).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite spending the better part of the past year attending krav maga classes and learning tae kwon do, judo and hapkido with Miami’s Red Dragons martial arts club, I was about to find out I had been too tense to be able to effectively defend myself on my walk home in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While women’s self defense classes are often free of charge, they are nowhere near as intensive as the mindset training and maneuvers Tier 2 instructor Justin Goshorn focused on. He trained for a time in Langley, Virginia, to prepare for his current position, but he first worked for Tier 2 as a janitor before working his way up to an instructor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most self-defense classes offer a brief mindset or attitude training, but Goshorn began by pulling up a PowerPoint presentation complete with bullet points covering the legal rights of someone facing an assailant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you do have the right to defend yourself, Goshorn said that “you must be able to demonstrate you were not the initial aggressor,” since your attacker can file a civil suit if you injure them in a fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t punch someone just because they harrassed you at a bar,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unable to prove this in a court of law, consequences can land on you instead of the aggressor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You may be charged with assault even if you only use the force necessary to defend yourself,” Goshorn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the legal definition of aggression extends to the verbal kind as well — for example, if someone is intentionally intimidating you to get in their car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goshorn recommended escaping a situation as quickly as possible to avoid a lawsuit. He then moved on to what you should do before, during and after a potential physical altercation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is more applicable to your daily life than the moves you’ll learn later on in the training,” Goshorn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being aware of your surroundings can allow you to remove yourself from a situation before it starts. Goshorn also mentioned the importance of having a healthy amount of suspicion about people’s behavior and appearance, but warned that this was relative, citing the most recent high-profile sexual assaults in the news as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s okay to be suspicious of someone wearing a hoodie, but that does not mean a guy in a suit can’t be a potential aggressor,” Goshorn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Goshorn’s presentation, the 38 of us paired up to practice key moves that could apply to multiple situations. Goshorn and his assistant instructor, Chris Kleiner, would demonstrate a maneuver before allowing the class to break out and try the move on each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I paired up with a woman who’d been correcting the Chinese characters in her young daughter’s workbook before class started. Her name is Lei Kerr, a Miami University engineering professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think an attacker would be much taller than me. I need to be able to strike higher,” Kerr said while she practiced a lance strike — a quick hit to the throat with the space between the forefinger and thumb — on my forearm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kerr and I also practiced getting out of a hold if an attacker wraps their arms around you from behind, if they push you up against a wall and then if they are on top of you and holding you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goshorn encouraged everyone to return for another class. A two-hour session is educational, he said, but it is not a guarantee that we would be prepared for a potentially dangerous situation years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class was made up of Oxford residents of all sizes and ages, including Joelah Marcum, a 14-year-old who dances regularly at the Flowing Grace School of Dance studio, which hosted the lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not that you’ll necessarily have to go through this, but it makes you feel confident that you would be able to survive it,” Marcum said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcum and fellow dancer Sarah Webster, 17, asked the instructors questions long after the class ended. What if an attacker pinned you to the wall this way? What if they were holding you down this way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You see a bunch of scary stories all over the news and you think, ‘Oh my goodness, would I be able to survive this?” Webster said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tier 2 curriculum does not teach punching, kicking or kneeing techniques because this will supposedly come naturally in a dangerous situation. Goshorn leaves the “nitty gritty” details to traditional martial arts schools and gyms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the dark walk back to my dorm, I could tell Brick was packed through the windows. Music blared on both sides of Main Street. But after the Tier 2 Defense class, I felt a bit safer — relaxed, even — on my way to the other side of campus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/28/Womens-self-defence-class-rank/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/28/Womens-self-defence-class-rank/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABB press release: Monarch Cement purchases ABB upgrade to improve operator interface</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;abb-upgrades-cement-manufacturers-abb-knowledge-manager-and-laboratory-information-management-system-lims&quot;&gt;ABB upgrades cement manufacturer’s ABB Knowledge Manager and Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westerville, OHIO, USA—Monarch Cement awarded ABB a contract to upgrade their ABB Knowledge Manager and extend their ABB LIMS at Monarch’s Humboldt, Kansas, USA site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monarch will receive the latest version of ABB Knowledge Manager, which is updated with ABB AbilityTM System 800xA integration, increased reporting capability and improved user interface. The updated LIMS will run under one common operator interface for ease of data sharing, and also enable comprehensive data mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB LIMS works with ABB Knowledge Manager to manage quality information at laboratories serving process industries, covering tasks from routine quality control to final product tests and compliance certificates. ABB’s Knowledge Manager provides solutions and advanced tools to facilitate the collection, consolidation and distribution of production, quality and energy information via the plant’s web-based reports, trends, and graphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Monarch Cement Company (OTCMKTS: MCEM) has produced the highest quality cement for its customers in the Midwest for over nine decades. Today Monarch serves all or parts of Arkansas, Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, Nebraska, and Oklahoma from the Humboldt plant as well as Monarch’s terminals in Des Moines, Iowa and Dodge City, Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB (ABBN: SIX Swiss Ex) is a pioneering technology leader in electrification products, robotics and motion, industrial automation and power grids, serving customers in utilities, industry and transport and infrastructure globally. Continuing more than a 125-year history of innovation, ABB today is writing the future of industrial digitalization and driving the Energy and Fourth Industrial Revolutions. ABB operates in more than 100 countries with about 132,000 employees. www.abb.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 13:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/12/abb-press-release-monarch-cement-purchases-abb-upgrade-to-improve-operator-interface/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/12/abb-press-release-monarch-cement-purchases-abb-upgrade-to-improve-operator-interface/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABB press release: Indonesian oil and gas leader upgrades ABB Ability 800xA feature</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www04.abb.com/global/abbzh/abbzh251.nsf!OpenDatabase&amp;amp;db=/global/abbzh/abbzh250.nsf&amp;amp;v=553E&amp;amp;e=us&amp;amp;url=/global/seitp/seitp202.nsf/0/0AD3FA53B536C42EC12581860066A50B!OpenDocument&quot;&gt;abb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westerville, OHIO, USA—Private oil and gas leader PT Medco Energi Internasional Tbk (MedcoEnergi) renewed and extended its ABB Service Agreement for its site located in Lematang Block, South Sumatra province, Indonesia. The three-year agreement continues the same ABB rapid response and preventive maintenance services as the MedcoEnergi’s previous two-year agreement, and adds a Human Machine Interface (HMI) upgrade to MedcoEnergi’s existing ABB AbilityTM System 800xA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB AbilityTM System 800xA provides the functionality of a Distributed Control System, Electrical Control System and a Safety system to help plant operators make accurate and timely decisions. The HMI upgrade includes features that will provide increased operator efficiency, safety and capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB Oil and Gas Care is a modular service agreement framework designed to cut complexity, control cost, and maximize capital for ABB customers. ABB Oil and Gas Care offers: Rapid Response, which guarantees fast and flexible service response to maximize equipment availability; Lifecycle Management, which provides our powerful tools and knowledge base to optimize and extend equipment life; and Performance Improvement, which increases productivity through usability and efficiency optimization of equipment and processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MedcoEnergi (MEDC: IDX) is a publicly listed, integrated energy and natural resources company with significant interests in Mining and Power Generation alongside its core Oil &amp;amp; Gas Exploration &amp;amp; Production activities in Indonesia, the Middle East, North Africa and the US. (www.medcoenergi.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB (ABBN: SIX Swiss Ex) is a pioneering technology leader in electrification products, robotics and motion, industrial automation and power grids, serving customers in utilities, industry and transport &amp;amp; infrastructure globally. Continuing more than a 125-year history of innovation, ABB today is writing the future of industrial digitalization and driving the Energy and Fourth Industrial Revolutions. ABB operates in more than 100 countries with about 136,000 employees. www.abb.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 13:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/12/abb-press-release-indonesian-oil-and-gas-leader-upgrades-abb-ability-800xa-feature/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/12/abb-press-release-indonesian-oil-and-gas-leader-upgrades-abb-ability-800xa-feature/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABB press release: ArcelorMittal evolution path leads to ABB Ability upgrades</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;longtime-abb-steel-customer-orders-improvement&quot;&gt;Longtime ABB steel customer orders improvement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abb.co.in/cawp/seitp202/3f90f076010a97a6c125818600649f83.aspx&quot;&gt;abb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westerville, OHIO, USA—ABB received an order from ArcelorMittal Long Products Canada, a steel producer in Contrecoeur, Quebec, Canada, to upgrade their ABB AbilityTM System 800xA Human Machine Interface (HMI) in their profile mill to system version 6.0 with AC400 connect. ABB will also retrofit some of their DC Drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB AbilityTM System 800xA provides the functionality of a Distributed Control System, Electrical Control System and a Safety system to help plant operators make accurate and timely decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ArcelorMittal Long Products Canada is a steel producer with locations in Quebec and Ontario. They specialize in the manufacture of semi-finished products such as billets, slabs, bars and rod. These products are dedicated mostly to the construction and automotive markets, but also to other industrial uses. ArcelorMittal Long Products Canada is part of ArcelorMittal’s North America group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABB (ABBN: SIX Swiss Ex) is a pioneering technology leader in electrification products, robotics and motion, industrial automation and power grids, serving customers in utilities, industry and transport and infrastructure globally. Continuing more than a 125-year history of innovation, ABB today is writing the future of industrial digitalization and driving the Energy and Fourth Industrial Revolutions. ABB operates in more than 100 countries with about 132,000 employees. www.abb.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 13:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/10/abb-press-release-arcelormittal-evolution-path-leads-to-abb-ability-upgrades/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/10/abb-press-release-arcelormittal-evolution-path-leads-to-abb-ability-upgrades/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Missing home and hot tortillas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An early draft of this was originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://miamistudent.net/missing-home-and-hot-tortillas/&quot;&gt;The Miami Student&lt;/a&gt; in September 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I should wait to visit. I’ve only been at school for a few days,” I say over the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family only lives two hours away, but it’s my first weekend away at Miami and they already want me to come visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my family, but maybe I should have chosen an out-of-state school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I start calling Miami my home the day I move in. I love my new friends, I love the campus and I love being disappointed every time I see Brick Street’s entrance and think it’s a movie theater. I can’t wrap my head around being homesick in such a place because I’m ready to live such a life, just like that moving (and propaganda-tinged) poem said I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not ready for the feeling when it hits. I’m fighting procrastination in my dorm alone, when my stomach outright scoffs at my growing to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I open my fridge for the Mission brand tortillas graciously given to freshman students without anything to put inside, and can’t push away the memory of my grandma’s homemade tortillas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission tortillas taste fine when microwaved, but they don’t taste like home. I spit out the limp bite of flour, remembering how hot a fresh tortilla is when you snatch it off the pan with just your fingers. Homemade tortillas taste good even when you don’t have anything to stuff them with, even when they grow cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name sounds white, I look white and I am mostly white. I check “Caucasian” on the U.S. Census. But my great grandma Rodriguez greets the men in our family with an ecstatic “Papasito!” and kisses their cheek, and tells tales of the teachers in San Antonio who scorned her for her accent and her appearance. And my grandma wistfully recalls when she could speak fluent Spanish just as well as she remembers the recipes from her late Mexican restaurant, which closed before I was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heritage is part of my identity, even though I feel strange sharing it. I want to, but I also don’t want to lay claim to the experiences I don’t have. It gets awkward when a white girl reminisces about her grandma making mexican food for Thanksgiving, especially to someone who actually looks the part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how to fight this kind of homesickness here. Instead, I call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Grandma, can we make tortillas this weekend?”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/Missing-home-and-hot-tortillas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/Missing-home-and-hot-tortillas/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now accepting roommate applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accepted to college? Check. Cried over your scholarships, or lack thereof? Check. Joined the Facebook group? Check. Now all you need to score a roommate is an uber-detailed summary about yourself. But who has time for that?! Save some of your last precious moments of high school by screenshotting one of these Facebook autobiographies instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;216&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-02.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOR THE JOCK: Hi, my name is probably Brad. I played all the sports in high school, and I’ve provided some sweet action shots taken by my mom to show that off. Grades are important to me so I can stay on my gains. I’m most likely studying something in business, but on the weekends I’ll be getting a Ph.D. in partying—I mean, networking with my fellow peers. I’m looking for a chill roommate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-03.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOR THE MUSICAL THEATRE GEEK: Hey everyone! My name is something upbeat like Carly. I’m 100 percent committed to this school’s music and arts programs, and I’m so excited about it I could sing—both literally and figuratively! I was in show choir, but you could tell that a mile away from this sparkly outfit I’m wearing in at least one picture. I am very specific about the music I listen to and also mentioned the musical “Hamilton” somewhere in my post. If you don’t mind me practicing facial expressions in the mirror or losing against me in a karaoke competition then we should be roommates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-04.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR THE FUTURE FRAT BRO: Hey guys, I’m Chad. Brad and I are already bros, and I convinced him to rush Sigma Apple Pie this year with me. You can see based on my photos that I’m always down for a good time. Follow me on all my other social media, because my life is wayyy too lit to post on Facebook where my grandparents are. Feel free to message me too, but if you’re a girl and I think you’re hot I may or may not aggressively DM you first. Gotta practice for Sigma traditions, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-05.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR THE FUTURE SORORITY SIS: Hey all! I have a popular name like Samantha, and I’m super pumped for college life! I am a walking @dory twitter account which makes me super relatable, and I will get hella likes on this post. I love working out and I can study, but I’m also going to vaguely hint that I know how to party like there is no tomorrow. I am rushing for the Chi Omega-Three Vitamins sisterhood, so if you have a problem with my love for Greek life I will throw a toga at you on my way to the latest frat party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;244&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/images/posts/roommate-06.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR THE CONTROL FREAK: Hi everyone. You will only remember me as the crazy person with a billion planned activities, so my name is pretty irrelevant. I’ve provided bullet points of all my current achievements as well as my five-year plan, because I don’t have time to spend 15 minutes on a Facebook post. That said, this will still be an autobiography’s worth of facts about me because I can’t stand not doing the absolute most. This list might include student government, three seasons of sports where I was captain, along with a shortlist of nondescript clubs. My idea of fun involves having my crap together. I’m in the honors dorm this year so if you don’t have a 5.0 GPA, you probably can’t hang.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Now-accepting-roomate-applications/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Now-accepting-roomate-applications/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Juniors be warned: college apps are expensive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone talks about getting into college, but no one mentions the fees involved. Aspiring college students spend hours filling out personal information, writing essays, collecting teacher recommendations and sending test scores to get into schools of their dreams—only to pay a fee just to send an application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, students on average spent $41 on an application fee, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/education/best-colleges/the-short-list-college/articles/2015/12/01/colleges-that-charge-students-the-most-to-apply&quot;&gt;usnews.com&lt;/a&gt;. However, students often apply to more than one college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the time you are a senior, you should have three to five schools you are serious about. I know that $40 to $60 for each can add up,” guidance counselor Mike Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average student will pay $120 to $205 total in application fees, unless they request a fee waiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High school senior Jessica Jones spent $60 to apply to The Ohio State University, on top of applications sent to University of Dayton (although this fee was waived), University of Cincinnati ($50), Ohio University ($70) and Bowling Green State University ($45). She paid a total of $165 in application fees. After she was accepted, she was required to pay $100 more to commit to tOSU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I understand the application fee, since someone has to be paid to read them,” Jones said. “The acceptance fee seems ridiculous to me. If I’m going there, won’t I give them enough money anyways?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to economics teacher Joseph Cellar, whose wife Leslie formerly worked as an admissions counselor at Ohio Wesleyan University, there is an entire committee behind the admissions process taking home hours worth of applications. While she never provided a comment, J. Cellar said each individual on the committee at the time of L. Cellar’s employment was paid approximately $50,000 in wages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colleges charge these increasingly exorbitant fees to fund marketing campaigns and salaries of admissions counselors. University fiscal reports lump together revenue made from both tuition and fees, so where the money is funneled is unclear. Despite not knowing exactly where their money goes, most applicants are willing to pay the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We do have a segment of the Olentangy student population where they approach the process by wanting to go to the most prestigious college possible and they consider this factor above all others. They want to see if they can get in. At least one or two apply to 10 or more colleges,” Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest a student of Naveau’s has applied to is 16, but Naveau claims the highest in department history was 18.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Juniors-be-warned-college-apps-are-expensive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/Juniors-be-warned-college-apps-are-expensive/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Student’s foundation creates change in India slums</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;They were born in the country, yet are not considered citizens. They don’t have access to a stable job, so they live on less than $10 a month. They are not provided schooling or healthcare, when they are the ones who need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social class caste system of India known as Varna prevents the Dalit—the lowest rung on the caste—from opportunities we take for granted in the United States, according to &lt;a href=&quot;borgenmagazine.com&quot;&gt;borgenmagazine.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vision Foundation is a nonprofit education that provides healthcare and education in the Dharavi slums of Mumbai, India every summer—yet the foundation’s president, senior Esha Chadha, is 18 years old and lives half a world away in Lewis Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They are not citizens, so they have no fundamental rights,” Chadha said. “They are not allowed education or healthcare, so they need an outside source to provide those things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last summer, the foundation gave artificial lenses to 133 blind children in the slums of Mumbai, India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The children were not born without sight, but were made blind to be more successful at begging,” Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orphanages use maiming techniques on children to gain more sympathy from passerbys unlikely to give their money to a healthy child, according to Chadha. The Vision Foundation’s primary goal is to turn children away from begging and toward learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Once they have their eyesight, they can focus on getting an education,” Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a two-week period, Chadha taught basic math in the slums alongside a few volunteer teachers. She also spoke to 300-400 women and children in the slums about domestic violence, civil rights and the dangers of sending children—girls in particular—out on the streets to beg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Begging causes a lot of problems in India. It leaves children vulnerable to rape and murder,” Chadha said. “No one else would talk to them about [their rights].”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chadha’s history of volunteering in India began long before she took up the presidential role in summer 2016. Chadha grew up between two places she called home—one in the state of Ohio and the other in Mumbai, India. Her aunt, Neena Chadha, brought along E. Chadha and her twin brother, Arjun Chadha, to donate food to the slums. According to cia.gov, 43.5 percent of children in India under five years of age are underweight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most of their food is donated, but other than that they’re on their own,” E. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chadha also paid for education needs on occasion, since people in the slums are not granted schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re doing a project on Malala [Yousafzai] in English class, comparing education all over the world. [Olentangy is] so much more advanced in comparison to both [schools in the United States and around the world],” Kirsten K. ‘20 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chadha claims some applied for televised Indian dance shows, but were turned away due to their social status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They aren’t provided education, but they are talented kids, especially in dancing and music, since they don’t have much else to do,” E. Chadha said. “In the slums, they are all moving backward while everyone else moves forward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Family friend Prasoon Dixit ran the foundation before he appointed E. Chadha as president. E. Chadha said he noticed her throwing herself into the foundation following her aunt’s death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My aunt was one of the last of my family still in India. I wanted a reason to come back home even without having family there,” E. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation morphed into a family affair following E. Chadha’s new role. E. Chadha’s sister, Neha Chadha, is putting together an official website, while A. Chadha attended the trip last summer to clean up slums in disrepair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The slums do not even have houses. Their roof may be a bedsheet. Their bed is the floor,” E. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While A. Chadha removed trash and recycled plastic, living conditions in the slums cannot remain clean without continual support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People complain about life in this country, but they have no clue about the conditions [the Dalit are] living in,” English teacher Sarah Zettler said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/geos/in.html&quot;&gt;cia.gov&lt;/a&gt;, 71.5 percent of India’s rural population—where most slums are located—has unimproved sanitation facility access. These living conditions allow “major infectious diseases” in India such as malaria, dengue fever, rabies and hepatitis strains to spread more quickly throughout slums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is really dirty and unhygienic there. A lot of kids are passing away from infections. If you ate their food, you would get sick and have to go to the hospital,” A. Chadha said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While attending school in the United States, E. Chadha recruits U.S. doctors, nurses and teachers to work with her in India. She is seeking a new doctor to help her set up another blind camp this upcoming summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation has already created massive positive change, but E. Chadha claims the Vision Foundation is relatively small and hopes to expand the charity over time. Those who would like to get involved with the Vision Foundation can visit their Facebook page or email E. Chadha at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:eshachadha@gmail.com&quot;&gt;eshachadha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/Students-foundation-creates-change-in-india-slums/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/Students-foundation-creates-change-in-india-slums/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerschool helps, harms student stress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teen stress rivals that of adults during the school year, according to data collected from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apapracticecentral.org/update/2014/02-13/teen-stress.aspx&quot;&gt;2014 Stress in America survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A lot of things stress me out, especially Powerschool,” Justin F. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While colleges look for the well-rounded individual as the ideal student, the importance of grades has not lessened in the college admission process. This is one of the reasons the district introduced Powerschool, a program which helps parents and students track grades online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is more helpful to have current, updated grades as opposed to waiting to get the report card in the mail,” guidance counselor Meghan Roberts said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freshmen Jaclyn H., Grace M. and Simi A. felt Powerschool reduced stress in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In elementary school I had anxiety about when I would get a test back,” Assi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simi’s stress waned with the introduction of Powerschool, since it removes her fear of not knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I check [Powerschool] multiple times a day if I know an assignment is coming in soon,” Simmi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberts recommends students and parents check Powerschool once or twice a week to monitor progress, and even less for students who know their grades cause them stress. However, many students check Powerschool to lower stress over grades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I’m able to see what I’m doing bad in, then I can help that grade [improve] so I know what to do,” Jenna W. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frequency with which students and parents check grades varies from the recommended amount to several times per day. Grace and Jaclyn check it once a day, while Simi on average checks it “once in the morning and once at night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents who receive Powerschool notifications tend to check it more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Notifications] come in once or twice a week, at least,” Jaclyn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When teachers post new assignments, however, parents see it and confront students more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whenever they know I have a test, they ask about my grade,” Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Grace views the pressure from her parents in a positive light, Justin does not feel the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[My parents are] on my case about it, and it stresses me out more than it should,” Justin said. “When the grade from something that would boost my grade doesn’t come in immediately, they say, ‘hey, you didn’t work on this,’ when I did work on it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberts recognizes the “occasional confusion” Powerschool creates, but she argues the benefits outweigh the costs—and one bad grade is not going to ruin a student’s future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s the end of the year grade that is going to hit your transcript. A little dip is not going to hurt you,” Roberts said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Powerschool-helps-harms-student-stress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Powerschool-helps-harms-student-stress/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get off the couch, see these movies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/before-i-fall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Before-I-Fall&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q3Zyy4ZXegE&quot;&gt;Before I Fall&lt;/a&gt;” (PG-13) — three-point-five stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular girl lives the same day over and over after experiencing a tragedy and reevaluates her life choices in the process. Prior to watching the film, I incorrectly assumed this was a romantic drama. I am lucky enough to have found a boy who doesn’t mind “chick flicks,” so I was in good company; however, this screen version of a novel of the same name by Lauren Oliver was not what either of us anticipated. The repetitive day did not bore me into giving it three-point-five stars, but the shallow character development did. However, this movie will still make you feel all the feelings for family, friends and strangers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Pregame for this serious “Mean Girls”-esque movie with the latest seasonal Starbucks drink, then get basic white girl concessions: a small cherry ICEE and a box candy of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/get-out.png&quot; alt=&quot;Get-Out-Movie&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sRfnevzM9kQ&quot;&gt;Get Out&lt;/a&gt;” (R) — five stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris’ girlfriend takes him to her white parents’ plantation house, where his awkward interactions with her strange family escalate into dystopian violence. Actor Daniel Kaluuya, who plays main character Chris, was also the protagonist in the British horror TV show “Black Mirror” episode “Fifteen Million Merits”—I expected a lot out of this thriller, and I was not disappointed. Director Jordan Peele (half of the “Key and Peele” comedian duo) injects profound messages alongside surprising humor, often in the form of Chris’ TSA friend Rod, played by Lil Rel Howery. The Armitage family incites more psychological violence on Chris than physical—they claim they only intend for him to enjoy himself, but their psychopathic attitudes toward his skin color lie just underneath the surface from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Stress eat all your popcorn in the first scene so you don’t jump during a scary moment later and spill it everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/logan-movie.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Logan-Movie&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Div0iP65aZo&quot;&gt;Logan&lt;/a&gt;” (R) — four stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aging Wolverine and Professor Xavier drive across the country with Hispanic mutant girl Laura (played by Dafne Keen) in an unsuccessful attempt to avoid a clandestine cloning company. The villains were an unwelcome distraction from the three characters’ camaraderie, who bicker in true-to-form family road trip style—except in bullet-ridden cars, of course. However, the grudging bond between past and future Wolverines, Logan and Laura, grows into true respect in the final moments. Xavier’s deterioration due to Alzheimer’s makes an important statement about aging. While this will be the final Wolverine sequel, it is set in 2029 so we should at least expect more Logan and Xavier cameos in upcoming X-Men films. Laura shredded their adversaries just as well as Logan, and if she doesn’t star in future films I will boycott Marvel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Superheroes go big or go home, and so should you with the large drink and popcorn combo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/john-wick-2-movie.webp&quot; alt=&quot;John-Wick-2&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChpLV9AMqm4&quot;&gt;John Wick Chapter Two&lt;/a&gt;” (R) — two stars out of five&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sole reason I bothered to see this movie was because my self defense instructor recommended Keanu Reeve’s stellar fight scenes, but that and Wick’s dog were the only things going for it. To be fair, I did not see the first “John Wick,” but after seeing this garbage I don’t want to. I wanted to throw my popcorn at Keanu Reeves every time he opened his mouth and choked on his lines. The weird subtitle font, cheesy acting and overdramatic music reminded me of a bad Spanish telenovela. Actress Ruby Rose is not even deaf but plays a hearing-impaired bodyguard for the villain—an impressive and underused actress, but she plays a part which could go to someone who is actually deaf. Wick never named his dog and left it with someone else for most of the movie, which was why I rated this so low—other than how many of my brain cells died while trying to comprehend the awfulness of this movie. I should have waited for this to launch on Netflix, so I could mute it and fast-forward to the fight scenes and whenever his dog showed up on screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concession recommendation: Don’t even come to see this trash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Get-off-the-couch-see-these-movies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Get-off-the-couch-see-these-movies/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feminism vs. Equalism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a full version of my letter from the editor originally published and cut down due to spacing issues in the March 2017 issue of The Beacon. This is a response to a letter to the editor from a student who did not agree with our feminism in-depth spread.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Beacon editor and fellow student, thank you for your lively reply to our in-depth opinion article on feminism. However, there are a few errors in your response I need to point out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You claimed the article should have remained unbiased in the face of such a controversial issue. However, the article was an “in-depth opinion,” and we labeled it so on the top-middle section of the page and in the table of contents. An opinion piece, by definition, carries a slant. Opinion articles should at least bring up the opposing side’s viewpoint, then follow it with a counterargument, which is how our writers conducted the structure of the piece. All information included in the article was true, albeit filtered with a clear stance on the issue which was appropriate for opinion writing style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your statement claiming we are a school-funded—and therefore government-funded—publication to argue why The Beacon should remain unbiased is also incorrect. The Beacon is in fact funded by the small businesses and organizations who buy advertisements from us, as well as the issues we sell monthly. We do not receive funding in any form from the school. This is also mentioned in our policy statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the freedom of speech protects The Beacon’s writers as well as your opinion, it also protects mine. While the Latin definition of the word “fem” is, as you said, “feminine,” the term’s history, and therefore full meaning, carries a more complex connotation. Since this page doesn’t have enough space for me to describe the three waves of feminism and the changing goals of the feminist movement,* I will again repeat a variation of the official definition from reputable dictionaries: feminism recognizes the political, social and economic status of the sexes has yet to become equal. While women in the past made great strides in civil rights, we still have a long way to go to eliminate institutionalized sexism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have to tell you women make up about half of the population. This is one thing we have equal ground on. However, you might not be aware of the state of political inequality of women, looking at representation in the United States. Out of 535 members of Congress, 104 are female, according to the Center for American Women and Politics. Only the most qualified individuals should hold office, of course. But when men and women legally have equal opportunities to be elected into office, we have to look to social factors to understand why women’s representation in Congress is half of what it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender defines how parents should raise their children the moment they are born, and not just by choosing pink or blue paint for their bedroom wall. Girls are traditionally praised for being quiet, demure, pretty; boys are exalted for strength. They are expected to roughhouse and experiment but above all exhibit dominance, often in the form of aggression. While nothing seems inherently wrong with this parenting style, it assigns both genders respective advantages and disadvantages to navigate into adulthood. While some of these double standards do benefit women, most of them support men in a way which creates disproportionate demographics in the workforce—in particular the political, math and science fields, which encourages traditionally male traits and are still comprised of mostly men. Women with aspirations in these fields have a different set of obstacles to contend with than men, often with no clear outline available on how to combat them. While it is still possible for women to succeed in these fields, it puts them at a direct disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of “feminism” is for women to obtain the same social privileges men receive the moment they are born—not to be dominant over men, but to reach the same standards and expectations men are automatically granted. Bridging this gap also includes defying negative male stereotypes. “Equalism” debases the platform and meaning already built around feminism, and counteracts the focus on the need for women specifically to achieve equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, we would all be “equalists” as you say—but from what I can gather from your letter, you believe men and women are perfectly equal already and do not realize how this term debases the women and men who worked toward gender equality for over a century. The point of the article was to create a dialogue around a topic which is a major point of contention, and you opened up this conversation. The Beacon welcomes people of action like you to join in on discussions on a public platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you again for your response, and I hope you and readers like you are further encouraged to create a dialogue about issues of contention like gender. Only then will injustices and evidence of progress be brought to light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*A rundown of the changing goals of the feminist movement in the United States: the right to vote with the 19th Amendment, discrimination in the workplace, Equal Rights Amendment, Roe v. Wade, to the present: intersectional feminism, which incorporates all factors of inequality like race, socioeconomic status, sexual identity, etc. into the present inequality of the sexes; fighting female genital mutilation at home and abroad; addressing rape culture (which also applies to men but is often overlooked) and general violence against women; LGBTQ+ rights; challenges of people of color who identify as women; women’s health issues; unrealistic expectations for both men and women in society…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is too complex to summarize in one blog post. Not all feminists or even all women agree on all issues (linked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gloriasteinem.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Gloria Steinem) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.volkskrant.nl/boeken/ngozi-adichie-beyonce-s-feminism-isn-t-my-feminism~a4390684/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Beyonce and Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie’s somewhat conflicting viewpoints on feminism) are women of influence who seem to identify with the traditionally left-leaning feminist movement, linked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syracuse.com/celebrity-news/index.ssf/2017/05/kara_mccullough_healthcare_feminism_miss_usa_2017.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Miss USA 2017 preferring to call herself an equalist), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makers.com/phyllis-schlafly&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Phyllis Schlafly), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theblaze.com/video/tomi-lahren-offers-a-clear-message-to-left-wing-feminists-this-is-what-real-women-look-like/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Tomi Lahren) are examples of women of influence who distanced themselves from the word feminism, and linked here is the late &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/10/style/frida-kahlo-is-having-a-moment.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;Frida Kahlo&lt;/a&gt;, a Mexican artist also revered as an unapologetic feminist icon, although an unorthodox one). Educate yourself to see where you stand, whether or not you intend to join the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Feminism-vs-equalism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Feminism-vs-equalism/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cesar Chavez Day withstands today’s political climate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2017 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight states close school and government offices on March 31 for the national holiday celebrating the former leader of the late National Farm Workers Association (now known as United Farm Workers of America, or UFW).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Mahatma Gandhi’s strategies of nonviolence and fasting, Chavez cofounded the UFW with Dolores Huerta to advocate for better pay and safer working conditions for farm workers—many of whom identified as Mexican American and Filipino American, according to &lt;a href=&quot;ufw.org&quot;&gt;ufw.org&lt;/a&gt;.  In 1966, Chavez led the UFW’s 340 mile march from Delano, Calif. to Sacramento, Calif. to allow peaceful collective bargaining agreements between unions and the state government. Chavez endured three historic fasts to protest his own organization’s violent behavior and bring attention to the UFW’s “La Causa.” His longest fast in 1988 lasted 36 days, which influenced celebrities, politicians and religious leaders to continue the fast for several days to raise awareness of the UFW’s work—decades before the 2014 ALS ice bucket challenge raised awareness and money for its respective cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;recordsofrights.org&quot;&gt;recordsofrights.org&lt;/a&gt;, Chavez faced the greatest opposition from Delano, Calif. table grapes in 1968—a five-year-long boycott and strike protest—as well as pesticide proponents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 1989 address to Pacific Lutheran University, Chavez considered “protecting farm workers—and consumers—from systematic poisoning through the reckless use of agricultural toxins” more integral to the UFW’s cause than any other aspect of a safe working environment. This is still a point of contention in today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Monsanto is a company that does a lot of lobbying to get certain laws passed to allow pesticides to be used,” AP Environmental Science teacher Julie Effler said. “Touching” and “inhaling” chemicals is dangerous, as well as ingesting it via foods that are not organic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue the UFW continues to work toward in Chavez’s name is his stance on immigration. Chavez described illegal immigrants brought over by companies to break up UFW strikes as “wetbacks” and “illegals” in a 1972 KQED TV interview; he also supported President Ronald Reagan’s 1986 proposed immigration reform bill, according to NPR. The original bill converted illegal immigrants into citizens if they had lived in the United States since before 1982, on top of tightening border security and punishing employers who hired “scabs,” or illegal Mexican immigrants from Mexico, to continue working in protesters’ places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Growers were] in need of workers willing to work for less money, essentially taking advantage of those wanting a better life for themselves,” history teacher Daniel Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the UFW’s dismay, the section which put pressure on employers who hired scabs was eliminated to pass the bill as a law. However, Chavez’s past work in the UFW at the time had already made immense strides in farm worker’s rights. President Bill Clinton later gave a posthumous Presidential Medal of Freedom in Chavez’s name to the influencer’s wife, Helen, in 1994, a year after his death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight states touched by his existence (California, Arizona, Colorado, Michigan, New Mexico, Texas, Utah and Wisconsin) celebrate Cesar Chavez Day by closing government offices and school buildings, according to &lt;a href=&quot;time.com&quot;&gt;time.com&lt;/a&gt;. However, Lewis Center students such as freshman Rachel S. would not mind another day off of school—despite her limited knowledge of Cesar Chavez’s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If other states think it’s that important, they clearly must have reason for it,” Rachel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior Kayla Blanton does not agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know who he is. It doesn’t make sense for us to miss school for it,” Blanton said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Cesar-Chaves-day-withstands-todays-political-climate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/Cesar-Chaves-day-withstands-todays-political-climate/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Attraction turns scientific</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published as a cover article in the 2017 February issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is it about the glimmer in a pair of eyes across the room that makes you wish you knew the person behind them? Can we pin down the “je ne sais quoi,” or a special someone’s intangible beauty you can’t explain, that leaves one falling head over heels? Whether or not you already have a certain person in mind, the answer to making a connection may lie in a few psychological theories rather than a mystical connection. If you’re desperate to trap a boo, put your doubts aside for these borderline manipulation tactics, curated from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceofrelationships.com/home/2012/5/17/top-5-classic-studies-in-the-psychology-of-attraction.html&quot;&gt;scienceofrelationships.com&lt;/a&gt; and backed up by AP Psychology teacher Brian Wendel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your looks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If they take time to make themselves more presentable, they hold themselves to a higher standard,” Anthony Sasso ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal of beauty changes depending on who you talk to, but a cleanly appearance and good hygiene gives the impression of exceptional trustworthiness in any situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you walk into a job interview, and you don’t try to look nice, it looks like you don’t care,” Grace H. ‘19 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While stealing the attention of a love interest is not a major career move, taking care of your physical appearance—both synthetic and genetic—defines the iconic “love at first sight” plotline. However, some consider exceptional beauty at arm’s length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I just assume ‘she doesn’t like me, there’s no way,’” Luke S. ‘20 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freshman Joe D. agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m intimidated because I don’t think I’m good looking,” Joe said. “You critique yourself and what you did wrong when you have a chance to talk to them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Luke and Joe admitted feeling inadequate despite being otherwise confident in themselves. But those considered physically imposing may work harder to establish a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When someone is mangled, disfigured, or viewed as a threat it may prevent connection. We are biologically hardwired to not trust people outside our group biases,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proximity fosters genuine connection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily interactions reveal more about a person than the seven seconds it takes to make a first impression. We are more likely to become attracted to those we come in contact with on a daily basis rather than someone we pass once in the hallway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With a fellow student or coworker, you are usually going to have things in common,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strongest attraction over time, however, can stem from someone you once hated—per the mere exposure theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The mere exposure theory is a sequence of events occurring over months or years. There may be a certain person you have nothing in common with or are not even physically attracted to, but go through an evolution of your feelings for each other,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After initial dislike passes, a tolerance for one another develops into respect—which may turn into a deeper connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is based on compatibility rather than looks, so it can survive the test of time. This explains why arranged marriages are often successful,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opposites don’t attract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to surround ourselves with people who foster the same core beliefs and values; therefore, we are attracted to people who are similar to us—or are at least resemble an ideal we want to strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We tend to be attracted to characteristics we find admirable in ourselves,” Wendel said. “Similar interests, goals, thoughts and attitudes can certainly form an attraction between two people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it surprising to find out people are not magnets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I never look for someone who’s different from me. I look for someone who will push me out of my comfort zone, but still aligns with me,” Sasso said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It depends on who you find. If you find someone similar, you have stuff to talk about. But with someone different you have more to discover about one another,” Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, Wendel argues opposites attract when infatuation is involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Infatuation occurs when someone is more reckless, or unlike ourselves. This leans on physical characteristics, and traits or behaviors you know aren’t typical to your own,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fear creates romance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fancy dinner is classically romantic, as are chocolates and flowers. But to create an authentic chemistry between you two, scare the love out of your date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any time people share a traumatic experience, they experience a shared biochemical reaction,” Wendel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While studies focus on life-or-death situations, Wendel says any emotional bond creates a deeper feeling of attraction than the physical aspects of romance. To recreate this, put a spin on the classic “dinner and a movie”—or more likely “Netflix and chill”—by hitting “play” on the latest thriller… as long as the other person doesn’t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s more about what the girl is into, especially if you really like them,” Aiden M. ‘20 said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/Attraction-turns-scientific/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/Attraction-turns-scientific/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Holidays draw out religious differences</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first job in fast food at Subway. Five other workers worked up front with me on the notorious sandwich line, and together we cranked out orders like a machine. We did all we could to finish their meals as fast as possible, but I still felt guilty for holding up their holiday shopping. I finished up my current customer’s order with no problems, even with a line of angry people stretching past the booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Happy holidays!” I said, releasing a sigh of relief and a big smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t say that. That’s what terrorists say. Merry Christmas!” the customer said cheerily. My former manager agreed with him, and they shared a moment of bonding over their blatant intolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, two women wearing traditional hijab head coverings waited further down in line, silent amid the chaos of the food court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the most wonderful time of the year—except for those who do not share the same traditions as mainstream culture. The embedded impatience of the season tends to bring the worst out in shoppers. Those in the minimum wage workforce are exposed to little moments of people’s covert bias against others who do not look or celebrate like them. Holiday deals lure in customers, and long lines keep them long enough for an unsuspecting worker to see or hear snippets of underlying prejudice of Christmas time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family and I also celebrate Christmas and participate in mainstream traditions associated with the holiday. We listen to Christmas music, we put up a freshly cut pine in the corner of the living room and we cover presents in wrapping paper dotted with “Joy to the World” lyrics. I am a typical white girl, dark blonde hair and all. I do not want to speak for those who face these struggles this time of year, but I do wish to comment on the controversy of political correctness during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should not be offensive to say “happy holidays,” but the motivation behind it—to consider other religions or beliefs as well as those who celebrate Christmas—can be perceived as threatening to Christianity. Yes, Christians are still threatened in this country because of their faith. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucr.fbi.gov/hate-crime/2013/topic-pages/victims/victims_final&quot;&gt;FBI data&lt;/a&gt; collected in 2013, 105 hate crimes targeted Protestants and Catholics combined. However, 625 crimes were also committed against Jewish people and 135 attacked those of the Islamic faith in the same year. Everyone deserves a chance to exercise their religious freedom, but this does not mean it is okay to disregard other faiths in the process. We still have a long way to go toward acceptance of all people in our melting pot of a country, and this is just one aspect of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/01/Holidays-draw-out-religious-differences/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/01/Holidays-draw-out-religious-differences/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Voters OK Olentangy Levy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 16, 2016—Local newspapers reported the successful passing of the Olentangy levy, determined by voters a day prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Passage of yesterday’s ballot issue allows us to continue the level of excellence that has become the standard in our community,” Superintendent Mark Raiff said in a public thank you letter on the school website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with the standard means the district maintains AP classes, electives and extracurricular programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While building repairs, new technology and more teachers are also mentioned, these administrative decisions will alleviate student overcrowding in the district while construction is planned for a fourth high school on Berlin Station Road, another addition to the levy ballot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The design for the fourth high school will be similar to both Liberty and Orange high schools with some key updates and modifications,” Raiff said in an April 15 statement to the district community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The groundbreaking ceremony for the building site is set for June 9 of this year. Raiff expects to finish redrawing attendance boundaries by March 2017. Similar to building openings in the past, a senior class will not exist in the first year of opening. Student rearrangement will affect those in sixth, seventh and eighth grades this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No current high school students will change schools,” Raiff said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students already feel effects of overcrowding in school restrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before [classes], after classes and during lunch are the worst to go,” Muskan A. ‘19 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parking lot space is an additional concern for students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I changed my schedule second semester so I could get out early and avoid the after-school traffic,” Shayna Haberman ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Voters-ok-olentangy-levy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Voters-ok-olentangy-levy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sriram fulfills 2016 valedictorian dream</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, the only Olentangy High School student to qualify as a Class of 2016 valedictorian is Adithya Sriram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a young age, Sriram was already learning at a pace to become valedictorian, taking AP Calculus AB his freshman year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Needless to say, I did study a lot. I made a point to make sure I was always as prepared as I could be for big tests, so I was never reluctant to put in the time. I also studied in groups which made it a lot easier. I never got a tutor, but I did seek out extra help from teachers anytime I needed it,” Sriram said via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing about the valedictorian title as a freshman, Sriram sought advice from his guidance counselor, Michael Naveau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It takes a tremendous amount of work to achieve the marks to become valedictorian,” Guidance department head Michael Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sriram went on to take 15 APs total in four years. Somehow, he still has free time after his rigorous school schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I play Varsity tennis as a spring sport and play recreational tennis year-round. I play violin, I’m in chamber orchestra at school and in the Columbus Symphony Youth Orchestra. I’m also involved in robotics and biophysics research down at The Ohio State University,” Sriram said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Sriram was the sole qualified valedictorian announced last semester, co-valedictorians could join Sriram by the end of the year. To become valedictorian, school policy states “a student must have attended OHS for their entire fifth through eighth semesters,” score all As and carry the highest GPA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It just so happened that at the end of the seventh semester, one student made the qualifications. However, it’s possible if more seniors meet them at the end of the eighth semester, we could have more valedictorians,” Naveau said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For seniors with similar lofty goals, hope is not lost. School handbook policy on the topic refers to plural “valedictorians,” due to “the probability that the above criteria will result in more than one senior being recognized as valedictorian.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Sriram-fulfills-2016-validictorian-dream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Sriram-fulfills-2016-validictorian-dream/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Haikus to summarize senior year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 May issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope FAFSA comes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In clutch or imma strip to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pay off college debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior year is meant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fun? Tell that to all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of my AP classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last tests taken, last&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadlines made, last goodbyes said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As last days pass by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The senior deadlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are killing graduation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vibes these last few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senioritis KILLS…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPAs for the sake of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning the shootout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last days will soon be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distant memories for our&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 class.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Haikus-to-summarize-senior-year/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/01/Haikus-to-summarize-senior-year/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring-cleaning a worldwide phenomenon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other season motivates those suffering from chronic disorganization like the one at present. But what inspires us to make our living space just as beautiful as it is outside? Is it the budding greenery, or the fear of pollen and collected dust hijacking our sinuses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We clean in the spring to get clutter out of the house, and start new for the season,” Emma W. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever one’s personal motivations, the practice itself spans across cultures. The cleaning ritual of Khaneh-Tekani—or “shaking house”—is meant to prep the home for the Persian, Iranian and Zoroastrian New Year called Nowruz, according to &lt;a href=&quot;howstuffworks.com&quot;&gt;howstuffworks.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its origins, Thailand’s festival Songkran was a time to clean and to show respect for elders, by pouring water used to clean Buddha statues onto them. This cleansing tradition has since modernized into a mass water gun fight in the streets, since temperatures can reach up to 100 degrees in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the week of Passover, Jews eat the flatbread “matzo” in remembrance of the Israelites’ escape from slavery. People may burn, give away or donate chametz to get rid of it, on top of cleaning their house thoroughly. Having chametz, products used to make bread rise, in the house during Passover is frowned upon. However, this is not synonymous in every Jewish household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My great grandparents never did any of that and they were very religious. It’s more of an orthodox thing. It depends on the person and how religious they are,” Julianna Kickbusch ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring cleaning takes place in varying degrees of cleanliness, whether it be the soul, the body or the home. Yet the theme of clean seems to be universal wherever we come from, and whatever we do or do not celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/spring-cleaning-a-worldwide-phenomenon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/spring-cleaning-a-worldwide-phenomenon/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Cursed child&quot; lights new wand this Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 March issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An eighth installment of the Harry Potter series comes to London’s Palace Theatre this summer in two parts, called “Cursed Child.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a Gothic theatre. There’s a majesty there, and it has this Hogwarts feel to it,” “Cursed Child” playwright Jack Thorne said via &lt;a href=&quot;pottermore.com&quot;&gt;pottermore.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thorne and Tony award-winning director John Tiffany collaborated with J.K. Rowling to create the play. They would be hard-pressed to say no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d asked my three nephews and my grandchildren whether I should do this show. They’d all gone through Harry Potter, and they all said ‘We’ll kill you if you don’t,’” Tiffany said, according to pottermore.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many rumors followed the announcement of “Cursed Child.” Rowling responded via Twitter to false reports of a prequel and a botched title “Unearthly Child” reported by Radio Times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jk_rowling/status/703562900464640000?lang=en&quot;&gt;“Not a prequel. Not unearthly. Magical,” Rowling said on Twitter.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The play stars a grown-up Harry Potter, according to &lt;a href=&quot;harrypottertheplay.com&quot;&gt;harrypottertheplay.com&lt;/a&gt;. An aging Potter, played by Jamie Parker, is dissatisfied with his Ministry of Magic desk job while his fame tortures youngest son, Albus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowling also defended the decision to cast Olivier award-winner and black actress Noma Dumezweni as Hermione. The heroine’s race was never identified in the books, yet some fans are making a ruckus about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Diversifying the character makes Hermione a better character because [she] has more differences to overcome with race and wizard power and sexism,” Erin Devine ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, no one complained about the lack of red pigment in actor Paul Thornley’s hair, who plays Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re all preoccupied with race and women’s physical appearance in the media. Yet Harry had blue eyes instead of green in the movie, and now Ron is different. It just shows [boys appreciate the character’s true value over the character’s appearance]. No one cares about Rupert Grint,” Devine said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To monitor the arrival of the play, visit harrypottertheplay.com for more up-to-date information on the show’s development and a countdown to the release. For those unable to see their favorite characters come to life onstage, the play’s script book comes out July 31 this summer. But the new mode of writing could damage the Harry Potter reading experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s so many of the books that you become accustomed to a certain writing style. To change that at the very end might make it difficult for readers to enjoy,” school librarian Kaelin Harrison said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/cursed-child-lights/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/03/01/cursed-child-lights/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Reasons to Vote for Vermin Supreme! in 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 February issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sat·ire    ˈsaˌtī(ə)r/     noun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the use of humor, irony, exaggeration, or ridicule to expose and criticize people’s stupidity or vices, particularly in the context of contemporary politics and other topical issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s the 2016 presidential candidate you never heard of, but wish you did. &lt;a href=&quot;https://verminsupreme2016.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Vermin Love Supreme&lt;/a&gt;—his legal name—and his zany wizard style cannot be topped. Not even a certain presidential hopeful with a bad haircut can trump Supreme, and here are 10 reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are you indecisive? Then Vermin Supreme is the candidate for you. His campaign slogan delivers the promise: “The decision to vote for Vermin Supreme! is the last decision you will ever have to make.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are you a Doomsday Prepper? If so, you would be ahead of the curve under Supreme’s regime. With the zombie apocalypse fast approaching, no other candidate is more concerned for the country’s welfare than the King of the Rats.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you reject conventional weddings? Supreme is a certified minister for the Universal Life Church and licensed to officiate marriage ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always wanted a pony, but worried about money? As a member of the Pony Party, Supreme intends to rescue the economy by requiring everyone to own a pony. He claims this tactic will increase jobs, lower fossil fuel emissions and serve as a government-issued identification for citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you brush your teeth? Clean chompers may be rewarded under Supreme’s proposed mandatory tooth brushing law, which aims to combat “moral and oral decay.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you appreciate the magical properties of glitter? Supreme used the power of gold glitter to turn Republican candidate Randall Terry “gay” in 2011. A recording of the ritual can be found on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you despise conventional fashion? The signature wide-calf rubber boot he wears as a hat may strike a chord in your own rebellious sole.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you despise protest violence? According to cnn.com, Supreme diffused tension between police and 2012 Florida protesters with humor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are you in denial of Dumbledore’s death? Of course you are. Let the leadership of this wizard doppelganger console your grief.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not care about the political process, anyway? You might as well give up any rights you still have by electing this self-described “friendly fascist.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/01/10-Reasons-to-vote-for-Vermin-Supreme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/02/01/10-Reasons-to-vote-for-Vermin-Supreme/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Islamophobia in the 21st century</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ohsbeacon.com/587/opinion/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/&quot;&gt;ohsbeacon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syrians fleeing violence have nowhere to go as countries turn them away, fearing a surplus of immigrants—through unemployment, overcrowding and terrorism—will bring only trouble to their country in the wake of the Paris attacks orchestrated by the Islamic State of Iraq, better known as ISIS. This should not be an excuse to victimize innocent Muslims because of the actions of terrorists, but this truth is not apparent to some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re the same type of refugees in Germany and taking over Germany now. I don’t want them to be doing that here,” John S. ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Council on American-Islamic Relations defines Islamophobia as “close-minded prejudice against or hatred of Islam and Muslims.” The phenomenon is a negative reflection on the Muslim population based on violent acts of radical terrorist groups. These feelings have been built up from the Palestinian group Black September, who killed and took hostage of several Israeli Olympic staff members during the 1972 Munich Olympics, according to nps.gov, to the present-day ISIS, the extremist organization responsible for the recent Paris attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the falling of the Twin Towers sparked Islamophobia’s most notable uptick. The media and government made discrimination of Muslims almost commonplace at the time, misbranding the tragedy as an “Islamic attack” rather than a “terrorist attack on the U.S.,” World History teacher Daniel Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An approximate 3,000 people—from all ideologies, including Muslims with no involvement in the attacks—died in the Sept. 11 tragedy, according to cnn.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, terrorist attacks worldwide are claimed by whichever “Islamic fundamentalist” terrorist group holds the most power. Although these groups rise and fall, the impact of these catastrophes extremists claim take a negative toll on the daily lives of a majority of peaceful Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every terror attack claimed by a group related to Islam is a further hit to Islam relations with the United States or even social discrimination against Islamic people,” Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growing death toll worldwide caused by ever-present militant groups, it is easy to blame an entire religion or culture for the actions of one organization spilling blood in the name of Allah. It is easy to scrutinize Muslims at home, when innocent people—many of them holding a peaceful interpretation of the same faith as their assailants—are dying at the hands of those committing heinous acts in the name of their religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After big terrorist attacks or events that portray Islam negatively, [I receive] a bit more questioning looks,” Junior Faiz J. said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While anti-Muslim backlash is not shown in statistics to increase after such terrorist attacks, Islamophobic sentiment does seem to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They keep arguing that they’re peaceful, but I guess people and their religion are making it worse,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 2011 Pew Research Center study found 55 percent of the average Muslim public abroad opposes all violence (including suicide bombings) against civilians in any form. An average 38 percent of this same group held terrorist group al-Qaeda in low esteem. But not everyone is open to the idea of Muslims being anything but violent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re still from their own country. They can be protected over there; we don’t need to house them,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, the refugees fleeing Syria are leaving their country because the Syrian government can’t protect them from the warfare tearing the land apart, or the terrors along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muslims in the aforementioned study who were also U.S. citizens held much stronger opposition against terrorist views. Eighty six percent of U.S. Muslims agree suicide bombing “is never justified,” and 81 percent “viewed al-Qaeda unfavorably” in some form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my case, no one expects me to fill a stereotype. [The idea is] we’re terrorists, we’re dirty,” Faiz said. “[Others] are aware that [Islamophobia] exists, but they don’t know what it’s like.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 2010 Gallup poll, Muslims were the most likely to experience discrimination because of their religion or race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I imagine if you were white, you would be treated a bit differently,” Faiz said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A study found white Americans were the greatest “terror threat in the U.S., killing more people in attacks than Muslims or any other group in the last 14 years,” according to independent.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite suspicions about the trustworthiness of Muslims, John does not think all Muslims are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everybody is pretty much equal, in the end,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a belief many share, but don’t practice. A 2013 University of Hawaii study revealed Muslim women who wore traditional headscarves had less employment opportunities in comparison to those who did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My mom wears a hijab, or a headscarf, and people don’t treat her the same as most other women. I don’t think it’s because of her color; I think it’s solely because of the headscarf,” Faiz said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a headscarf may be easier to target, dangerous assumptions are still made based on skin color and ethnicity. Two months ago, Texas freshman Ahmed Mohamed brought a homemade clock to MacArthur High School and was arrested on charges of bringing a “hoax bomb” to school, according to cnn.com. While charges were dropped, Mohamed no longer felt welcome at the public school and transferred elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’ve got the same opportunities, it’s whether they decide to take it or not,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those opportunities are not exactly in reach when people use the actions of the few to discriminate against all Muslims. Assuming all Muslims are radical suicide bombers perpetuates the “phobia” on both sides of the argument, and widens the divide between Muslims and everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a timeline of terror attacks go here: http://www.wsj.com/articles/timeline-of-terror-attacks-in-past-20-years-1420662841&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 12:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/21/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/21/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Islamophobia in the 21st century</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ohsbeacon.com/587/opinion/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/&quot;&gt;ohsbeacon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syrians fleeing violence have nowhere to go as countries turn them away, fearing a surplus of immigrants—through unemployment, overcrowding and terrorism—will bring only trouble to their country in the wake of the Paris attacks orchestrated by the Islamic State of Iraq, better known as ISIS. This should not be an excuse to victimize innocent Muslims because of the actions of terrorists, but this truth is not apparent to some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re the same type of refugees in Germany and taking over Germany now. I don’t want them to be doing that here,” John S. ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Council on American-Islamic Relations defines Islamophobia as “close-minded prejudice against or hatred of Islam and Muslims.” The phenomenon is a negative reflection on the Muslim population based on violent acts of radical terrorist groups. These feelings have been built up from the Palestinian group Black September, who killed and took hostage of several Israeli Olympic staff members during the 1972 Munich Olympics, according to nps.gov, to the present-day ISIS, the extremist organization responsible for the recent Paris attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the falling of the Twin Towers sparked Islamophobia’s most notable uptick. The media and government made discrimination of Muslims almost commonplace at the time, misbranding the tragedy as an “Islamic attack” rather than a “terrorist attack on the U.S.,” World History teacher Daniel Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An approximate 3,000 people—from all ideologies, including Muslims with no involvement in the attacks—died in the Sept. 11 tragedy, according to cnn.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, terrorist attacks worldwide are claimed by whichever “Islamic fundamentalist” terrorist group holds the most power. Although these groups rise and fall, the impact of these catastrophes extremists claim take a negative toll on the daily lives of a majority of peaceful Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every terror attack claimed by a group related to Islam is a further hit to Islam relations with the United States or even social discrimination against Islamic people,” Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growing death toll worldwide caused by ever-present militant groups, it is easy to blame an entire religion or culture for the actions of one organization spilling blood in the name of Allah. It is easy to scrutinize Muslims at home, when innocent people—many of them holding a peaceful interpretation of the same faith as their assailants—are dying at the hands of those committing heinous acts in the name of their religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After big terrorist attacks or events that portray Islam negatively, [I receive] a bit more questioning looks,” Junior Faiz J. said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While anti-Muslim backlash is not shown in statistics to increase after such terrorist attacks, Islamophobic sentiment does seem to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They keep arguing that they’re peaceful, but I guess people and their religion are making it worse,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 2011 Pew Research Center study found 55 percent of the average Muslim public abroad opposes all violence (including suicide bombings) against civilians in any form. An average 38 percent of this same group held terrorist group al-Qaeda in low esteem. But not everyone is open to the idea of Muslims being anything but violent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re still from their own country. They can be protected over there; we don’t need to house them,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, the refugees fleeing Syria are leaving their country because the Syrian government can’t protect them from the warfare tearing the land apart, or the terrors along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muslims in the aforementioned study who were also U.S. citizens held much stronger opposition against terrorist views. Eighty six percent of U.S. Muslims agree suicide bombing “is never justified,” and 81 percent “viewed al-Qaeda unfavorably” in some form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my case, no one expects me to fill a stereotype. [The idea is] we’re terrorists, we’re dirty,” Faiz said. “[Others] are aware that [Islamophobia] exists, but they don’t know what it’s like.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 2010 Gallup poll, Muslims were the most likely to experience discrimination because of their religion or race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I imagine if you were white, you would be treated a bit differently,” Faiz said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A study found white Americans were the greatest “terror threat in the U.S., killing more people in attacks than Muslims or any other group in the last 14 years,” according to independent.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite suspicions about the trustworthiness of Muslims, John does not think all Muslims are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everybody is pretty much equal, in the end,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a belief many share, but don’t practice. A 2013 University of Hawaii study revealed Muslim women who wore traditional headscarves had less employment opportunities in comparison to those who did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My mom wears a hijab, or a headscarf, and people don’t treat her the same as most other women. I don’t think it’s because of her color; I think it’s solely because of the headscarf,” Faiz said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a headscarf may be easier to target, dangerous assumptions are still made based on skin color and ethnicity. Two months ago, Texas freshman Ahmed Mohamed brought a homemade clock to MacArthur High School and was arrested on charges of bringing a “hoax bomb” to school, according to cnn.com. While charges were dropped, Mohamed no longer felt welcome at the public school and transferred elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’ve got the same opportunities, it’s whether they decide to take it or not,” John said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those opportunities are not exactly in reach when people use the actions of the few to discriminate against all Muslims. Assuming all Muslims are radical suicide bombers perpetuates the “phobia” on both sides of the argument, and widens the divide between Muslims and everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a timeline of terror attacks go here: http://www.wsj.com/articles/timeline-of-terror-attacks-in-past-20-years-1420662841&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 12:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/21/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/21/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New year, new pool, very cool</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 January issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sat·ire     ˈsaˌtī(ə)r/     noun
the use of humor, irony, exaggeration, or ridicule to expose and criticize people’s stupidity or vices, particularly in the context of contemporary politics and other topical issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lewis Center, OH—Swimmers spent their first practice of the year on Monday, Dec. 4 in the &lt;strong&gt;third-floor pool&lt;/strong&gt;, the latest sports renovation since the 2014 stadium turf installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The tiles are still very slippery. The pool hasn’t been broken in yet. You can still feel sawdust on the floor of the pool,” junior Alex Garner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, swimmers made a 23-minute drive to practice at the Delaware YMCA—a 7 ½ mile trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now we don’t have to waste as much gas to get to practice,” Garner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While saving on gas is an undeniable perk, the new &lt;strong&gt;third-floor&lt;/strong&gt; facilities also allow more privacy for the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before, we shared locker rooms with the public. Now we have locker rooms of our own,” Garner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The much-anticipated &lt;strong&gt;third-floor pool&lt;/strong&gt; and additional exercise opportunities opened December 2015 to the general public for those willing to pay membership fees. But due to years of misinformation, many freshmen are missing out on the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the past, the pool has been a joke,” Oshra Gadkar ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past semester, the class of 2019 drowned in punch lines from their older peers, the most popular being the third-floor swimming pool. Fact or fiction aside, the urban legend coming to life is somewhat of a relief from the constant grilling of poor freshmeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I heard rumors about the pool, but I was never fooled. Incoming freshmen won’t get scammed anymore, but I don’t think they’d fall for it anyway,” Varun G. ‘19 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upperclassmen seem to view the phenomenon as a benefit rather than a concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you tried to tell the freshmen there really is a pool now, they wouldn’t believe it and would never even try to go up there. It would become an all upperclassmen pool, which would be sweet,” Madalen Medovich ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the existence of the mysterious pool continues to be debated, the swim team faced off against Dublin Scioto Friday, Jan. 7—their first meet at the new location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: There is no third floor pool. Any mentions of the third-floor pool can be replaced with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountcarmelhealth.com/&quot;&gt;Mount Carmel Fitness Center&lt;/a&gt; and still make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;amp;A with Olentangy High School Dean of Students Brad Henry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How much money did it cost to install?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: I think it was a tax-free deal. We got a donation from one of our generous parents who helped us put it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How can students get to the pool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: The elevator, by the Wigwam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Does school dress code apply at the pool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Speedos are okay, as long as the boys aren’t wearing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Any rules or conditions regarding the third-floor pool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Just that students go to the fourth floor and try to use it as a high dive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/New-year-new-pool-very-coolmd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/New-year-new-pool-very-coolmd/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Health measured on a greater scale</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2016 January issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the ball made its annual drop in Madison Square Garden, the nationwide quest for fitness began—but the resolution to be healthy often isn’t for the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People who make a New Year’s resolution to lose weight don’t go about it the right way, because they only care about what they look like,” Jake R. said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our culture, appearance—weight in particular—is a supposed measurement of overall health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Society’s idea of attractiveness isn’t as attainable for some people, and that’s not fair,” Jake R. said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others are not as empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everyone is different. But sometimes the gains don’t agree with you,” Megan C. ’17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But weight isn’t a reliable tool of determining how healthy someone is, according to neuroscientist Sandra Aamodt’s 2013 TEDTalk, “Why dieting doesn’t usually work.” A person’s health is in fact more dependent on the number of healthy choices made on a regular basis, rather than the number of pounds on the scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a person below or meeting a “normal” weight range surviving on junk food and TV alone is more likely to develop a chronic disease than someone overweight taking daily walks and meeting their recommended fruit and vegetable intake—whether or not they lose weight in the process. However, making unhealthy choices on top of being overweight or obese is when chronic diseases like diabetes and heart disease come out to play. This deadly combination increases disease likelihood by three times the normal amount of risk, Aamodt said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If long-term disease prevention isn’t enough to tweak resolutions, preventing short-term sickness may be more convincing. Sickness is one less stressor for people making healthy choices, school psychologist Alison Armstrong said. Nutrient-dense foods and regular exercise strengthen the immune system, leaving the body less susceptible to illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with resiliency against the common cold, a healthy lifestyle can ward off a bad mood. Exercise prompts neurotransmitters to fire faster, which in turn “increase brain chemicals related to having an elevated mood,” Armstrong said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the first step is harder for those with depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you are clinically depressed, it is often very hard to get yourself to [exercise]. But the benefits are there,” Armstrong said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the more obvious physical benefits, greater confidence in what you and your body can do is the greatest advantage gained from making better choices—not losing weight. Well-being is measured on a more complicated scale than attractiveness, and resolving to be healthier just to change how you look on the outside won’t change how you feel on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/Health-measured-on-a-greater-scale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/Health-measured-on-a-greater-scale/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More vegans raise forks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VEGAN: &lt;strong&gt;A person who chooses to not eat meat or other animal products (dairy, eggs) because of health and/or moral and environmental reasons.&lt;/strong&gt; Many vegans don’t wear leather under similar logic. Six percent of the U.S. population is vegan, according to the 2015 Nutrition Business Journal Food Tribes Report—a number which has tripled in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the veg-curious, science teacher and vegan-leaning vegetarian Julie Pinney advises to, “take small steps at a time or you’ll end up crash dieting. Stick to white meat, then eventually wean yourself off.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consult a nutritionist to avoid protein deficiency and other health problems before becoming vegan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VEGETARIAN WITH VEGAN TENDENCIES: &lt;strong&gt;“I don’t drink milk. I don’t eat yogurt. Cheese is probably the only reason I don’t consider myself a full vegan.” — Science teacher Julie Pinney&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: “I have to be careful about how much protein I get,” Pinney said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinney relies on protein-packed nuts, hummus and organic burritos. Going out to eat can also be a challenge, but Pinney can always count on Mediterranean restaurants like Greek Express on Polaris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VEGETARIAN: &lt;strong&gt;“I became a vegetarian because it’s healthier, not because of animal cruelty. I didn’t eat much meat anyway.” — Gwendolyn Kunz ‘17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: Protein is the greatest concern. Kunz found forms of protein in foods like bean burgers and tofu, but the time and money needed to discover these new foods is sometimes too great a cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s too much effort,” Alyssa K. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;PESCATARIAN: &lt;strong&gt;A person who does not eat meat, but relies on seafood as a primary source of protein.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: Some fish have high amounts of mercury and other chemicals, which pose health risks to consumers. Overfishing is another environmental concern. But when sourced responsibly, fish can be a great source of omega-3s as well as protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MEAT EATER: &lt;strong&gt;“Meat tastes good. If it was easier to be a vegan or vegetarian, I’d do it.” — Faiz Jafri ‘17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DANGERS: The World Health Organization (WHO) deemed processed meat an “established carcinogen” and the 2015 Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee recommended a “movement toward less resource-intensive diets” grounded in plants, grains and legumes rather than meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/more-vegans-raise-forks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/more-vegans-raise-forks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snowboarding is rad, Skiing is sad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snowboarding is cooler than its polar opposite. With its origins in surfing, how could skiing compete?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, snowboarders are a nuisance to skiers, but it’s because skiers are so uptight in comparison. Snowboarders take time to enjoy the view from the top while strapping up, while skiers are so anxious to hop off the chairlift and get to the bottom as fast as they can. Snowboarders criss-crossing down the slope revel in the satisfying feeling of snow under their board, while skiers fast-forward to the end, not bothering to enjoy the journey. However, it’s not their fault for being in such a hurry; those uncomfortable ski boots would make anyone scramble over a hill as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skiers may reach faster speeds, but snowboarding tricks are still more entertaining to see. Who watches skiing in the X Games when they can watch Shaun White or Ohio-raised snowboarder Louie Vito shred up the snow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Snowboarding is more fun to watch than skiing. They can do better tricks,” Michael Savoldi ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While snowboarding has higher street cred than skiing, it is also surprisingly safer. According to snowboarding-essentials.com, snowboarding is kinder on the knees. While snowboarding does leave the wrists more vulnerable in a bad fall, this can be easily avoided with wrist guards and proper form. Although skiers and snowboarders nationwide are susceptible to similar amounts of catastrophic injuries, skiers are still more likely to die from a serious accident, according to the National Ski Area Association.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s too bad skiers can’t use their lame poles to propel their minds around how rad snowboarding is. The rivalry between the two sports has gone on for what seems like forever, but skiers will always shake their pole sticks at snowboarders for having more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/Snowboarding-is-rad-skiing-is-sad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/01/Snowboarding-is-rad-skiing-is-sad/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The evolution of social media</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 December issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, social media has enriched the lives of its users by allowing them to connect and share with others a couple clicks away. However, it also carries a potential to make life more complicated, with Twitter fights and direct messages gone awry. Here is a look at how social media has changed over time and continues to evolve, yet still borrows from preceding programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early 1980s: The Bulletin Board System, or BBS, becomes popular with nerds and outcasts. Although technology of the time limits its capabilities, users are still able to send messages similar to Remind101, as well as download files and games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late 1980s: CompuServe, a communication system reserved for business purposes, is released to the public market. AOL is released not long after, with the first communities of members and member profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1995: &lt;a href=&quot;classmates.com&quot;&gt;Classmates.com&lt;/a&gt; enables users to find former classmates. Today, the site has over 57 million accounts, according to &lt;a href=&quot;digitaltrends.com&quot;&gt;digitaltrends.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1997: &lt;a href=&quot;SixDegrees.com&quot;&gt;SixDegrees.com&lt;/a&gt; launches, based on the six degrees of separation theory: a person is a mere six steps away from being connected to any other given person. In 2000, the site shuts down; the failure is attributed to the over-spamming of users to invite friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2002: &lt;a href=&quot;Friendster.com&quot;&gt;Friendster.com&lt;/a&gt; allows users to find friends in a similar matchmaking process to modern dating sites. When the social media aspect of the site lost considerable traffic, it focused on online games instead before shutting down in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.friendster.com/&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2003: LinkedIn and MySpace become popular. While MySpace fell from a household name to social networking for musicians and bands, LinkedIn continues to be a mainstream business networking tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2006: Facebook is released to the public, after being restricted to the Harvard campus for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2007: Another FaceBook launch introduces the “Like” button on Facebook and Twitter, Facebook’s adopted sibling site. Google changes the social media game with Google+’s live video chat “hangouts,” and FaceBook scrambles to replicate this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010-2015: Mobile-based apps such as Instagram, Snapchat and dating apps based on location rule the social media sphere – yet Facebook still reigns supreme with 1,490 million users, according to &lt;a href=&quot;statista.com&quot;&gt;statista.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future: Virtual reality in social media may be in reach in a few years, with the Oculus virtual reality headset and Google Glasses already making gains in this area. Developers hope to someday immerse all five senses of users in experiencing games, live sports and even while speaking to friends in holographic form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/The-evolution-of-social-media/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/The-evolution-of-social-media/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to shop and survive in the thrift store jungle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 October issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step One: STALK YOUR PREY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you seek a few classic pieces or the latest trend blasted from the past (we’re looking at you, dad sandals), you must have an idea of what you want before even stepping into the mod-print rainforest that is Goodwill. So, do your fashion homework! Read up on trends coming back into style or reference entire time periods for your style inspiration. Shopping with a half-baked goal in mind will suppress any urges to impulse buy green gator shoes at half its original 1980s price—or pass on the hunt for a bargain altogether. The latter is where inexperienced hunters fail to understand the full reality of a thrift store, led astray by the Macklemore hit single—there will be rows upon inevitable rows of your grandad’s clothes, and not all of them will look incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Two: PROWL THE AISLES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skim the entire store the moment you hit the linoleum tile. Once this is completed, move in for the kill and target specific clothing sections. While examining each individual hanger is the most thorough approach, consider each article of clothing quickly. Otherwise, you will have miraculously aged faster than your purchases upon exiting the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Three: DON’T BE AFRAID TO EXPLORE THE UNKNOWN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outer layers, ambiguous jackets or coats in particular, are notorious for being disorganized. Regardless of gender, check both the men’s and women’s sections for a hidden gem not yet copped. Also, hello? Oversized men’s sweaters? Need I say more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Four: CLEAN YOUR KILL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Goodwill does dry clean all of their fabric items, you may still want to wash your (new?) clothing purchases anyway for the sake of comfort. The smell of your family’s detergent will smell more familiar than a secondhand scent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STEP FIVE: WEAR IT WITH PRIDE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finally rock your thrifted finds, do so with the confidence that you made a purchase friendly to your wallet, the environment and your community. The stigma surrounding thrift stores may be off-putting, but only increases your chances of finding a diamond purchase out of the rough interior of the thrift store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/How-to-shop-and-survive-in-the-thrift-store-jungle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/01/How-to-shop-and-survive-in-the-thrift-store-jungle/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sister hikers get lost, then found</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 September issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;285, 505 acres. Three sisters. One hiking trip gone wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gros Ventre Wilderness Area in Moose, WY is most known for where the infamous Andrews-Sharer sisters went missing and since been found in the summer of 2015, but not before their story spread worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sisters left for the trip June 28, to hike the trail that Tuesday. They planned to be in the woods for five days and hike back out to their car on July 4. They were officially lost for six days, July 4 until July 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As experienced hikers, they had all the essentials to survive. They did everything right, speaking with rangers beforehand to ensure their safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The park ranger recommended the trail we went on because it was the most-used. We figured we would see people, and the trail would be maintained like a national park,” Kelsi Andrews-Sharer ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nothing like they thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The trail was a small game-hunting trail along a mountain cliff. The meadowgrasses overcrowded the path and came up to our necks, making it hard to see,” Andrews-Sharer said. “But my sisters are both experienced in reading maps and using a compass, so we fared pretty well for most of the trip.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday afternoon, they decided to follow a shorter loop on the map than planned, since they moved slower than anticipated that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had been hiking hard for four days, but I had not yet acclimatized to the altitude,” Andrews-Sharer said. “Then we came upon an avalanche of rocks covering the trail. We planned to hike back to our previous campsite, then to a sign we’d passed before on the edge of the Wilderness Area and hike to our car from there. But the trail we took to retrace our steps began to veer off in a different direction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They knew they were lost, but more immediate problems loomed on the horizon. The sun was to go down in an hour and a half, when they found fresh mountain lion pawprints. They acted fast to pitch their tent for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The next morning my sister Megan, the most experienced hiker, decided the safest choice was to stop and get help,” Andrews-Sharer said. “We thought our parents would be waiting for us to call in the morning, and when they didn’t get the call they would start searching immediately.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three stayed optimistic while they waited but took precautions to ration food, build a signal fire, set out colored gear and make right angles with fallen trees as an SOS to any aircraft flying overhead. But when they weren’t rescued Saturday night, they began to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We realized we hadn’t explained to our parents exactly where we were hiking before we left for the trip,” Andrews-Sharer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday came and went, with hopes of being rescued unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When our food supply became dangerously low, we found strength in our faith… We all realized we could very possibly die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday morning, the sisters sat freezing in their tent, bodies too weak from starvation to keep warm. In mid-prayer for a helicopter, they heard two fly overhead, the second one spotting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It hovered over us, and we were screaming and crying and our bodies were shaking,” Andrews-Sharer said. “Five minutes after getting into the helicopter, we were in our dad’s arms.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never take the little things for granted. They are what matter in the end. Food, showers, hugs from your parents, late night conversations with a friend, laughing so hard your stomach aches. Life is short and tentative, so take chances. You might not get them again,” Andrews-Sharer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against all odds, fear did not trump these sisters’ love of backpacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re planning on hiking again next summer,” Andrews-Sharer said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/sister-hikers-get-lost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/sister-hikers-get-lost/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 Olentangy HS Fall Sports Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally published in 2015 September issue of The Beacon magazine for Olentangy High School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boys Golf:&lt;/strong&gt; After players came up to par in OCC’s, the boys prepare to dominate in the Delaware County Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a major rivalry event that goes back 25 years, and we have won this event more than any other school,” head coach Joel Glassburn said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Football:&lt;/strong&gt; The defending OCC champs swept Westerville South with a score of 41-17. They also did well in the preseason scrimmages, with a tie against St. Edwards High School and a 17-7 win against Pickerington Central High School. The boys have big plans for this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to win the state championship,” Jimmy Elmurr ‘16 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boys Cross Country:&lt;/strong&gt; The boys placed third place at Mt. Vernon, with top finisher Anthony Sasso ‘17 taking eighth place in the team race. New head coach Ken Whalen experienced leading his first high school cross country team in a meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I coached many of the runners as middle schoolers, so I know what needs to be done to push them to their full potential,” Whalen said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whalen coached the middle school cross country team for eight years, was on staff for the middle school boys track program for seven and assistant-coached the boys and girls distance track team for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He is really making an effort to understand the strengths and weaknesses of the team, to get us in optimal shape for districts and hopefully beyond,” Tyler Reed ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Cross Country: The 87-strong team placed second at Mt. Vernon. The exploding number of the team is double the challenge for captains and coaches, where new assistant coach Kaitlin Rever comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Size is a challenge, but top athletes only get better with more teammates challenging and pushing them forward,” Rever said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rever, a 1990 Olentangy alumni with 20 years of coaching experience, has taken multiple teams to states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Coach Rever is very supportive and encouraging,” Krescens K. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Volleyball: After losing their first two matches, all three teams won matches against Big Walnut Aug. 27 and Dublin Scioto Aug. 29.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had a bumpy start, but we are now playing well after our opening conference,” head coach Michelle Mimna said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Varsity team also beat Orange Sept. 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re expecting a good season,” Katelyn Petrycki ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Tennis:  2014 state quarter finalists Brianna Brdicka ‘16 and Kathleen J. ‘18 are serving aces and taking names. They are the first ever players of any OHS tennis team or individual to win the first Doubles Division of the Watterson Invitational, according to the school athletics website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t want to get overconfident, but we definitely hope to place at states,” Brdicka said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Golf: Kara Raines ‘17 finished sixth out of 66 golfers at the Midwest Classic in Canton with a score of 82, with the team finishing ninth out of 18 teams in the tournament, head coach John Feasel said. Raines and Alexandra Cardi ‘17 are the players to watch for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They are two of the best golfers the team has ever seen, and they are only juniors,” Feasel said. “If they make it to districts it would be the first time in school history.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Field Hockey: Varsity Captain Allison Martin ‘17 and Junior Varsity player Emma B. ‘18 each scored a goal on state champion Thomas Worthington Aug. 24, the first time in the school’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was refreshing to see the ball hit the back of the goal and know we are capable of scoring against a powerhouse team in our division,” Martin said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also a first, 14 seniors return to play this year, the highest retention rate ever for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As long as they continue to push themselves to be better, anything is possible,” head coach Biz Brehm said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boys Soccer: The Varsity team won 1-0 against Big Walnut Sept. 1 with a goal by Corey Sweet ‘17, cheered on by new assistant defensive coach Dan Ensign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s good at explaining tactics,” Ryan R. ‘18 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite a rough start to the season, Ensign still saw the team’s potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had the pieces needed to make a great starting lineup, we just needed to sort out who plays what after so many graduating seniors last year,” Ensign said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls Soccer: Last season, the girls team won their first OCC Championship since 1999. They also took home First Regional Finalists, 12 individual awards, and an OCC Coach of the Year award for head coach Megan Kirsten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re prepared to live up to how we did last year,” Ireland Fallona ‘17 said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Varsity team won their season opener 1-0 against Thomas Worthington, goal courtesy of Stephanie Burzinski ‘16. With another goal by Julia F. ‘18, Varsity beat Big Walnut 1-0 in a game Sept. 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/Olentangy-HS-fall-sports-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/01/Olentangy-HS-fall-sports-review/</guid>
      </item>
    

    
      
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m an intern as well as a college student who is studying journalism and international studies. Whether I’m writing a news article, a feature story, a press release or a script, I set out to turn complicated topics into stories anyone can read. I can complete any assignment, but I especially love my job when I write stories that make people think, act, feel or do all three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is my virtual portfolio. Explore my resume and past work to see what I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/about.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Resume</title>
            <description>Writer and marketing intern

Email me at &lt;mailto:murdocc3@miamioh.edu&gt; or view my [LinkedIn](http://www.linkedin.com/in/chloe-m-275197133)

## **Education**

2018-2021 — current student at **Miami University** in Oxford, Ohio

* majoring in Journalism and International Studies
* 3.6 cumulative GPA

2017 — Graduated from Olentangy High School

* 3.7 cumulative GPA

## **Experience**

June 2019 - July 2019: writer at [KosovaLive](https://www.kosovalive360.com//?s=Chloe+Murdock) in Pristina, Kosovo

May 2019 - July 2019: undergraduate assistant for Miami University journalism course, &quot;The Role of Journalism in a Democracy,&quot; in Pristina, Kosovo

* Edited long-form pieces of inexperienced writers and recommended next steps
* Led class discussions and provided materials for professor, Dr. Richard Campbell

May 2017 - Present: marketing intern at [ABB Inc.](http://www.abb.com/) in Westerville, Ohio, United States

* Editing and formatting brochures that enhance ABB sales interactions
* Writing internal success stories and scripts for videos and video teasers
  * Project managed, acted in and wrote the script for a [promotional video](https://www.dropbox.com/s/ut79jmyeimx9tou/ServiceSells%20FINAL%20High%20Quality.mp4?dl=0)
* Writing order announcements
  * [Monarch Cement purchases ABB upgrade to improve operator interface](http://www.abb.com/cawp/seitp202/41e785445f004da8c1258154006c22c3.aspx)

  * [MedcoEnergi renews ABB Oil and Gas Care](http://medcoenergi%20renews%20abb%20oil%20and%20gas%20care/)

  * [ArcelorMittal evolution path leads to ABB Ability upgrades](http://www.abb.co.in/cawp/seitp202/3f90f076010a97a6c125818600649f83.aspx)

  * [Self-maintaining plant opens up for ABB services](http://www.abb.com/cawp/seitp202/fc80eb99040d282bc12582ab0063d059.aspx)

  * [PGE Capital Group renews ABB Care, adds control system services](https://new.abb.com/news/detail/5887/pge-capital-group-renews-abb-care-adds-control-systems-services)
* Managing [@abbindustryserv](https://twitter.com/abbindustryserv?lang=en)
* Project managing an internal marketing campaign and drafting campaign emails through Constant Contact

October 2018 - Present: Contributing editor and writer for [The Miami Student Magazine](http://magazine.miamistudent.net/)

November 2018 - December 2018: Social media manager for The Miami Student magazine [Twitter](https://twitter.com/miamistudentmag?lang=en) and [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/miamistudentmagazine/)

September 2017 - Present: Writer for The Miami Student [newspaper](https://miamistudent.net/author/chloe-murdock/) and [magazine](http://magazine.miamistudent.net/tortillas-and-motorcycles-my-family-its-memories-and-the-opinions-in-between/)

Featured in The Miami Student Magazine:

* [Real-life fairy godmothers](http://magazine.miamistudent.net/real-life-fairy-godmothers/)



* [Tortillas and motorcycles: My family, its memories and the opinions in between](http://magazine.miamistudent.net/tortillas-and-motorcycles-my-family-its-memories-and-the-opinions-in-between/)



* [Nowhere to turn](http://magazine.miamistudent.net/nowhere-to-turn/)

Featured in the Culture section of The Miami Student newspaper:

* [Kosovo. &quot;Where is that?&quot;](https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2019/08/discovering-kosovo-great-coffee-better-people-and-a-tangled-history)



* [Humans of Oxford: He doesn't just speak for the trees](https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2019/10/humans-of-oxford-he-doesnt-just-speak-for-the-trees?ct=content_open&amp;cv=cbox_featured)



* [Artist's talk shines light on A-bomb history](https://www.miamistudent.net/article/2019/09/artists-talk-shines-light-on-a-bomb-history?ct=content_open&amp;cv=cbox_latest)



* [A medieval club in no man’s land](https://miamistudent.net/a-medieval-club-in-no-mans-land/)



* [MUFD combines style and sustainability](https://miamistudent.net/mufd-combines-style-and-sustainability/)



* [People are finally talking about the Elephants in the Room](https://miamistudent.net/people-are-finally-talking-about-the-elephants-in-the-room/)



* [April poetry contest buds into spring](https://miamistudent.net/april-poetry-contest-buds-into-spring/)



* [Ballroom dance club finds footing in new roles](https://miamistudent.net/ballroom-dance-club-finds-footing-in-new-roles/)



* [Women’s self-defense class a rank above the rest](https://miamistudent.net/womens-self-defense-class-a-rank-above-the-rest/)



* [Missing home and hot tortillas](https://miamistudent.net/first-year-shock/)

Featured in the Opinion section of The Miami Student newspaper:

* [And Marie Antoinette said, “Let them go vote!”](https://miamistudent.net/and-marie-antoinette-said-let-them-go-vote/)



* [Ask me, “Are you sure?” again, I dare you](https://miamistudent.net/ask-me-are-you-sure-again-i-dare-you/)

Featured in the News section of The Miami Student newspaper:

* [Central Park Five member speaks on institutionalized racism](https://miamistudent.net/central-park-five-member-speaks-on-institutionalized-racism/)

January 2019 - Present: Vice President of Miami University Martial Arts Club

* Weighing in on club executive board decisions
* Planning alumni events, taekwondo performances and other club gatherings
* Announcing at festivals

May 2018 – February 2019: PR Chair for Miami University Martial Arts Club

* Created and implemented a recruitment campaign plan
* Posted relevant Facebook and [Twitter](https://twitter.com/MartialMiami) content that aligns with recruitment campaign

2016-2017 Olentangy High School’s The Beacon magazine: Editor-in-chief, Writer, Designer

* [Get off the couch, see these movies](/2017/03/01/Get-off-the-couch-see-these-movies)



* [Student’s foundation creates change in India slums](/2017/04/19/Students-foundation-creates-change-in-india-slums/)



* [Attraction turns scientific](/2017/02/01/Attraction-turns-scientific/)



* [Holidays draw out religious differences](/2016/12/01/Holidays-draw-out-religious-differences/)



* [Powerschool helps, harms student stress](/2017/03/01/Powerschool-helps-harms-student-stress/)



* [Cesar Chavez Day withstands today’s political climate](/2017/03/01/Cesar-Chaves-day-withstands-todays-political-climate/)

2015-2016 Online Olentangy High School’s The Beacon magazine – Writer

* [Islamophobia in the 21st century](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/01/21/islamophobia-in-the-21st-century/)



* [New coach returns to alma mater](https://ohsbeacon.com/688/sports/new-coach-returns-to-alma-mater/)

2015-2016 Olentangy High School’s The Beacon magazine – Writer / Designer

* [Sriram fulfills 2016 valedictorian dream](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/05/01/Sriram-fulfills-2016-validictorian-dream/)



* [Voters OK 2016 Olentangy Levy](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/05/01/Voters-ok-olentangy-levy/)



* [“Cursed Child” lights new wand](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/03/01/cursed-child-lights/)



* [Spring-cleaning a worldwide phenomenon](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/03/01/spring-cleaning-a-worldwide-phenomenon/)



* [10 reasons to vote for Vermin Supreme! in 2016](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/02/01/10-Reasons-to-vote-for-Vermin-Supreme/)



* [Health measured on a greater scale](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/01/01/Health-measured-on-a-greater-scale/)



* [New year, new pool, very cool (satire)](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2016/01/01/New-year-new-pool-very-coolmd/)



* [Snowboarding is rad, skiing is sad](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2015/12/01/Snowboarding-is-rad-skiing-is-sad/)



* [More vegans raise forks](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2015/12/01/more-vegans-raise-forks/)



* [The evolution of social media](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2015/10/01/The-evolution-of-social-media/)



* [2015 Olentangy High School Fall Sports Review](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2015/09/01/Olentangy-HS-fall-sports-review/)



* [Sister hikers get lost, then found](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2015/09/01/sister-hikers-get-lost/)



* [How to shop and survive in the thrift store jungle](https://chloemurdock.github.io/2015/10/01/How-to-shop-and-survive-in-the-thrift-store-jungle/)

## **Awards**

2017 — James L. McCann Excellence in High School Journalism Award

2017 – “Superior” and “Excellent” ratings from the Ohio Scholastic Media Association

2016 – three “Honorable Mentions” from the Ohio Scholastic Media Association

Won first place in Power of the Pen competition while representing Olentangy Shanahan Middle School

Won essay contest to present wreath on the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier

## **Interests**

Traveling, snowboarding, kayaking, paddle boarding, reading, volunteer work.
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/resume.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
